<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
	<idinfo>
		<keywords>
			<theme>
				<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
				<themekey>planningCadastre</themekey>
			</theme>
			<place>
				<placekt>GeoNames</placekt>
				<placekey>Virginia (6254928)</placekey>
			</place>
			<place>
				<placekt>None</placekt>
				<placekey>Virginia</placekey>
			</place>
			<temporal>
				<tempkt>None</tempkt>
				<tempkey>2023</tempkey>
			</temporal>
		</keywords>
		<spdom>
			<bounding>
				<westbc>-83.675395</westbc>
				<eastbc>-75.242266</eastbc>
				<northbc>39.466012</northbc>
				<southbc>36.540738</southbc>
			</bounding>
		</spdom>
		<descript>
			<langdata>eng</langdata>
<abstract>Virginia Tax Parcels, 2023 is a polygon theme representing tax parcels and lots in various Virginia counties from the year 2006-2023. The counties included are Accomack, Albemarle, Alleghany, Amelia, Amherst, Appomattox, Arlington, Augusta, Bath, Bedford, Bland, Botetourt, Brunswick, Bucannan, Buckingham, Campbell, Caroline, Carroll, Charles City, Charlotte, Chesterfield, Clarke, Craig, Culpeper, Cumberland, Dickenson, Dinwiddie, Essex, Fairfax, Fauquier, Floyd, Fluvanna, Franklin, Frederick, Giles, Gloucester, Goochland, Grayson, Greene, Greensville, Halifax, Hanover, Henrico, Henry, Highland, Isle of Wight, James City, King and Queen, King George, King William, Lancaster, Lee, Loudoun, Louisa, Lunenburg, Madison, Mathews, Mecklenburg, Middlesex, Montgomery, Nelson, New Kent, Northampton, Northumberland, Nottoway, Orange, Page, Patrick, Pittsylvania, Powhatan, Prince Edward, Prince George, Prince William, Pulaski, Richmond, Roanoke, Rockbridge, Campbell, Russell, Scott, Shenandoah, Smyth, Southampton, Spotsylvania, Stafford, Surry, Sussex, Tazewell, Warren, Washington, Westmoreland, Wise, Wythe, York, Alexandria city, Bedford City, Bristol, Buena Vista, Charlottesville, Chesapeake city, Colonial Heights city, Covington, Danville, Emporia city, Fairfax city, Falls Church city, Franklin city, Fredericksburg city, Galax, Hampton city, Harrisonburg city, Hopewell city, Lexington, Lynchburg, Manassas city, Manassas Park City, Martinsville, Newport News city, Norfolk city, Norton city, Petersburg city, Poquoson city, Portsmouth city, Radford city, Richmond city, Roanoke city, Salem city, Staunton city, Suffolk city, Virginia Beach city, Waynesboro city, Williamsburg city, Winchester city. Attribute information typically includes details regarding the address, ownership and valuation of the lot as well as information regarding structures on the parcel. Accompanying layers will usually include street centerlines and county boundary layers.  Additional cadastral and property files are included, though the content and format of these additional files may vary. All files were collected and published by Boundary Solutions as part of the National ParcelMap Data Portal.
		</abstract>
		<purpose>These files are formatted for use in a GIS</purpose>
	</descript>
	<citation>
		<citeinfo>
			<title>Virginia Tax Parcels, 2023 </title>
			<origin>Boundary Solutions, Inc.</origin>
			<pubdate>2023</pubdate>
			<geoform>map</geoform>
			<pubinfo>
				<publish>Boundary Solutions, Inc.</publish>
			</pubinfo>
<onlink>https://www1.columbia.edu/sec/acis/eds/dgate/studies/C1301/data/bsi_2023_parcelmap_51_va.zip
		</onlink>
	</citeinfo>
</citation>
<timeperd>
	<current>Ground condition</current>
	<timeinfo>
		<sngdate>
			<caldate>2023</caldate>
		</sngdate>
	</timeinfo>
</timeperd>
<status>
	<progress>Complete</progress>
	<update>Unknown</update>
</status>
<accconst>For current Columbia affiliates only.</accconst>
<useconst>For educational, non-commercial use only.</useconst>
<ptcontac>
	<cntinfo>
		<cntperp>
			<cntorg>Boundary Solutions, Inc.</cntorg>
		</cntperp>
	</cntinfo>
</ptcontac>
</idinfo>
<spdoinfo>
	<direct>Vector</direct>
	<ptvctinf>
		<sdtsterm>
			<sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>
		</sdtsterm>
	</ptvctinf>
</spdoinfo>
<spref>
	<horizsys>
		<geodetic>
			<horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
			<ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
			<semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
			<denflat>298.257222</denflat>
		</geodetic>
		<cordsysn>
			<geogcsn>GCS_North_American_1983</geogcsn>
			<projcsn>NAD_1983_StatePlane_New_York_Long_Island_FIPS_3104_Feet</projcsn>
		</cordsysn>
	</horizsys>
</spref>
<distinfo>
	<stdorder>
		<digform>
			<digtinfo>
				<formname>GeoPackage</formname>
				<formspec>zip</formspec>
				<transize>4000.0 MB</transize>
			</digtinfo>
		</digform>
	</stdorder>
	<resdesc>bsi_2023_parcelmap_51_va</resdesc>
	<distrib>
	</distrib>
</distinfo>
<metainfo>
	<metd>20230615</metd>
	<metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
	<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
	<mettc>local time</mettc>
	<metc>
		<cntinfo>
			<cntperp>
				<cntorg>Research Data Services (RDS), Columbia University Libraries</cntorg>
				<cntper>GIS/Metadata Librarian</cntper>
			</cntperp>
			<cntaddr>
				<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
				<address>420 W. 118th St. 215 IAB, MC 3301</address>
				<city>New York</city>
				<state>NY</state>
				<postal>10027</postal>
			</cntaddr>
			<cntvoice>(212) 854-6012</cntvoice>
			<cntemail>data@library.columbia.edu</cntemail>
		</cntinfo>
	</metc>
</metainfo>
</metadata>
