<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
	<idinfo>
		<keywords>
			<theme>
				<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
				<themekey>planningCadastre</themekey>
			</theme>
			<place>
				<placekt>GeoNames</placekt>
				<placekey>Texas (4736286)</placekey>
			</place>
			<place>
				<placekt>None</placekt>
				<placekey>Texas</placekey>
			</place>
			<temporal>
				<tempkt>None</tempkt>
				<tempkey>2023</tempkey>
			</temporal>
		</keywords>
		<spdom>
			<bounding>
				<westbc>-106.645646</westbc>
				<eastbc>-93.508292</eastbc>
				<northbc>36.500704</northbc>
				<southbc>25.837377</southbc>
			</bounding>
		</spdom>
		<descript>
			<langdata>eng</langdata>
<abstract>Texas Tax Parcels, 2023 is a polygon theme representing tax parcels and lots in various Texas counties from the year 2007-2023. The counties included are Anderson, Andrews, Angelina, Aransas, Archer, Armstrong, Atascosa, Austin, Bailey, Bandera, Bastrop, Bee, Bell, Bexar, Blanco, Borden, Bosque, Bowie, Brazoria, Brazos, Brewster, Brooks, Brown, Burleson, Burnet, Caldwell, Calhoun, Callahan, Cameron, Camp, Carson, Cass, Castro, Chambers, Cherokee, Childress, Clay, Cochran, Coke, Collin, Collingsworth, Comal, Comanche, Concho, Cooke, Coryell, Crane, Crosby, Culberson, Dallam, Dallas, Deaf Smith, Delta, Denton, DeWitt, Dickens, Dimmit, Duval, Eastland, Ector, Edwards, Ellis, El Paso, Erath, Falls, Fannin, Fayette, Fisher, Floyd, Foard, Fort Bend, Franklin, Freestone, Frio, Gaines, Galveston, Gillespie, Glasscock, Goliad, Gonzales, Gray, Grayson, Gregg, Grimes, Guadalupe, Hale, Hall, Hamilton, Hansford, Hardin, Harris, Harrison, Hartley, Haskell, Hays, Hemphill, Henderson, Hidalgo, Hill, Hockley, HOOD, Hopkins, Houston, Howard, Hudspeth, Hunt, Jack, Jackson, Jasper, Jeff Davis, Jefferson, Jim Hogg, Jim Wells, Johnson, Jones, Karnes, Kaufman, Kendall, Kenedy, Kent, Kerr, Kimble, King, Kinney, Kleberg, Knox, Lamar, Lamb, Lampasas, La Salle, Lavaca, Lee, Liberty, Limestone, Lipscomb, Live Oak, Llano, Loving, Lubbock, Lynn, McCulloch, McLennan, McMullen, Madison, Marion, Martin, Mason, Matagorda, Maverick, Medina, Menard, Midland, Milam, Mills, Mitchell, Montgomery, Moore, Morris, Motley, Nacogdoches, Navarro, Newton, Nolan, Nueces, Ochiltree, Oldham, Orange, Palo Pinto, Panola, Parker, Parmer, Pecos, Polk, Potter, Presidio, Rains, Randall, Red River, Reeves, Refugio, Roberts, Robertson, Rockwall, Runnels, Rusk, Sabine, San Augustine, San Jacinto, San Patricio, San Saba, Schleicher, Scurry, Shackelford, Shelby, Smith, Somervell, STARR, Stephens, Sterling, Stonewall, Sutton, Swisher, Tarrant, Taylor, Terrell, Terry, Throckmorton, Titus, Tom Green, Travis, Tyler, Upshur, Upton, Uvalde, Val Verde, Van Zandt, Victoria, Walker, Waller, Ward, Washington, Webb, Wharton, Wheeler, Wichita, Willacy, Williamson, Wilson, Winkler, Wise, Wood, Yoakum, Young, Zapata, Zavala. Attribute information typically includes details regarding the address, ownership and valuation of the lot as well as information regarding structures on the parcel. Accompanying layers will usually include street centerlines and county boundary layers.  Additional cadastral and property files are included, though the content and format of these additional files may vary. All files were collected and published by Boundary Solutions as part of the National ParcelMap Data Portal.
		</abstract>
		<purpose>These files are formatted for use in a GIS</purpose>
	</descript>
	<citation>
		<citeinfo>
			<title>Texas Tax Parcels, 2023 </title>
			<origin>Boundary Solutions, Inc.</origin>
			<pubdate>2023</pubdate>
			<geoform>map</geoform>
			<pubinfo>
				<publish>Boundary Solutions, Inc.</publish>
			</pubinfo>
<onlink>https://www1.columbia.edu/sec/acis/eds/dgate/studies/C1301/data/bsi_2023_parcelmap_48_tx.zip
		</onlink>
	</citeinfo>
</citation>
<timeperd>
	<current>Ground condition</current>
	<timeinfo>
		<sngdate>
			<caldate>2023</caldate>
		</sngdate>
	</timeinfo>
</timeperd>
<status>
	<progress>Complete</progress>
	<update>Unknown</update>
</status>
<accconst>For current Columbia affiliates only.</accconst>
<useconst>For educational, non-commercial use only.</useconst>
<ptcontac>
	<cntinfo>
		<cntperp>
			<cntorg>Boundary Solutions, Inc.</cntorg>
		</cntperp>
	</cntinfo>
</ptcontac>
</idinfo>
<spdoinfo>
	<direct>Vector</direct>
	<ptvctinf>
		<sdtsterm>
			<sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>
		</sdtsterm>
	</ptvctinf>
</spdoinfo>
<spref>
	<horizsys>
		<geodetic>
			<horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
			<ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
			<semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
			<denflat>298.257222</denflat>
		</geodetic>
		<cordsysn>
			<geogcsn>GCS_North_American_1983</geogcsn>
			<projcsn>NAD_1983_StatePlane_New_York_Long_Island_FIPS_3104_Feet</projcsn>
		</cordsysn>
	</horizsys>
</spref>
<distinfo>
	<stdorder>
		<digform>
			<digtinfo>
				<formname>GeoPackage</formname>
				<formspec>zip</formspec>
				<transize>13000.0 MB</transize>
			</digtinfo>
		</digform>
	</stdorder>
	<resdesc>bsi_2023_parcelmap_48_tx</resdesc>
	<distrib>
		<cntinfo>
			<cntorgp>
				<cntorg>Boundary Solutions, Inc.</cntorg>
			</cntorgp>
		</cntinfo>
	</distrib>
</distinfo>
<metainfo>
	<metd>20230615</metd>
	<metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
	<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
	<mettc>local time</mettc>
	<metc>
		<cntinfo>
			<cntperp>
				<cntorg>Research Data Services (RDS), Columbia University Libraries</cntorg>
				<cntper>GIS/Metadata Librarian</cntper>
			</cntperp>
			<cntaddr>
				<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
				<address>420 W. 118th St. 215 IAB, MC 3301</address>
				<city>New York</city>
				<state>NY</state>
				<postal>10027</postal>
			</cntaddr>
			<cntvoice>(212) 854-6012</cntvoice>
			<cntemail>data@library.columbia.edu</cntemail>
		</cntinfo>
	</metc>
</metainfo>
</metadata>
