<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
	<idinfo>
		<citation>
			<citeinfo>
				<origin>University of Michigan. China Data Center</origin>
				<pubdate>2005</pubdate>
				<title>Tibet Province With 2000 Population Census Data From 9.95% Long Form Data (table L5-L8)</title>
				<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
				<serinfo>
					<sername>2000 Tibet Township Population Census Data with GIS Maps</sername>
				</serinfo>
				<pubinfo>
					<pubplace>Beijing</pubplace>
					<publish>Beijing Hua tong ren shi chang xin xi you xian ze ren gong si</publish>
				</pubinfo>
<onlink>https://www1.columbia.edu/sec/acis/eds/dgate/studies/C1301/data/cdc_2000_tibet_province2000l2.zip
			</onlink>
		</citeinfo>
	</citation>
	<descript>
		<langdata>eng</langdata>
		<langdata>chi</langdata>
<abstract>Tibet Province With 2000 Population Census Data From 9.95% Long Form Data (table L5-L8) is a polygon theme representing Tibet province in China.  Attribute information includes a variety of variables from the long form data from the 2000 Chinese census.

This data layer is part of the Tibet 2000 Township Census data set produced by the All China Marketing Research Co. and distributed by the University of Michigan, China Data Center.</abstract>
		<purpose>The data set was developed for display and analysis using GIS.</purpose>
<supplinf>Notes on China 2000 Population Census Data:
In order to guide you to use the data correctly, provide you some explanations as follows:
(l) Census time: 0:00AM of November 1, 2000 as the reference time for the census.
(2) The 2000 population census covered all persons who hold the nationality of, and have permanent residing place in the People's Republic of China. During the census, each person was enumerated in his/her permanent residing place.
The following persons should be enumerated in their permanent residing place: a) Those who reside in the townships, towns and street communities and have their permanent household registration there. b) Those who have resided in the townships, towns and street communities for more than 6 months but the places of their permanent household registration are elsewhere. c) Those who have resided in the townships, towns and street communities for less than 6 months but have been away from the place of their permanent household registration for more than 6 months. d) Those who live in the townships, towns and street communities during the population census while the places of their household registration have not yet settled. e) Those who used to live in the townships, towns and street communities but are working or studying abroad during the census and have no Permanent household registration for the time being.
(3) Two types of questionnaires (long form and short form) were used for the 2000 population census. The short form contains items that reflect the basic situation of the population, while the long form include all short form items plus other items such as migration, education, economic activities, marriage and family, fertility , housing , etc. . According to the Statute for the Fifth National Population Census and the Procedures for the Selection of Samples for the Long Forms, households selected by a random sampling program completed the long forms, and the rest of the households completed the short forms.
(4) The data table consists of three parts. The first part (variables A1-A97 and A154-A156) contains data aggregated from all households data (i. e. common items in both long and short forms) that reflects the basic situation of population. The second part (variables A98-A153 and A157-A169) contains data aggregated from the long forms from the 9.5% sample data, which present various detailed compositions of the population. The third part (variables B1-31) contains socioeconomic variables reported by the National Bureau of Statistics in annual statistics. Please note that there might be some difference between the county population aggregated from the 2000 population Census data and the one reported by government, which is derived from household registration and sample survey data.
(5) Results in this publication are based on the processing of data directly from enumeration without any adjustment. It is therefore worthwhile to notice the following:
    a. Data in the publication do not include population not enumerated in the census.
    b. Data in the publication do not include the 2.5 million servicemen of the People's Liberation Army.
    c. Total population as shown in this publication is 1,242.61 million, or 23.22 million less than the population figure of 1,265.83 million (including 2.5 million servicemen) released earlier by the National Bureau of Statistics ,which was based on the advance tabulation.
    d. The post-enumeration sample survey indicates an undercount of 1.81% in the census enumeration.
    e. The sampling ratio for the long forms = total population in the long forms/total population calculated by computer processing = 9.50%.
    f. The sampling ratio for various compositions of the population may not be the same as household is used as the ultimate sampling unit.
Users should pay attention to the above-mentioned factors when using information in the publication, and in particular, is estimating the population from the sample results.
(5) Regulation on the Classification of Urban/Rural Residence for Statistical Purpose (Provisional) prepared by the National Bureau of Statistics is used in urban/rural classification of the population in this census.</supplinf>
	</descript>
	<timeperd>
		<timeinfo>
			<sngdate>
				<caldate>2000</caldate>
			</sngdate>
		</timeinfo>
		<current>ground condition</current>
	</timeperd>
	<status>
		<progress>Complete</progress>
		<update>Unknown</update>
	</status>
	<spdom>
		<bounding>
			<westbc>
78.956635</westbc>
				<eastbc>
98.984121</eastbc>
					<northbc>
34.079955</northbc>
						<southbc>
27.403888</southbc>
						</bounding>
					</spdom>
					<keywords>
						<theme>
							<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
							<themekey>society</themekey>
							<themekey>boundaries</themekey>
						</theme>
						<theme>
							<themekt>Library of Congress Subject Headings</themekt>
							<themekey>Cities and towns --China --Population --Statistics --Databases.</themekey>
							<themekey>Cities and towns --China --Population --Statistics --Maps.</themekey>
							<themekey>Cities and towns --Census, 2000 --China --Databases.</themekey>
							<themekey>Cities and towns --Census, 2000 --China --Maps.</themekey>
							<themekey>China --Population --Statistics --Databases.</themekey>
							<themekey>China --Population --Statistics --Maps.</themekey>
							<themekey>China --Census, 2000 --Databases.</themekey>
							<themekey>China --Census, 2000 --Maps.</themekey>
						</theme>
						<theme>
							<themekt>None</themekt>
							<themekey>Census</themekey>
							<themekey>Population statistics</themekey>
							<themekey>Demographics</themekey>
							<themekey>Migration</themekey>
							<themekey>Counties</themekey>
							<themekey>Administrative and political divisions</themekey>
							<themekey>Vital statistics</themekey>
							<themekey>Education Statistics</themekey>
							<themekey>Occupations</themekey>
							<themekey>Childbirth Statistics</themekey>
							<themekey>Dwellings</themekey>
							<themekey>Housing Statistics</themekey>
							<themekey>Households</themekey>
							<themekey>Households</themekey>
						</theme>
						<place>
							<placekt>GeoNames</placekt>
							<placekey>Tibet (1279685)</placekey>
						</place>
						<place>
							<placekt>Library of Congress Subject Headings</placekt>
							<placekey>China</placekey>
							<placekey>Xizang (China)</placekey>
							<placekey>Xikang Sheng (China)</placekey>
							<placekey>Tibet (China)</placekey>
						</place>
						<temporal>
							<tempkt>None</tempkt>
							<tempkey>2000</tempkey>
						</temporal>
					</keywords>
					<accconst>For current Columbia affiliates only.</accconst>
					<useconst>For educational, non-commercial use only.</useconst>
					<ptcontac>
						<cntinfo>
							<cntorgp>
								<cntorg>China Data Center - University of Michigan</cntorg>
							</cntorgp>
							<cntaddr>
								<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
								<address>1007 E Huron St</address>
								<city>Ann Arbor</city>
								<state>MI</state>
								<postal>48104</postal>
							</cntaddr>
							<cntvoice>(734) 647-9610</cntvoice>
							<cntfax>(734) 763-0335</cntfax>
							<cntemail>chinadata@umich.edu</cntemail>
						</cntinfo>
					</ptcontac>





					<native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.1850</native>
				</idinfo>
				<dataqual>
					<posacc>
						<horizpa>
							<horizpar>The 2000 China township maps are developed for matching 2000 China population Census data, which should only be used as references for research or education instead of used as official maps. The distributor is not responsible for the accuracy of the those maps if the maps are used for business or other purposes.</horizpar>
						</horizpa>
					</posacc>
					<lineage>
						<procstep>
<procdesc>The 2000 China township GIS maps were developed for the 5th population Census data, which covered all 31 municipalities, provinces and autonomous regions of China, except for Taiwan, Hong Kong and Macao, with more than 50,000 townships (Xiang, Zhen and Jiedao). The 2000 China township maps provide geographical reference for the 5th population census data in spatial data analysis. It will help users to understand the spatial distribution of population and regional difference in China.

The population data came from the 5th China Population Census surveyed in 2000. The GIS data is based on the national digital map (1:1 million) developed by the National Geographic Information Center of China (NGCC), including rives, roads, residential area and administrative boundaries. Other sources "The China Atlas of Standard Place Names", the newly published provincial atlas, the digital city atlas, the street atlas of major cities, the zip code atlas, and the directory of all enterprises and administrative units of China.

The primary work for the 2000 China township maps is to find the geographic location of each township on the 1:1 million digital map of China. The procedures include:

1) Verifying the location of townships on the administrative maps based on 2000 population Census tables, and making the correction to those township names which don't match those names in the Census tables.

2) For those townships of cities at prefecture level and above, we found the location of those townships on the city maps based on their addresses in the directory of all China basic units and zip code.

3) For some virtual townships, which don't have central locations, we try to find the mostly related locations on the map.

4) The administrative boundaries of urban districts of prefecture cities are based on the geographic locations of their townships and related boundary maps.

5) The geographic reference degree data is extracted from the maps with the locations of the townships, compatible with 2000 population Census data.

6) The digital township map (1: 1 million) is converted from the geographic degree data.</procdesc>
							<proccont>
								<cntinfo>
									<cntorgp>
										<cntorg>China Data Center - University of Michigan</cntorg>
									</cntorgp>
									<cntaddr>
										<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
										<address>1007 E Huron St</address>
										<city>Ann Arbor</city>
										<state>MI</state>
										<postal>48104</postal>
									</cntaddr>
									<cntvoice>(734) 647-9610</cntvoice>
									<cntfax>(734) 763-0335</cntfax>
									<cntemail>chinadata@umich.edu</cntemail>
								</cntinfo>
							</proccont>
						</procstep>
					</lineage>
				</dataqual>
				<spdoinfo>
					<direct>Vector</direct>
					<ptvctinf>
						<sdtsterm>
							<sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>
							<ptvctcnt>1</ptvctcnt>
						</sdtsterm>
					</ptvctinf>
				</spdoinfo>
				<spref>
					<horizsys>
						<geodetic>
							<horizdn>D_WGS_1984</horizdn>
							<ellips>WGS_1984</ellips>
							<semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
							<denflat>298.257224</denflat>
						</geodetic>
					</horizsys>
				</spref>
				<eainfo>
					<overview>
<eaover>Tibet 2000 Provincial Population Census Data with Maps
Variable Description
Area The area size
GB  Two digit GB code of province
Gbcode Five digit GB code of province
Cname Name of province in Chinese Pingying
Ename Name of province in English

L503001 Population of Age 15 and Over
L503002 Male Population of Age 15 and Over
L503003 Female Population of Age 15 and Over
L503004 Population of Age 15 and Over: Never Married
L503005 Male Population of Age 15 and Over: Never Married
L503006 Female Population of Age 15 and Over: Never Married
L503007 Population of Age 15 and Over: First Married
L503008 Male Population of Age 15 and Over: First Married
L503009 Female Population of Age 15 and Over: First Married
L503010 Population of Age 15 and Over: Re-married
L503011 Male Population of Age 15 and Over: Re-married
L503012 Female Population of Age 15 and Over: Re-married
L503013 Population of Age 15 and Over: Divorced
L503014 Male Population of Age 15 and Over: Divorced
L503015 Female Population of Age 15 and Over: Divorced
L503016 Population of Age 15 and Over: Widowed
L503017 Male Population of Age 15 and Over: Widowed
L503018 Female Population of Age 15 and Over: Widowed

L601001 The Fertility Rate of Women Aged 15-19(?)
L601002 The Fertility Rate of Women Aged 20-24(?)
L601003 The Fertility Rate of Women Aged 25-29(?)
L601004 The Fertility Rate of Women Aged 30-34(?)
L601005 The Fertility Rate of Women Aged 35-39(?)
L601006 The Fertility Rate of Women Aged 40-44(?)
L601007 The Fertility Rate of Women Aged 45-49(?)
L601008 The Total Fertility Rate(?)

L609001 Women Population Aged 15-50
L609002 Total Number of Live Births of Women Aged 15-50
L609003 Total Number of Live Births of Women Aged 15-50
L609004 Total Number of Live Births of Women Aged 15-50
L609005 Total Number of Surviving Children of Women Aged 15-50
L609006 Total Number of Surviving Children of Women Aged 15-50: Male
L609007 Total Number of Surviving Children of Women Aged 15-50: Female
L609008 Percent of Surviving Children to Live Births
L609009 Woman's average live Births
L609010 Woman's average Surviving Children

L701001 Total Population
L701002 Population Born in This County, City, or District
L701003 Population Born in Other Counties, Cities, or Districts of This Province
L701004 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Beijing
L701005 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Tianjin
L701006 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Hebei
L701007 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Shanxi
L701008 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Inner Mongolia
L701009 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Liaoning
L701010 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Jilin
L701011 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Heilongjiang
L701012 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Shanhai
L701013 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Jiangsu
L701014 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Zhejiang
L701015 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Anhui
L701016 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Fujian
L701017 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Jiangxi
L701018 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Shandong
L701019 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Henai
L701020 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Hubei
L701021 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Hunan
L701022 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Guangdong
L701023 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Guangxi
L701024 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Hainan
L701025 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Chongqing
L701026 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Sichuan
L701027 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Guizhou
L701028 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Yunnan
L701029 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Tibet
L701030 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Shaanxi
L701031 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Gansu
L701032 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Qinghai
L701033 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Ningxia
L701034 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Xinjiang
L701035 Population Born in Other Provinces:  Hong Kong, Macao, Taiwan or Abroad

L702001 Total Population
L702002 Population Who Have Lived Here After Being Born In This Place
L702003 Population Who Moved to This Place Before October 31, 1995
L702004 Population Who Moved to This Place Between November 1, 1995 - December 31, 1995
L702005 Population Who Moved to This Place in 1996
L702006 Population Who Moved to This Place in 1997
L702007 Population Who Moved to This Place in 1998
L702008 Population Who Moved to This Place in 1999
L702009 Population Who Moved to This Place in 2000

L703001 Total Population Moved to This Place
L703002 Total Population Moved to This Place from the Same Province
L703003 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of the Same Province
L703004 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of the Town of the Same Province
L703005 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of the Same Province
L703006 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedaos of the Same Province
L703007 Total Population Moved to This Place from Beijing
L703008 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Beijing
L703009 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Beijing
L703010 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Beijing
L703011 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Beijing
L703012 Total Population Moved to This Place from Tianjin
L703013 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Tianjin
L703014 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Tianjin
L703015 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Tianjin
L703016 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Tianjin
L703017 Total Population Moved to This Place from Hebei
L703018 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Hebei
L703019 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Hebei
L703020 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Hebei
L703021 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Hebei
L703022 Total Population Moved to This Place from Shanxi
L703023 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Shanxi
L703024 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Shanxi
L703025 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Shanxi
L703026 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Shanxi
L703027 Total Population Moved to This Place from Inner Mongolia
L703028 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Inner Mongolia
L703029 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Inner Mongolia
L703030 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Inner Mongolia
L703031 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Inner Mongolia
L703032 Total Population Moved to This Place from Liaoning
L703033 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Liaoning
L703034 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Liaoning
L703035 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Liaoning
L703036 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Liaoning
L703037 Total Population Moved to This Place from Jilin
L703038 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Jilin
L703039 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Jilin
L703040 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Jilin
L703041 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Jilin
L703042 Total Population Moved to This Place from Heilongjiang
L703043 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Heilongjiang
L703044 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Heilongjiang
L703045 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Heilongjiang
L703046 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Heilongjiang
L703047 Total Population Moved to This Place from Shanghai
L703048 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Shanghai
L703049 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Shanghai
L703050 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Shanghai
L703051 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Shanghai
L703052 Total Population Moved to This Place from Jiangsu
L703053 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Jiangsu
L703054 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Jiangsu
L703055 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Jiangsu
L703056 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Jiangsu
L703057 Total Population Moved to This Place from Zhejiang
L703058 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Zhejiang
L703059 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Zhejiang
L703060 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Zhejiang
L703061 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Zhejiang
L703062 Total Population Moved to This Place from Anhui
L703063 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Anhui
L703064 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Anhui
L703065 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Anhui
L703066 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Anhui
L703067 Total Population Moved to This Place from Fujian
L703068 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Fujian
L703069 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Fujian
L703070 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Fujian
L703071 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Fujian
L703072 Total Population Moved to This Place from Jiangxi
L703073 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Jiangxi
L703074 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Jiangxi
L703075 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Jiangxi
L703076 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Jiangxi
L703077 Total Population Moved to This Place from Shandong
L703078 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Shandong
L703079 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Shandong
L703080 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Shandong
L703081 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Shandong
L703082 Total Population Moved to This Place from Henan
L703083 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Henan
L703084 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Henan
L703085 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Henan
L703086 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Henan
L703087 Total Population Moved to This Place from Hubei
L703088 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Hubei
L703089 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Hubei
L703090 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Hubei
L703091 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Hubei
L703092 Total Population Moved to This Place from Hunan
L703093 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Hunan
L703094 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Hunan
L703095 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Hunan
L703096 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Hunan
L703097 Total Population Moved to This Place from Guangdong
L703098 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Guangdong
L703099 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Guangdong
L703100 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Guangdong
L703101 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Guangdong
L703102 Total Population Moved to This Place from Guangxi
L703103 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Guangxi
L703104 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Guangxi
L703105 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Guangxi
L703106 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Guangxi
L703107 Total Population Moved to This Place from Hainan
L703108 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Hainan
L703109 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Hainan
L703110 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Hainan
L703111 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Hainan
L703112 Total Population Moved to This Place from Chongqing
L703113 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Chongqing
L703114 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Chongqing
L703115 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Chongqing
L703116 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Chongqing
L703117 Total Population Moved to This Place from Sichuan
L703118 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Sichuan
L703119 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Sichuan
L703120 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Sichuan
L703121 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Sichuan
L703122 Total Population Moved to This Place from Guizhou
L703123 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Guizhou
L703124 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Guizhou
L703125 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Guizhou
L703126 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Guizhou
L703127 Total Population Moved to This Place from Yunnan
L703128 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Yunnan
L703129 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Yunnan
L703130 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Yunnan
L703131 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Yunnan
L703132 Total Population Moved to This Place from Tibet
L703133 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Tibet
L703134 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Tibet
L703135 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Tibet
L703136 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Tibet
L703137 Total Population Moved to This Place from Shaanxi
L703138 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Shaanxi
L703139 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Shaanxi
L703140 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Shaanxi
L703141 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Shaanxi
L703142 Total Population Moved to This Place from Gansu
L703143 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Gansu
L703144 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Gansu
L703145 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Gansu
L703146 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Gansu
L703147 Total Population Moved to This Place from Qinghai
L703148 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Qinghai
L703149 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Qinghai
L703150 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Qinghai
L703151 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Qinghai
L703152 Total Population Moved to This Place from Ningxia
L703153 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Ningxia
L703154 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Ningxia
L703155 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Ningxia
L703156 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Ningxia
L703157 Total Population Moved to This Place from Xinjiang
L703158 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of Xinjiang
L703159 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of Xinjiang
L703160 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of The Town of Xinjiang
L703161 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of Xinjiang
L703162 Total Population Moved to This Place from Hong Kong,Macao and Taiwan or abroad

L704001 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years
L704002 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from the Same Provinces
L704003 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from the Other Provinces
L704004 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Beijing
L704005 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Tianjin
L704006 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Hebei
L704007 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Shanxi
L704008 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Inner Mongolia
L704009 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Liaoning
L704010 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Jilin
L704011 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Heilongjiang
L704012 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Shanghai
L704013 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Jiangsu
L704014 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Zhejiang
L704015 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Anhui
L704016 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Fujian
L704017 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Jiangxi
L704018 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Shandong
L704019 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Henai
L704020 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Hubei
L704021 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Hunan
L704022 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Guangdong
L704023 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Guangxi
L704024 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Hainan
L704025 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Chongqing
L704026 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Sichuan
L704027 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Guizhou
L704028 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Yunnan
L704029 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Tibet
L704030 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Shaanxi
L704031 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Gansu
L704032 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Qinghai
L704033 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Ningxia
L704034 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Xinjiang
L704035 Total Population Moved to This Place for More Than Five Years from Hong Kong, Macao and Taiwan or abroad

L706001 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Places of the Same Province (intraprovince)
L706002 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of the Same Province (intraprovince)
L706003 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of the Towns of the Same Province (intraprovince)
L706004 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of the Towns of the Same Province (intraprovince)
L706005 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of the Same Province (intraprovince)
L706006 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Places of the Same Province (intraprovince):  No Schooling
L706007 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of the Same Province (intraprovince):  No Schooling
L706008 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of the Towns of the Same Province (intraprovince):  No Schooling
L706009 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of the Towns of the Same Province (intraprovince):  No Schooling
L706010 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of the Same Province (intraprovince):  No Schooling
L706011 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Places of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Eminiate Illiteracy
L706012 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Eminiate Illiteracy
L706013 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of the Towns of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Eminiate Illiteracy
L706014 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of the Towns of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Eminiate Illiteracy
L706015 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Eminiate Illiteracy
L706016 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Places of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Primary School
L706017 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Primary School
L706018 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of the Towns of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Primary School
L706019 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of the Towns of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Primary School
L706020 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Primary School
L706021 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Places of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Junior Middle School
L706022 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Junior Middle School
L706023 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of the Towns of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Junior Middle School
L706024 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of the Towns of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Junior Middle School
L706025 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Junior Middle School
L706026 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Places of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Senior Middle School
L706027 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Senior Middle School
L706028 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of the Towns of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Senior Middle School
L706029 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of the Towns of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Senior Middle School
L706030 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Senior Middle School
L706031 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Places of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Sepcialized secondary school
L706032 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Sepcialized secondary school
L706033 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of the Towns of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Sepcialized secondary school
L706034 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of the Towns of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Sepcialized secondary school
L706035 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Sepcialized secondary school
L706036 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Places of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Junior College
L706037 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Junior College
L706038 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of the Towns of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Junior College
L706039 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of the Towns of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Junior College
L706040 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Junior College
L706041 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Places of the Same Province (intraprovince):  University
L706042 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of the Same Province (intraprovince):  University
L706043 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of the Towns of the Same Province (intraprovince):  University
L706044 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of the Towns of the Same Province (intraprovince):  University
L706045 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of the Same Province (intraprovince):  University
L706046 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Places of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Graduate Student
L706047 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Graduate Student
L706048 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of the Towns of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Graduate Student
L706049 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of the Towns of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Graduate Student
L706050 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of the Same Province (intraprovince):  Graduate Student

L706051 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Places of the Other Province (interprovince)
L706052 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of the Other Province (interprovince)
L706053 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of the Towns of the Other Province (interprovince)
L706054 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of the Towns of the Other Province (interprovince)
L706055 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of the Other Province (interprovince)
L706056 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Places of the Other Province (interprovince):  No Schooling
L706057 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of the Other Province (interprovince):  No Schooling
L706058 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of the Towns of the Other Province (interprovince):  No Schooling
L706059 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of the Towns of the Other Province (interprovince):  No Schooling
L706060 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of the Other Province (interprovince):  No Schooling
L706061 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Places of the Other Province (interprovince):  Eminiate Illiteracy
L706062 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of the Other Province (interprovince):  Eminiate Illiteracy
L706063 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of the Towns of the Other Province (interprovince):  Eminiate Illiteracy
L706064 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of the Towns of the Other Province (interprovince):  Eminiate Illiteracy
L706065 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of the Other Province (interprovince):  Eminiate Illiteracy
L706066 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Places of the Other Province (interprovince):  Primary School
L706067 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of the Other Province (interprovince):  Primary School
L706068 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of the Towns of the Other Province (interprovince):  Primary School
L706069 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of the Towns of the Other Province (interprovince):  Primary School
L706070 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of the Other Province (interprovince):  Primary School
L706071 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Places of the Other Province (interprovince):  Junior Middle School
L706072 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of the Other Province (interprovince):  Junior Middle School
L706073 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of the Towns of the Other Province (interprovince):  Junior Middle School
L706074 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of the Towns of the Other Province (interprovince):  Junior Middle School
L706075 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of the Other Province (interprovince):  Junior Middle School
L706076 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Places of the Other Province (interprovince):  Senior Middle School
L706077 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of the Other Province (interprovince):  Senior Middle School
L706078 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of the Towns of the Other Province (interprovince):  Senior Middle School
L706079 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of the Towns of the Other Province (interprovince):  Senior Middle School
L706080 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of the Other Province (interprovince):  Senior Middle School
L706081 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Places of the Other Province (interprovince):  Sepcialized secondary school
L706082 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of the Other Province (interprovince):  Sepcialized secondary school
L706083 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of the Towns of the Other Province (interprovince):  Sepcialized secondary school
L706084 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of the Towns of the Other Province (interprovince):  Sepcialized secondary school
L706085 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of the Other Province (interprovince):  Sepcialized secondary school
L706086 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Places of the Other Province (interprovince):  Junior College
L706087 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of the Other Province (interprovince):  Junior College
L706088 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of the Towns of the Other Province (interprovince):  Junior College
L706089 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of the Towns of the Other Province (interprovince):  Junior College
L706090 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of the Other Province (interprovince):  Junior College
L706091 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Places of the Other Province (interprovince):  University
L706092 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of the Other Province (interprovince):  University
L706093 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of the Towns of the Other Province (interprovince):  University
L706094 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of the Towns of the Other Province (interprovince):  University
L706095 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of the Other Province (interprovince):  University
L706096 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Places of the Other Province (interprovince):  Graduate Student
L706097 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Townships of the Other Province (interprovince):  Graduate Student
L706098 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Neighbourhood Committees of the Towns of the Other Province (interprovince):  Graduate Student
L706099 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Village Committees of the Towns of the Other Province (interprovince):  Graduate Student
L706100 Total Population Moved to This Place from Other Jiedao of the Other Province (interprovince):  Graduate Student

L707001 Total Migration (intraprovince)
L707002 Total Male Migration (intraprovince)
L707003 Total Female Migration (intraprovince)
L707004 Total Migration (intraprovince):  Administrator/Manager
L707005 Total Male Migration (intraprovince): Administrator/Manager
L707006 Total Female Migration (intraprovince): Administrator/Manager
L707007 Total Migration (intraprovince):  Professional/Technical
L707008 Total Male Migration (intraprovince): Professional/Technical
L707009 Total Female Migration (intraprovince): Professional/Technical
L707010 Total Migration (intraprovince):  Clerical &amp; Related Workers
L707011 Total Male Migration (intraprovince): Clerical &amp; Related Workers
L707012 Total Female Migration (intraprovince): Clerical &amp; Related Workers
L707013 Total Migration (intraprovince):  Sales &amp; Service Workers
L707014 Total Male Migration (intraprovince): Sales &amp; Service Workers
L707015 Total Female Migration (intraprovince): Sales &amp; Service Workers
L707016 Total Migration (intraprovince):  Agriculture &amp; Related Workers
L707017 Total Male Migration (intraprovince): Agriculture &amp; Related Workers
L707018 Total Female Migration (intraprovince): Agriculture &amp; Related Workers
L707019 Total Migration (intraprovince):  Production &amp; Related Workers
L707020 Total Male Migration (intraprovince): Production &amp; Related Workers
L707021 Total Female Migration (intraprovince): Production &amp; Related Workers
L707022 Total Migration (intraprovince):  Not Stated
L707023 Total Male Migration (intraprovince): Not Stated
L707024 Total Female Migration (intraprovince): Not Stated

L707025 Total Migration (interprovince)
L707026 Total Male Migration (interprovince)
L707027 Total Female Migration (interprovince)
L707028 Total Migration (interprovince):  Administrator/Manager
L707029 Total Male Migration (interprovince): Administrator/Manager
L707030 Total Female Migration (interprovince): Administrator/Manager
L707031 Total Migration (interprovince):  Professional/Technical
L707032 Total Male Migration (interprovince): Professional/Technical
L707033 Total Female Migration (interprovince): Professional/Technical
L707034 Total Migration (interprovince):  Clerical &amp; Related Workers
L707035 Total Male Migration (interprovince): Clerical &amp; Related Workers
L707036 Total Female Migration (interprovince): Clerical &amp; Related Workers
L707037 Total Migration (interprovince):  Sales &amp; Service Workers
L707038 Total Male Migration (interprovince): Sales &amp; Service Workers
L707039 Total Female Migration (interprovince): Sales &amp; Service Workers
L707040 Total Migration (interprovince):  Agriculture &amp; Related Workers
L707041 Total Male Migration (interprovince): Agriculture &amp; Related Workers
L707042 Total Female Migration (interprovince): Agriculture &amp; Related Workers
L707043 Total Migration (interprovince):  Production &amp; Related Workers
L707044 Total Male Migration (interprovince): Production &amp; Related Workers
L707045 Total Female Migration (interprovince): Production &amp; Related Workers
L707046 Total Migration (interprovince):  Not Stated
L707047 Total Male Migration (interprovince): Not Stated
L707048 Total Female Migration (interprovince): Not Stated

L708001 Total Women from Other Places (1999 11.l - 2000.10.31)
L708002 Total Women from Other Places (1999 11.l - 2000.10.31): Giving the 1st Birth
L708003 Total Women from Other Places (1999 11.l - 2000.10.31): Giving the 2nd Birth
L708004 Total Women from Other Places (1999 11.l - 2000.10.31): Giving the 3rd Birth &amp; Over
L708005 Total Women from Other Places of the Same Province (1999 11.l - 2000.10.31)
L708006 Total Women from Other Places of the Same Province (1999 11.l - 2000.10.31): Giving the 1st Birth
L708007 Total Women from Other Places of the Same Province (1999 11.l - 2000.10.31): Giving the 2nd Birth
L708008 Total Women from Other Places of the Same Province (1999 11.l - 2000.10.31): Giving the 3rd Birth &amp; Over
L708009 Total Women from Other Province (1999 11.l - 2000.10.31)
L708010 Total Women from Other Province (1999 11.l - 2000.10.31): Giving the 1st Birth
L708011 Total Women from Other Province (1999 11.l - 2000.10.31): Giving the 2nd Birth
L708012 Total Women from Other Province (1999 11.l - 2000.10.31): Giving the 3rd Birth &amp; Over

L801001 Total No. of Households
L801002 No. of Households that Use the House for Daily Life Only
L801003 No. of Households that Share House for Production and Management
L801004 No. of Households Sharing the House With other Households
L801005 No. of Households Without Sharing the House with Other Households
L801006 No. of Households Staying in Bungalow
L801007 No. of Households Staying in Buildings Under 6 Stories
L801008 No. of Households Staying in Building Under 7 Stories
L801009 No. of Households Staying in the House Made of Concrete
L801010 No. of Households Staying in the House Made of Brick and Stone
L801011 No. of Households Staying in the House Made of Wood, Bamboo, and Grass
L801012 No. of Households Staying in the House Made of Other Materials

L802001 Total No. of Households
L802002 Total No. of Rooms
L802003 Total No. of Floor Spaces
L802004  No. of Households Staying in the House Built Before 1949
L802005  No. of Rooms Built Before 1949
L802006  No. of Floor Places Built Before 1949
L802007  No. of Households Staying in the House Built Before 1950-1959
L802008  No. of Rooms Built Before 1950-1959
L802009  No. of Floor Places Built Before 1950-1959
L802010  No. of Households Staying in the House Built Before 1960-1969
L802011  No. of Rooms Built Before 1960-1969
L802012  No. of Floor Places Built Before 1960-1969
L802013  No. of Households Staying in the House Built Before 1970-1979
L802014  No. of Rooms Built Before 1970-1979
L802015  No. of Floor Places Built Before 1970-1979
L802016  No. of Households Staying in the House Built Before 1980-1989
L802017  No. of Rooms Built Before 1980-1989
L802018  No. of Floor Places Built Before 1980-1989
L802019  No. of Households Staying in the House Built Before 1990-1999
L802020  No. of Rooms Built Before 1990-1999
L802021  No. of Floor Places Built Before 1990-1999

L803001 Number of Households
L803002 Number of Households: Using Kitchen By Oneself
L803003 Number of Households: Pubic Kitchen
L803004 Number of Households: No Kitchen
L803005 Number of Households With Main Cooking Fuel: Gas
L803006 Number of Households With Main Cooking Fuel: Electricity
L803007 Number of Households With Main Cooking Fuel: Coal
L803008 Number of Households With Main Cooking Fuel: Firewood
L803009 Number of Households With Main Cooking Fuel: Other
L803010 Number of Households: Using Tap Water
L803011 Number of Households: No Tap Water
L803012 Number of Households: Central Supply of the Hot Water
L803013 Number of Households: Self-installedHot Water Facilities
L803014 Number of Households: Other Facility for Bath
L803015 Number of Households: No Facility for Bath
L803016 Number of Households: Self-Own Pump Toliet
L803017 Number of Households: Sharing the Pump Toliet With Neighbors
L803018 Number of Households: Self-Own Other Types of Toliet
L803019 Number of Households: Sharing Other Types of Toliet With Neighbors
L803020 Number of Households: No Toliet

L804001 No.of Family households
L804002 No.of Family households :Self-built House
L804003 No.of Family households :Buy the Commodity Apartment
L804004 No.of Family households :Buy the Economic Apartment
L804005 No.of Family households :Buy the Original Public-owned House
L804006 No.of Family households :Rent the Public-owned House
L804007 No.of Family households :Rent the Commercial Apartment
L804008 No.of Family households :Other

L805001 No. of Family households With the Purchased House
L805002 No. of Family households With the House Purchased: Under 10,000 yuan
L805003 No. of Family households With the House Purchased: 10,000-20,000 yuan
L805004 No. of Family households With the House Purchased: 20,000-30,000 yuan
L805005 No. of Family households With the House Purchased: 30,000-50,000 yuan
L805006 No. of Family households With the House Purchased: 50,000-100,000 yuan
L805007 No. of Family households With the House Purchased: 100,000-200,000 yuan
L805008 No. of Family households With the House Purchased: 200,000-300,000 yuan
L805009 No. of Family households With the House Purchased: 300,000-500,000 yuan
L805010 No. of Family households With the House Purchased: 500,000 yuan and Over

L806001 No. of Family households With the Rented House
L806002 No. of Family Households With the Monthly Rent: Under 20 yuan
L806003 No. of Family Households With the Monthly Rent: 20-50 yuan
L806004 No. of Family Households With the Monthly Rent: 50-100 yuan
L806005 No. of Family Households With the Monthly Rent: 100-200 yuan
L806006 No. of Family Households With the Monthly Rent: 200-500 yuan
L806007 No. of Family Households With the Monthly Rent: 500-1000 yuan
L806008 No. of Family Households With the Monthly Rent: 1000-1500 yuan
L806009 No. of Family Households With the Monthly Rent: 1500-2000 yuan
L806010 No. of Family Households With the Monthly Rent: 2000 yuan and Over</eaover>
					</overview>
				</eainfo>
				<distinfo>
					<distrib>
						<cntinfo>
							<cntorgp>
								<cntorg>China Data Center - University of Michigan</cntorg>
							</cntorgp>
							<cntaddr>
								<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
								<address>1007 E Huron St</address>
								<city>Ann Arbor</city>
								<state>MI</state>
								<postal>48104</postal>
							</cntaddr>
							<cntvoice>(734) 647-9610</cntvoice>
							<cntfax>(734) 763-0335</cntfax>
							<cntemail>chinadata@umich.edu</cntemail>
						</cntinfo>
					</distrib>
					<resdesc>cdc_2000_tibet_province2000l2</resdesc>
					<stdorder>
						<digform>
							<digtinfo>
								<formname>GeoPackage</formname>
								<formspec>zip</formspec>

								<transize>0.057 MB</transize>
							</digtinfo>
						</digform>
					</stdorder>
				</distinfo>
				<metainfo>
					<metd>20090527</metd>
					<metc>
						<cntinfo>
							<cntorgp>
								<cntorg>Research Data Services (RDS), Columbia University Libraries</cntorg>
								<cntper>GIS/Metadata Librarian</cntper>
							</cntorgp>
							<cntaddr>
								<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
								<address>420 W. 118th St., 215 IAB, MC 3301</address>
								<city>New York</city>
								<state>NY</state>
								<postal>10027</postal>
								<country>USA</country>
							</cntaddr>
							<cntvoice>(212)854-6012</cntvoice>
							<cntemail>data@library.columbia.edu</cntemail>
						</cntinfo>
					</metc>
					<metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
					<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
					<mettc>local time</mettc>
				</metainfo>
			</metadata>
