<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
	<idinfo>
		<citation>
			<citeinfo>
				<origin>University of Michigan. China Data Center</origin>
				<pubdate>2005</pubdate>
				<title>Tibet Province with 2000 Population Census Data From 9.95% Long Form Data (table L1-L4)</title>
				<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
				<serinfo>
					<sername>2000 Tibet Township Population Census Data with GIS Maps</sername>
				</serinfo>
				<pubinfo>
					<pubplace>Beijing</pubplace>
					<publish>Beijing Hua tong ren shi chang xin xi you xian ze ren gong si</publish>
				</pubinfo>
<onlink>https://www1.columbia.edu/sec/acis/eds/dgate/studies/C1301/data/cdc_2000_tibet_province2000l1.zip
			</onlink>
		</citeinfo>
	</citation>
	<descript>
		<langdata>eng</langdata>
		<langdata>chi</langdata>
<abstract>Tibet Province with 2000 Population Census Data From 9.95% Long Form Data (table L1-L4) is a polygon theme representing Tibet Province China in 2000.   Attribute information includes a variety of variables from the long form data from the 2000 Chinese census.

This data layer is part of the Tibet 2000 Township Census data set produced by the All China Marketing Research Co. and distributed by the University of Michigan, China Data Center.</abstract>
		<purpose>The data set was developed for display and analysis using GIS.</purpose>
<supplinf>Notes on China 2000 Population Census Data:
In order to guide you to use the data correctly, provide you some explanations as follows:
(l) Census time: 0:00AM of November 1, 2000 as the reference time for the census.
(2) The 2000 population census covered all persons who hold the nationality of, and have permanent residing place in the People's Republic of China. During the census, each person was enumerated in his/her permanent residing place.
The following persons should be enumerated in their permanent residing place: a) Those who reside in the townships, towns and street communities and have their permanent household registration there. b) Those who have resided in the townships, towns and street communities for more than 6 months but the places of their permanent household registration are elsewhere. c) Those who have resided in the townships, towns and street communities for less than 6 months but have been away from the place of their permanent household registration for more than 6 months. d) Those who live in the townships, towns and street communities during the population census while the places of their household registration have not yet settled. e) Those who used to live in the townships, towns and street communities but are working or studying abroad during the census and have no Permanent household registration for the time being.
(3) Two types of questionnaires (long form and short form) were used for the 2000 population census. The short form contains items that reflect the basic situation of the population, while the long form include all short form items plus other items such as migration, education, economic activities, marriage and family, fertility , housing , etc. . According to the Statute for the Fifth National Population Census and the Procedures for the Selection of Samples for the Long Forms, households selected by a random sampling program completed the long forms, and the rest of the households completed the short forms.
(4) The data table consists of three parts. The first part (variables A1-A97 and A154-A156) contains data aggregated from all households data (i. e. common items in both long and short forms) that reflects the basic situation of population. The second part (variables A98-A153 and A157-A169) contains data aggregated from the long forms from the 9.5% sample data, which present various detailed compositions of the population. The third part (variables B1-31) contains socioeconomic variables reported by the National Bureau of Statistics in annual statistics. Please note that there might be some difference between the county population aggregated from the 2000 population Census data and the one reported by government, which is derived from household registration and sample survey data.
(5) Results in this publication are based on the processing of data directly from enumeration without any adjustment. It is therefore worthwhile to notice the following:
    a. Data in the publication do not include population not enumerated in the census.
    b. Data in the publication do not include the 2.5 million servicemen of the People's Liberation Army.
    c. Total population as shown in this publication is 1,242.61 million, or 23.22 million less than the population figure of 1,265.83 million (including 2.5 million servicemen) released earlier by the National Bureau of Statistics ,which was based on the advance tabulation.
    d. The post-enumeration sample survey indicates an undercount of 1.81% in the census enumeration.
    e. The sampling ratio for the long forms = total population in the long forms/total population calculated by computer processing = 9.50%.
    f. The sampling ratio for various compositions of the population may not be the same as household is used as the ultimate sampling unit.
Users should pay attention to the above-mentioned factors when using information in the publication, and in particular, is estimating the population from the sample results.
(5) Regulation on the Classification of Urban/Rural Residence for Statistical Purpose (Provisional) prepared by the National Bureau of Statistics is used in urban/rural classification of the population in this census.</supplinf>
	</descript>
	<timeperd>
		<timeinfo>
			<sngdate>
				<caldate>2000</caldate>
			</sngdate>
		</timeinfo>
		<current>ground condition</current>
	</timeperd>
	<status>
		<progress>Complete</progress>
		<update>Unknown</update>
	</status>
	<spdom>
		<bounding>
			<westbc>
78.956635</westbc>
				<eastbc>
98.984121</eastbc>
					<northbc>
34.079955</northbc>
						<southbc>
27.403888</southbc>
						</bounding>
					</spdom>
					<keywords>
						<theme>
							<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
							<themekey>Society</themekey>
							<themekey>Boundaries</themekey>
						</theme>
						<theme>
							<themekt>Library of Congress Subject Headings</themekt>
							<themekey>Cities and towns --China --Population --Statistics --Databases.</themekey>
							<themekey>Cities and towns --China --Population --Statistics --Maps.</themekey>
							<themekey>Cities and towns --Census, 2000 --China --Databases.</themekey>
							<themekey>Cities and towns --Census, 2000 --China --Maps.</themekey>
							<themekey>China --Population --Statistics --Databases.</themekey>
							<themekey>China --Population --Statistics --Maps.</themekey>
							<themekey>China --Census, 2000 --Databases.</themekey>
							<themekey>China --Census, 2000 --Maps.</themekey>
						</theme>
						<theme>
							<themekt>None</themekt>
							<themekey>Census</themekey>
							<themekey>Population statistics</themekey>
							<themekey>Demographics</themekey>
							<themekey>Vital statistics</themekey>
							<themekey>Industrial statistics</themekey>
							<themekey>Family</themekey>
							<themekey>Households</themekey>
							<themekey>Occupations</themekey>
							<themekey>Employment</themekey>
							<themekey>Unemployment, Sex Statistics</themekey>
							<themekey>Marital status Statistics</themekey>
							<themekey>Childbirth Statistics</themekey>
							<themekey>Counties</themekey>
							<themekey>Administrative and political divisions</themekey>
							<themekey>Fertility</themekey>
							<themekey>Childbirth Statistics</themekey>
						</theme>
						<place>
							<placekt>GeoNames</placekt>
							<placekey>Tibet</placekey>
						</place>
						<place>
							<placekt>Library of Congress Subject Headings</placekt>
							<placekey>China</placekey>
							<placekey>Xizang (China)</placekey>
							<placekey>Xikang Sheng (China)</placekey>
							<placekey>Tibet (China)</placekey>
						</place>
						<temporal>
							<tempkt>None</tempkt>
							<tempkey>2000</tempkey>
						</temporal>
					</keywords>
					<accconst>For current Columbia affiliates only.</accconst>
					<useconst>For educational, non-commercial use only.</useconst>
					<ptcontac>
						<cntinfo>
							<cntorgp>
								<cntorg>China Data Center - University of Michigan</cntorg>
							</cntorgp>
							<cntaddr>
								<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
								<address>1007 E Huron St</address>
								<city>Ann Arbor</city>
								<state>MI</state>
								<postal>48104</postal>
							</cntaddr>
							<cntvoice>(734) 647-9610</cntvoice>
							<cntfax>(734) 763-0335</cntfax>
							<cntemail>chinadata@umich.edu</cntemail>
						</cntinfo>
					</ptcontac>





					<native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.1850</native>
				</idinfo>
				<dataqual>
					<posacc>
						<horizpa>
							<horizpar>The 2000 China township maps are developed for matching 2000 China population Census data, which should only be used as references for research or education instead of used as official maps. The distributor is not responsible for the accuracy of the those maps if the maps are used for business or other purposes.</horizpar>
						</horizpa>
					</posacc>
					<lineage>
						<procstep>
<procdesc>The 2000 China township GIS maps were developed for the 5th population Census data, which covered all 31 municipalities, provinces and autonomous regions of China, except for Taiwan, Hong Kong and Macao, with more than 50,000 townships (Xiang, Zhen and Jiedao). The 2000 China township maps provide geographical reference for the 5th population census data in spatial data analysis. It will help users to understand the spatial distribution of population and regional difference in China.

The population data came from the 5th China Population Census surveyed in 2000. The GIS data is based on the national digital map (1:1 million) developed by the National Geographic Information Center of China (NGCC), including rives, roads, residential area and administrative boundaries. Other sources "The China Atlas of Standard Place Names", the newly published provincial atlas, the digital city atlas, the street atlas of major cities, the zip code atlas, and the directory of all enterprises and administrative units of China.

The primary work for the 2000 China township maps is to find the geographic location of each township on the 1:1 million digital map of China. The procedures include:

1) Verifying the location of townships on the administrative maps based on 2000 population Census tables, and making the correction to those township names which don't match those names in the Census tables.

2) For those townships of cities at prefecture level and above, we found the location of those townships on the city maps based on their addresses in the directory of all China basic units and zip code.

3) For some virtual townships, which don't have central locations, we try to find the mostly related locations on the map.

4) The administrative boundaries of urban districts of prefecture cities are based on the geographic locations of their townships and related boundary maps.

5) The geographic reference degree data is extracted from the maps with the locations of the townships, compatible with 2000 population Census data.

6) The digital township map (1: 1 million) is converted from the geographic degree data.</procdesc>
							<proccont>
								<cntinfo>
									<cntorgp>
										<cntorg>China Data Center - University of Michigan</cntorg>
									</cntorgp>
									<cntaddr>
										<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
										<address>1007 E Huron St</address>
										<city>Ann Arbor</city>
										<state>MI</state>
										<postal>48104</postal>
									</cntaddr>
									<cntvoice>(734) 647-9610</cntvoice>
									<cntfax>(734) 763-0335</cntfax>
									<cntemail>chinadata@umich.edu</cntemail>
								</cntinfo>
							</proccont>
						</procstep>
					</lineage>
				</dataqual>
				<spdoinfo>
					<direct>Vector</direct>
					<ptvctinf>
						<sdtsterm>
							<sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>
							<ptvctcnt>1</ptvctcnt>
						</sdtsterm>
					</ptvctinf>
				</spdoinfo>
				<spref>
					<horizsys>
						<geodetic>
							<horizdn>D_WGS_1984</horizdn>
							<ellips>WGS_1984</ellips>
							<semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
							<denflat>298.257224</denflat>
						</geodetic>
					</horizsys>
				</spref>
				<eainfo>
					<overview>
<eaover>Tibet 2000 Provincial Population Census Data with Maps
Variable Description
Area The area size
GB  Two digit GB code of province
Gbcode Five digit GB code of province
Cname Name of province in Chinese Pingying
Ename Name of province in English

L101001 Total Households
L101002 Total Family Households
L101003 Total Collective Households
L101004 Total Population
L101005 Total Male
L101006 Total Female
L101007 Total Population Sex Ratio (M/F)
L101008 Population of Family Households
L101009 Male of Family Households
L101010 Female of Family Households
L101011 Population Sex Ratio of Family Households (M/F)
L101012 Population of Collective Households
L101013 Male of Collective Households
L101014 Female of Collective Households
L101015 Population Sex Ratio of Collective Households (M/F)
L101016 Average Population of Family Households

L102001  Total Employment
L102002  Total Employment: Male
L102003  Total Employment: Female
L102004 Employment in Farming, Forestry, Animal, Husbandry and Fishery: Total
L102005 Employment in Farming, Forestry, Animal, Husbandry and Fishery: Male
L102006 Employment in Farming, Forestry, Animal, Husbandry and Fishery: Female
L102007 Employment in Mining and Quarrying:
L102008 Employment in Mining and Quarrying: Male
L102009 Employment in Mining and Quarrying: Female
L102010 Employment in Manufacturing:
L102011 Employment in Manufacturing: Male
L102012 Employment in Manufacturing: Female
L102013 Employment in Electric Power, Gas and Water Production and Supply:
L102014 Employment in Electric Power, Gas and Water Production and Supply: Male
L102015 Employment in Electric Power, Gas and Water Production and Supply: Female
L102016 Employment in Construction:
L102017 Employment in Construction: Male
L102018 Employment in Construction: Female
L102019 Employment in Geological Prospecting and Water Conservancy:
L102020 Employment in Geological Prospecting and Water Conservancy: Male
L102021 Employment in Geological Prospecting and Water Conservancy: Female
L102022 Employment in Transportation, Storage, Postal and Telecommunications Services:
L102023 Employment in Transportation, Storage, Postal and Telecommunications Services: Male
L102024 Employment in Transportation, Storage, Postal and Telecommunications Services: Female
L102025 Employment in Wholesale and Retail Trade, Catering Services:
L102026 Employment in Wholesale and Retail Trade, Catering Services: Male
L102027 Employment in Wholesale and Retail Trade, Catering Services: Female
L102028 Employment in Banking and Insurance:
L102029 Employment in Banking and Insurance: Male
L102030 Employment in Banking and Insurance: Female
L102031 Employment in Real Estate Management:
L102032 Employment in Real Estate Management: Male
L102033 Employment in Real Estate Management: Female
L102034 Employment in Social Services:
L102035 Employment in Social Services: Male
L102036 Employment in Social Services: Female
L102037 Employment in Health Care, Sport and Social Welfare:
L102038 Employment in Health Care, Sport and Social Welfare: Male
L102039 Employment in Health Care, Sport and Social Welfare: Female
L102040 Employment in Education, Culture and Arts, Radio, Film and Television:
L102041 Employment in Education, Culture and Arts, Radio, Film and Television: Male
L102042 Employment in Education, Culture and Arts, Radio, Film and Television: Female
L102043 Employment in Scientific Research and Polytechnical Services:
L102044 Employment in Scientific Research and Polytechnical Services: Male
L102045 Employment in Scientific Research and Polytechnical Services: Female
L102046 Employment in Government Agencies, Party Agencies and Social Orangnizations:
L102047 Employment in Government Agencies, Party Agencies and Social Orangnizations: Male
L102048 Employment in Government Agencies, Party Agencies and Social Orangnizations: Female
L102049 Employment in Other Sectors:
L102050 Employment in Other Sectors: Male
L102051 Employment in Other Sectors: Female

L103001 Total Employment
L103002 Employment in Total Employment: Male
L103003 Employment in Total Employment: Female
L103004 Employment in Government Agencies
L103005 Employment in Government Agencies: Male
L103006 Employment in Government Agencies: Female
L103007 Employment in Professional/Technical
L103008 Employment in Professional/Technical: Male
L103009 Employment in Professional/Technical: Female
L103010 Employment in Clerical &amp; Related Workers
L103011 Employment in Clerical &amp; Related Workers: Male
L103012 Employment in Clerical &amp; Related Workers: Female
L103013 Employment in Sales and Services
L103014 Employment in Sales and Services: Male
L103015 Employment in Sales and Services: Female
L103016 Employment in Farming, Forestry, Husbandry, Fishery and Water Conservancy
L103017 Employment in Farming, Forestry, Husbandry, Fishery and Water Conservancy: Male
L103018 Employment in Farming, Forestry, Husbandry, Fishery and Water Conservancy: Female
L103019 Employment in Production &amp; Transportation Facility
L103020 Employment in Production &amp; Transportation Facility: Male
L103021 Employment in Production &amp; Transportation Facility: Female
L103022 Employment in Others
L103023 Employment in Others: Male
L103024 Employment in Others: Female

L104001 Unemployed Population
L104002 Unemployed Population
L104003 Unemployed Population
L104004 Unemployed Population: Current Students
L104005 Unemployed Male Population: Current Students
L104006 Unemployed Female Population: Current Students
L104007 Unemployed Population: Housework
L104008 Unemployed Male Population: Housework
L104009 Unemployed Female Population: Housework
L104010 Unemployed Population: Retired
L104011 Unemployed Male Population: Retired
L104012 Unemployed Female Population: Retired
L104013 Unemployed Population: Lose the Ability to Work
L104014 Unemployed Male Population: Lose the Ability to Work
L104015 Unemployed Female Population: Lose the Ability to Work
L104016 Unemployed Population: Have Never Worked and Looking for A Job
L104017 Unemployed Male Population: Have Never Worked and Looking for A Job
L104018 Unemployed Female Population: Have Never Worked and Looking for A Job
L104019 Unemployed Population: Lose Job and Looking for A Job
L104020 Unemployed Male Population: Lose Job and Looking for A Job
L104021 Unemployed Female Population: Lose Job and Looking for A Job
L104022 Unemployed Population: Other
L104023 Unemployed Male Population: Others
L104024 Unemployed Female Population: Others

L105001 Total Population Aged 15 and over
L105002 Total Population Aged 15 and over: Male
L105003 Total Population Aged 15 and over: Female
L105004 Total Employment: Female
L105005 Total Employment: Male
L105006 Total Employment: Female
L105007 Total Unemployment
L105008 Total Unemployment: Male
L105009 Total Unemployment: Female
L105010 Unemployment Rate
L105011 Unemployment Rate: Male
L105012 Unemployment Rate: Female

L106001 Population aged 15 and over
L106002 Population aged 15 and over: Male
L106003 Population aged 15 and over: Female
L106004 Population Never Married
L106005 Population Never Married: Male
L106006 Population Never Married: Female
L106007 Population First Married
L106008 Population First Married: Male
L106009 Population First Married: Female
L106010 Population Re-married
L106011 Population Re-married: Male
L106012 Population Re-married: Female
L106013 Population Divorced
L106014 Population Divorced: Male
L106015 Population Divorced: Female
L106016 Population Widowed
L106017 Population Widowed: Male
L106018 Population Widowed: Female

L107001 Number of Birth
L107002 Number of Birth: Male
L107003 Number of Birth: Female
L107004 Number of Birth: Sex Ratio
L107005 Number of 1st Birth
L107006 Number of 1st Birth: Male
L107007 Number of 1st Birth: Female
L107008 Number of 1st Birth: Sex Ratio
L107009 Number of 2nd Birth
L107010 Number of 2nd Birth: Male
L107011 Number of 2nd Birth: Female
L107012 Number of 2nd Birth: Sex Ratio
L107013 Number of 3rd Birth
L107014 Number of 3rd Birth: Male
L107015 Number of 3rd Birth: Female
L107016 Number of 3rd Birth: Sex Ratio
L107017 Number of 4th Birth
L107018 Number of 4th Birth: Male
L107019 Number of 4th Birth: Female
L107020 Number of 4th Birth: Sex Ratio
L107021 Number of 5th Birth and Over
L107022 Number of 5th Birth and Over: Male
L107023 Number of 5th Birth and Over: Female
L107024 Number of 5th Birth and Over: Sex Ratio

L109001 Women between Aged 15 to 50
L109002 Women between Aged 15 to 50 with 0 Surviving Births
L109003 Women between Aged 15 to 50 with 1 Surviving Births
L109004 Women between Aged 15 to 50 with 2 Surviving Births
L109005 Women between Aged 15 to 50 with 3 Surviving Births
L109006 Women between Aged 15 to 50 with 4 Surviving Births
L109007 Women between Aged 15 to 50 with 5 and over Surviving Births
L109008 Average Number of Surviving Births Per Women

L108001 Women between Aged 15 to 50
L108002 Women between Aged 15 to 50 with 0 Living Births
L108003 Women between Aged 15 to 50 with 1 Living Births
L108004 Women between Aged 15 to 50 with 2 Living Births
L108005 Women between Aged 15 to 50 with 3 Living Births
L108006 Women between Aged 15 to 50 with 4 Living Births
L108007 Women between Aged 15 to 50 with 5 and over Living Births
L108008 Average Number of Living Births Per Women

L401001 Total Employed Population
L401002 Total Employed Population: Male
L401003 Total Employed Population: Female
L401004 Employed Population in Farming, Forestry, Animal Husbandry and Fishery
L401005 Employed Population in Farming, Forestry, Animal Husbandry and Fishery: Male
L401006 Employed Population in Farming, Forestry, Animal Husbandry and Fishery: Female
L401007 Employed Population in Farming
L401008 Employed Population in Farming: Male
L401009 Employed Population in Farming: Female
L401010 Employed Population in Forestry
L401011 Employed Population in Forestry: Male
L401012 Employed Population in Forestry: Female
L401013 Employed Population in Animal Husbandry
L401014 Employed Population in Animal Husbandry: Male
L401015 Employed Population in Animal Husbandry: Female
L401016 Employed Population in Fishery
L401017 Employed Population in Fishery: Male
L401018 Employed Population in Fishery: Female
L401019 Employed Population in Agricultural Services
L401020 Employed Population in Agricultural Services: Male
L401021 Employed Population in Agricultural Services: Female
L401022 Employed Population in Mining and Quarrying
L401023 Employed Population in Mining and Quarrying: Male
L401024 Employed Population in Mining and Quarrying: Female
L401025 Employed Population in Coal Mining and Dressing
L401026 Employed Population in Coal Mining and Dressing : Male
L401027 Employed Population in Coal Mining and Dressing : Female
L401028 Employed Population in Extraction of petroleum and Natural Gas
L401029 Employed Population in Extraction of petroleum and Natural Gas: Male
L401030 Employed Population in Extraction of petroleum and Natural Gas: Female
L401031 Employed Population in Mining and Dressing of Ferrous Metals
L401032 Employed Population in Mining and Dressing of Ferrous Metals: Male
L401033 Employed Population in Mining and Dressing of Ferrous Metals: Female
L401034 Employed Population in Mining and Dressing of Nonferrous Metals
L401035 Employed Population in Mining and Dressing of Nonferrous Metals: Male
L401036 Employed Population in Mining and Dressing of Nonferrous Metals: Female
L401037 Employed Population in Mining and Dressing of Nonmetal Minerals
L401038 Employed Population in Mining and Dressing of Nonmetal Minerals: Male
L401039 Employed Population in Mining and Dressing of Nonmetal Minerals: Female
L401040 Employed Population in Mining and Dressing of Other Minerals
L401041 Employed Population in Mining and Dressing of Other Minerals: Male
L401042 Employed Population in Mining and Dressing of Other Minerals: Female
L401043 Employed Population in Logging and Transport of Wood and Bamboo
L401044 Employed Population in Logging and Transport of Wood and Bamboo: Male
L401045 Employed Population in Logging and Transport of Wood and Bamboo: Female
L401046 Employed Population in Manufacturing
L401047 Employed Population in Manufacturing: Male
L401048 Employed Population in Manufacturing: Female
L401049 Employed Population in Food Processing
L401050 Employed Population in Food Processing: Male
L401051 Employed Population in Food Processing: Female
L401052 Employed Population in Food Production
L401053 Employed Population in Food Production: Male
L401054 Employed Population in Food Production: Female
L401055 Employed Population in Beverages
L401056 Employed Population in Beverages: Male
L401057 Employed Population in Beverages: Female
L401058 Employed Population in Tobacco
L401059 Employed Population in Tobacco: Male
L401060 Employed Population in Tobacco: Female
L401061 Employed Population in Textiles
L401062 Employed Population in Textiles: Male
L401063 Employed Population in Textiles: Female
L401064 Employed Population in Garments and Other Fiber Products
L401065 Employed Population in Garments and Other Fiber Products: Male
L401066 Employed Population in Garments and Other Fiber Products: Female
L401067 Employed Population in Leather, Furs, Down and Related Products
L401068 Employed Population in Leather, Furs, Down and Related Products: Male
L401069 Employed Population in Leather, Furs, Down and Related Products: Female
L401070 Employed Population in Timber Processing, Bamboo, Cane, Palm Fiber and Straw Products
L401071 Employed Population in Timber Processing, Bamboo, Cane, Palm Fiber and Straw Products: Male
L401072 Employed Population in Timber Processing, Bamboo, Cane, Palm Fiber and Straw Products: Female
L401073 Employed Population in Furniture Manufacturing
L401074 Employed Population in Furniture Manufacturing: Male
L401075 Employed Population in Furniture Manufacturing: Female
L401076 Employed Population in Papermaking and Paper Products
L401077 Employed Population in Papermaking and Paper Products: Male
L401078 Employed Population in Papermaking and Paper Products: Female
L401079 Employed Population in Printing and Record Medium Reproduction
L401080 Employed Population in Printing and Record Medium Reproduction: Male
L401081 Employed Population in Printing and Record Medium Reproduction: Female
L401082 Employed Population in Cultural, Educational and Sports Goods
L401083 Employed Population in Cultural, Educational and Sports Goods: Male
L401084 Employed Population in Cultural, Educational and Sports Goods: Female
L401085 Employed Population in Petroleum Processing and Coking
L401086 Employed Population in Petroleum Processing and Coking: Male
L401087 Employed Population in Petroleum Processing and Coking: Female
L401088 Employed Population in Raw Chemical Materials and Chemical Products
L401089 Employed Population in Raw Chemical Materials and Chemical Products: Male
L401090 Employed Population in Raw Chemical Materials and Chemical Products: Female
L401091 Employed Population in Medical and Pharmaceutical Products
L401092 Employed Population in Medical and Pharmaceutical Products: Male
L401093 Employed Population in Medical and Pharmaceutical Products: Female
L401094 Employed Population in Chemical Fiber
L401095 Employed Population in Chemical Fiber: Male
L401096 Employed Population in Chemical Fiber: Female
L401097 Employed Population in Rubber Products
L401098 Employed Population in Rubber Products: Male
L401099 Employed Population in Rubber Products: Female
L401100 Employed Population in Plastic Products
L401101 Employed Population in Plastic Products: Male
L401102 Employed Population in Plastic Products: Female
L401103 Employed Population in Nonmetal Mineral Products
L401104 Employed Population in Nonmetal Mineral Products: Male
L401105 Employed Population in Nonmetal Mineral Products: Female
L401106 Employed Population in Smelting and Pressing of Ferrous Metals
L401107 Employed Population in Smelting and Pressing of Ferrous Metals: Male
L401108 Employed Population in Smelting and Pressing of Ferrous Metals: Female
L401109 Employed Population in Smelting and Pressing of Nonferrous Metals
L401110 Employed Population in Smelting and Pressing of Nonferrous Metals: Male
L401111 Employed Population in Smelting and Pressing of Nonferrous Metals: Female
L401112 Employed Population in Metal Products
L401113 Employed Population in Metal Products: Male
L401114 Employed Population in Metal Products: Female
L401115 Employed Population in Ordinary Machinery
L401116 Employed Population in Ordinary Machinery: Male
L401117 Employed Population in Ordinary Machinery: Female
L401118 Employed Population in Equipment for Special Purposes
L401119 Employed Population in Equipment for Special Purposes: Male
L401120 Employed Population in Equipment for Special Purposes: Female
L401121 Employed Population in Transport Equipment
L401122 Employed Population in Transport Equipment: Male
L401123 Employed Population in Transport Equipment: Female
L401124 Employed Population in Weapons and ammunitions
L401125 Employed Population in Weapons and ammunitions: Male
L401126 Employed Population in Weapons and ammunitions: Female
L401127 Employed Population in Electric Equipment and Machinery
L401128 Employed Population in Electric Equipment and Machinery: Male
L401129 Employed Population in Electric Equipment and Machinery: Female
L401130 Employed Population in Electronic and Telecommunications Equipment
L401131 Employed Population in Electronic and Telecommunications Equipment: Male
L401132 Employed Population in Electronic and Telecommunications Equipment: Female
L401133 Employed Population instruments, Meters, Cultural and Office Machinery
L401134 Employed Population instruments, Meters, Cultural and Office Machinery: Male
L401135 Employed Population in Instruments, Meters, Cultural and Office Machinery: Female
L401136 Employed Population in Other Manufacturing
L401137 Employed Population in Other Manufacturing: Male
L401138 Employed Population in Other Manufacturing: Female
L401139 Employed Population in Production and Supply of Electric Power, Gas and Water
L401140 Employed Population in Production and Supply of Electric Power, Gas and Water: Male
L401141 Employed Population in Production and Supply of Electric Power, Gas and Water: Female
L401142 Employed Population in Production and Supply of Electric Power, Steam and Hot Water
L401143 Employed Population in Production and Supply of Electric Power, Steam and Hot Water: Male
L401144 Employed Population in Production and Supply of Electric Power, Steam and Hot Water: Female
L401145 Employed Population in Production and Supply of Gas
L401146 Employed Population in Production and Supply of Gas: Male
L401147 Employed Population in Production and Supply of Gas: Female
L401148 Employed Population in Production and Supply of Tap Water
L401149 Employed Population in Production and Supply of Tap Water: Male
L401150 Employed Population in Production and Supply of Tap Water: Female
L401151 Employed Population in Construction
L401152 Employed Population in Construction: Male
L401153 Employed Population in Construction: Female
L401154 Employed Population in Civil Engineering Construction
L401155 Employed Population in Civil Engineering Construction: Male
L401156 Employed Population in Civil Engineering Construction: Female
L401157 Employed Population installation of lines, Pipelines and Equipment
L401158 Employed Population installation of lines, Pipelines and Equipment: Male
L401159 Employed Population in Installation of lines, Pipelines and Equipment: Female
L401160 Employed Population in Fitting and Decoration
L401161 Employed Population in Fitting and Decoration: Male
L401162 Employed Population in Fitting and Decoration: Female
L401163 Employed Population in Geological Prospecting and Water Conservancy
L401164 Employed Population in Geological Prospecting and Water Conservancy: Male
L401165 Employed Population in Geological Prospecting and Water Conservancy: Female
L401166 Employed Population in Geological Prospecting
L401167 Employed Population in Geological Prospecting: Male
L401168 Employed Population in Geological Prospecting: Female
L401169 Employed Population in Water Conservancy
L401170 Employed Population in Water Conservancy: Male
L401171 Employed Population in Water Conservancy: Female
L401172 Employed Population in Transport, Storage, Postal and Telecommunication Services
L401173 Employed Population in Transport, Storage, Postal and Telecommunication Services: Male
L401174 Employed Population in Transport, Storage, Postal and Telecommunication Services: Female
L401175 Employed Population in Railway Transport
L401176 Employed Population in Railway Transport: Male
L401177 Employed Population in Railway Transport: Female
L401178 Employed Population in Highway Transport
L401179 Employed Population in Highway Transport: Male
L401180 Employed Population in Highway Transport: Female
L401181 Employed Population in Pipeline Transport
L401182 Employed Population in Pipeline Transport: Male
L401183 Employed Population in Pipeline Transport: Female
L401184 Employed Population in Waterway Transport
L401185 Employed Population in Waterway Transport: Male
L401186 Employed Population in Waterway Transport: Female
L401187 Employed Population in Air Transport
L401188 Employed Population in Air Transport: Male
L401189 Employed Population in Air Transport: Female
L401190 Employed Population in Transport Subsidiary Services
L401191 Employed Population in Transport Subsidiary Services: Male
L401192 Employed Population in Transport Subsidiary Services: Female
L401193 Employed Population in Other Transport
L401194 Employed Population in Other Transport: Male
L401195 Employed Population in Other Transport: Female
L401196 Employed Population in Storage
L401197 Employed Population in Storage: Male
L401198 Employed Population in Storage: Female
L401199 Employed Population in Postal and Telecommunications Services
L401200 Employed Population in Postal and Telecommunications Services: Male
L401201 Employed Population in Postal and Telecommunications Services: Female
L401202 Employed Population in Wholesale &amp; Retail Trade and Catering Services
L401203 Employed Population in Wholesale &amp; Retail Trade and Catering Services: Male
L401204 Employed Population in Wholesale &amp; Retail Trade and Catering Services: Female
L401205 Employed Population in Wholesale Trade of Food, Beverage, Tobacco and Household Articles
L401206 Employed Population in Wholesale Trade of Food, Beverage, Tobacco and Household Articles: Male
L401207 Employed Population in Wholesale Trade of Food, Beverage, Tobacco and Household Articles: Female
L401208 Employed Population in Wholesale Trade of Energy, Materials and Electronic Equipment
L401209 Employed Population in Wholesale Trade of Energy, Materials and Electronic Equipment: Male
L401210 Employed Population in Wholesale Trade of Energy, Materials and Electronic Equipment: Female
L401211 Employed Population in Other Wholesale Trade
L401212 Employed Population in Other Wholesale Trade: Male
L401213 Employed Population in Other Wholesale Trade: Female
L401214 Employed Population in Retail Trade
L401215 Employed Population in Retail Trade: Male
L401216 Employed Population in Retail Trade: Female
L401217 Employed Population in Commercial Brokerage and Agencies
L401218 Employed Population in Commercial Brokerage and Agencies: Male
L401219 Employed Population in Commercial Brokerage and Agencies: Female
L401220 Employed Population in Catering Trade
L401221 Employed Population in Catering Trade: Male
L401222 Employed Population in Catering Trade: Female
L401223 Employed Population in Finance and Insurance
L401224 Employed Population in Finance and Insurance: Male
L401225 Employed Population in Finance and Insurance: Female
L401226 Employed Population in Finance
L401227 Employed Population in Finance: Male
L401228 Employed Population in Finance: Female
L401229 Employed Population insurance
L401230 Employed Population insurance: Male
L401231 Employed Population in Insurance: Female
L401232 Employed Population in Real Estate
L401233 Employed Population in Real Estate: Male
L401234 Employed Population in Real Estate: Female
L401235 Employed Population in Real Estate Development and Operation
L401236 Employed Population in Real Estate Development and Operation: Male
L401237 Employed Population in Real Estate Development and Operation: Female
L401238 Employed Population in Real Estate Management
L401239 Employed Population in Real Estate Management: Male
L401240 Employed Population in Real Estate Management: Female
L401241 Employed Population in Real Estate Brokerage and Agencies
L401242 Employed Population in Real Estate Brokerage and Agencies: Male
L401243 Employed Population in Real Estate Brokerage and Agencies: Female
L401244 Employed Population in Social Services
L401245 Employed Population in Social Services: Male
L401246 Employed Population in Social Services: Female
L401247 Employed Population in Public Services
L401248 Employed Population in Public Services: Male
L401249 Employed Population in Public Services: Female
L401250 Employed Population in Resident Services
L401251 Employed Population in Resident Services: Male
L401252 Employed Population in Resident Services: Female

L401253 Employed Population in Hotels
L401254 Employed Population in Hotels: Male
L401255 Employed Population in Hotels: Female
L401256 Employed Population in Leasing Services
L401257 Employed Population in Leasing Services: Male
L401258 Employed Population in Leasing Services: Female
L401259 Employed Population in Touris
L401260 Employed Population in Touris: Male
L401261 Employed Population in Touris: Female
L401262 Employed Population in Recreational Services
L401263 Employed Population in Recreational Services: Male
L401264 Employed Population in Recreational Services: Femaleemale
L401265 Employed Population in Information and Consultative Services
L401266 Employed Population in Information and Consultative Services: Maleale
L401267 Employed Population in Information and Consultative Services: Femaleemale
L401268 Employed Population in Computer Application Services
L401269 Employed Population in Computer Application Services: Maleale
L401270 Employed Population in Computer Application Services: Femaleemale
L401271 Employed Population in Other Social Services
L401272 Employed Population in Other Social Services: Maleale
L401273 Employed Population in Other Social Services: Female
L401274 Employed Population in Health Care, Sports and Social Welfare
L401275 Employed Population in Health Care, Sports and Social Welfare: Male
L401276 Employed Population in Health Care, Sports and Social Welfare: Female
L401277 Employed Population in Health Care
L401278 Employed Population in Health Care: Male
L401279 Employed Population in Health Care: Female
L401280 Employed Population in Sports
L401281 Employed Population in Sports: Male
L401282 Employed Population in Sports: Female
L401283 Employed Population in Social Welfare and Social Security
L401284 Employed Population in Social Welfare and Social Security: Male
L401285 Employed Population in Social Welfare and Social Security: Female
L401286 Employed Population in Education, Culture and Arts, Radio, Film Television
L401287 Employed Population in Education, Culture and Arts, Radio, Film Television: Male
L401288 Employed Population in Education, Culture and Arts, Radio, Film Television: Female
L401289 Employed Population in Education
L401290 Employed Population in Education: Male
L401291 Employed Population in Education: Female
L401292 Employed Population in Culture and Arts
L401293 Employed Population in Culture and Arts: Male
L401294 Employed Population in Culture and Arts: Female
L401295 Employed Population in Radio, Film Television
L401296 Employed Population in Radio, Film Television: Male
L401297 Employed Population in Radio, Film Television: Female
L401298 Employed Population in Scientific Research and Polytechnic Services
L401299 Employed Population in Scientific Research and Polytechnic Services: Male
L401300 Employed Population in Scientific Research and Polytechnic Services: Female
L401301 Employed Population in Scientific Research
L401302 Employed Population in Scientific Research: Male
L401303 Employed Population in Scientific Research: Female
L401304 Employed Population in Polytechnic Services
L401305 Employed Population in Polytechnic Services: Male
L401306 Employed Population in Polytechnic Services: Female
L401307 Employed Population in Governments Agencies, Party agencies and Social Organizations
L401308 Employed Population in Governments Agencies, Party agencies and Social Organizations: Male
L401309 Employed Population in Governments Agencies, Party agencies and Social Organizations: Female
L401310 Employed Population in Governments
L401311 Employed Population in Governments: Male
L401312 Employed Population in Governments: Female
L401313 Employed Population in Party
L401314 Employed Population in Party: Male
L401315 Employed Population in Party: Female
L401316 Employed Population in Social Organizations
L401317 Employed Population in Social Organizations: Male
L401318 Employed Population in Social Organizations: Female
L401319 Employed Population in Self-discipline organization of masses at the basic level
L401320 Employed Population in Self-discipline organization of masses at the basic level: Male
L401321 Employed Population in Self-discipline organization of masses at the basic level: Female
L401322 Employed Population in Others Industry
L401323 Employed Population in Others Industry: Male
L401324 Employed Population in Others Industry: Female
L401325 Employed Population in Others Industry
L401326 Employed Population in Others Industry: Male
L401327 Employed Population in Others Industry: Female

L402001 Total Employed Population
L402002 Total Employed Population: Male
L402003 Total Employed Population: Female
L402004 Employed Population of Administrator/Manager
L402005 Employed Population of Administrator/Manager: Male
L402006 Employed Population of Administrator/Manager: Female
L402007 Employed Population of Responsible Persons of the Central Committee of The Communist Party of China and of Different Local Organizations
L402008 Employed Population of Responsible Persons of the Central Committee of The Communist Party of China and of Different Local Organizations : Male
L402009 Employed Population of Responsible Persons of the Central Committee of The Communist Party of China and of Different Local Organizations: Female
L402010 Employed Population of Responsible Persons of Government Offices and Their Working Organizations
L402011 Employed Population of Responsible Persons of Government Offices and Their Working Organizations: Male
L402012 Employed Population of Responsible Persons of Government Offices and Their Working Organizations: Female
L402013 Employed Population of Responsible Persons of the Working Organizations of Democratic Party and Public Organization
L402014 Employed Population of Responsible Persons of the Working Organizations of Democratic Party and Public Organization: Male
L402015 Employed Population of Responsible Persons of the Working Organizations of Democratic Party and Public Organization: Female
L402016 Employed Population of Institution Unit Head
L402017 Employed Population of Institution Unit Head: Male
L402018 Employed Population of Institution Unit Head: Female
L402019 Employed Population of Enterprise Director
L402020 Employed Population of Enterprise Director: Male
L402021 Employed Population of Enterprise Director: Female
L402022 Employed Population of Professional/Technical
L402023 Employed Population of Professional/Technical: Male
L402024 Employed Population of Professional/Technical: Female
L402025 Employed Population of Scientific Researchers
L402026 Employed Population of Scientific Researchers: Male
L402027 Employed Population of Scientific Researchers: Female
L402028 Employed Population of Engineers and Technicians
L402029 Employed Population of Engineers and Technicians : Male
L402030 Employed Population of Engineers and Technicians : Female
L402031 Employed Population of Agricultural Technical Staff
L402032 Employed Population of Agricultural Technical Staff : Male
L402033 Employed Population of Agricultural Technical Staff : Female
L402034 Employed Population of the Air Plane and Ship Technical Staff
L402035 Employed Population of the Air Plane and Ship Technical Staff : Male
L402036 Employed Population of the Air Plane and Ship Technical Staff : Female
L402037 Employed Population of Hygienic Professional and Technical Personnel
L402038 Employed Population of Hygienic Professional and Technical Personnel: Male
L402039 Employed Population of Hygienic Professional and Technical Personnel: Female
L402040 Employed Population of Economic Business Personnel
L402041 Employed Population of Economic Business Personnel: Male
L402042 Employed Population of Economic Business Personnel: Female
L402043 Employed Population of Financial Business Personnel
L402044 Employed Population of Financial Business Personnel : Male
L402045 Employed Population of Financial Business Personnel : Female
L402046 Employed Population of Professional Personnel of Law
L402047 Employed Population of Professional Personnel of Law : Male
L402048 Employed Population of Professional Personnel of Law : Female
L402049 Employed Population of Teaching Personnel
L402050 Employed Population of Teaching Personnel: Male
L402051 Employed Population of Teaching Personnel: Female
L402052 Employed Population of Literature and Art Staff Member
L402053 Employed Population of Literature and Art Staff Member : Male
L402054 Employed Population of Literature and Art Staff Member : Female
L402055 Employed Population of Sports Staff Member
L402056 Employed Population of Sports Staff Member : Male
L402057 Employed Population of Sports Staff Member : Female
L402058 Employed Population of Journalism,Culture Staff Member
L402059 Employed Population of Journalism,Culture Staff Member: Male
L402060 Employed Population of Journalism,Culture Staff Member: Female
L402061 Employed Population of Religion Job Person
L402062 Employed Population of Religion Job Person : Male
L402063 Employed Population of Religion Job Person : Female
L402064 Employed Population of Other Professional and Technical Personnel
L402065 Employed Population of Other Professional and Technical Personnels: Male
L402066 Employed Population of Other Professional and Technical Personnels: Female
L402067 Employed Population of Clerk and Related Workers
L402068 Employed Population of Clerk and Related Workers: Male
L402069 Employed Population of Clerk and Related Workers: Female
L402070 Employed Population of Administration Official Personnel
L402071 Employed Population of Administration Official Personnel: Male
L402072 Employed Population of Administration Official Personnel: Female
L402073 Employed Population of Security,Safeguard and Fire Fighter
L402074 Employed Population of Security, Safeguard and Fire Fighter : Male
L402075 Employed Population of Security, Safeguard and Fire Fighter : Female
L402076 Employed Population of Postal Service and Telecommunications Business Personnel
L402077 Employed Population of Postal Service and Telecommunications Business Personnel : Male
L402078 Employed Population of Postal Service and Telecommunications Business Personnel : Female
L402079 Employed Population of Other Clerk and Related Workers
L402080 Employed Population of Other Clerk and Related Workers: Male
L402081 Employed Population of Other Clerk and Related Workers: Female
L402082 Employed Population of Commerce, Service Trade Personnel
L402083 Employed Population of Commerce, Service Trade Personnel: Male
L402084 Employed Population of Commerce, Service Trade Personnel: Female
L402085 Employed Population of Purchase and Sales Personnel
L402086 Employed Population of Purchase and Sales Personnel : Male
L402087 Employed Population of Purchase and Sales Personnel : Female
L402088 Employed Population of Store-house Personnel
L402089 Employed Population of Store-house Personnel : Male
L402090 Employed Population of Store-house Personnel : Female
L402091 Employed Population of Catering and Beverage Attendants
L402092 Employed Population of Catering and Beverage Attendants : Male
L402093 Employed Population of Catering and Beverage Attendants : Female
L402094 Employed Population of Drink, Travel and Keep Fit Public Place of Entertainment Attendants
L402095 Employed Population of Drink, Travel and Keep Fit Public Place of Entertainment Attendants: Male
L402096 Employed Population of Drink, Travel and Keep Fit Public Place of Entertainment Attendants: Female
L402097 Employed Population of Transport Service Personnel
L402098 Employed Population of Transport Service Personnel: Male
L402099 Employed Population of Transport Service Personnel: Female
L402100 Employed Population of Assistant Service Personnel of Medical and Health Work
L402101 Employed Population of Assistant Service Personnel of Medical and Health Work : Male
L402102 Employed Population of Assistant Service Personnel of Medical and Health Work : Female
L402103 Employed Population of Community Service and Resident Life Service Personnel
L402104 Employed Population of Community Service and Resident Life Service Personnel: Male
L402105 Employed Population of Community Service and Resident Life Service Personnel: Female
L402106 Employed Population of Other Commerce ,Service Trade Personnel
L402107 Employed Population of Other Commerce ,Service Trade Personnel: Male
L402108 Employed Population of Other Commerce ,Service Trade Personnel: Female
L402109 Employed Population of Water Conservancy Personnel
L402110 Employed Population of Water Conservancy Personnel: Male
L402111 Employed Population of Water Conservancy Personnel: Female
L402112 Employed Population of Crop Cultivation Production Personnel
L402113 Employed Population of Crop Cultivation Production Personnel: Male
L402114 Employed Population of Crop Cultivation Production Personnel: Female
L402115 Employed Population of Forestry Production and Wild Animal and Plant Protection Personnel
L402116 Employed Population of Forestry Production and Wild Animal and Plant Protection Personnel: Male
L402117 Employed Population of Forestry Production and Wild Animal and Plant Protection Personnel: Female
L402118 Employed Population of Animal Husbandry Production Personnel
L402119 Employed Population of Animal Husbandry Production Personnel: Male
L402120 Employed Population of Animal Husbandry Production Personnel: Female
L402121 Employed Population of Fishery Production Personnel
L402122 Employed Population of Fishery Production Personnel: Male
L402123 Employed Population of Fishery Production Personnel: Female
L402124 Employed Population of Water Conservancy Facilities Management and Maintenance Personnel
L402125 Employed Population of Water Conservancy Facilities Management and Maintenance Personnel: Male
L402126 Employed Population of Water Conservancy Facilities Management and Maintenance Personnel: Female
L402127 Employed Population of Other Water Conservancy Production Personnel
L402128 Employed Population of Other Water Conservancy Production Personnel: Male
L402129 Employed Population of Other Water Conservancy Production Personnel: Female
L402130 Employed Population of Production, Transport Equipment Operators and Related Personnel
L402131 Employed Population of Production, Transport Equipment Operators and Related Personnel: Male
L402132 Employed Population of Production, Transport Equipment Operators and Related Personnel: Female
L402133 Employed Population of Survey and Mineral Exploitation Personnel
L402134 Employed Population of Survey and Mineral Exploitation Personnel : Male
L402135 Employed Population of Survey and Mineral Exploitation Personnel : Female
L402136 Employed Population of Metal Smelt, Rolling Personnel
L402137 Employed Population of Metal Smelt, Rolling Personnel: Male
L402138 Employed Population of Metal Smelt, Rolling Personnel: Female
L402139 Employed Population of Chemical Products Production Personnel
L402140 Employed Population of Chemical Products Production Personnel : Male
L402141 Employed Population of Chemical Products Production Personnel : Female
L402142 Employed Population of Machine-building are Processed to Personnel
L402143 Employed Population of Machine-building are Processed to Personnel : Male
L402144 Employed Population of Machine-building are Processed to Personnel : Female
L402145 Employed Population of Electronic Product Assembles Personnel
L402146 Employed Population of Electronic Product Assembles Personnel : Male
L402147 Employed Population of Electronic Product Assembles Personnel : Female
L402148 Employed Population of Plant Equipment Repairing Personnel
L402149 Employed Population of Plant Equipment Repairing Personnel : Male
L402150 Employed Population of Plant Equipment Repairing Personnel : Female
L402151 Employed Population of Rig Up of Electric Power, Running, Overhauling and Supply Power to Personnel
L402152 Employed Population of Rig Up of Electric Power, Running, Overhauling and Supply Power to Personnel : Male
L402153 Employed Population of Rig Up of Electric Power, Running, Overhauling and Supply Power to Personnel : Female
L402154 Employed Population of Electronic Devices and Components, Device Fabrication, Assembling, Debugging and Maintenance Personal
L402155 Employed Population of Electronic Devices and Components, Device Fabrication, Assembling, Debugging and Maintenance Personal: Male
L402156 Employed Population of Electronic Devices and Components, Device Fabrication, Assembling, Debugging and Maintenance Personal: Female
L402157 Employed Population of Rubber and Plastic Products Produce Personnel
L402158 Employed Population of Rubber and Plastic Products Produce Personnel : Male
L402159 Employed Population of Rubber and Plastic Products Produce Personnel : Female
L402160 Employed Population of Textile,Knitting,Prints and Dye Personnel
L402161 Employed Population of Textile,Knitting,Prints and Dye Personnel : Male
L402162 Employed Population of Textile,Knitting,Prints and Dye Personnel : Female
L402163 Employed Population of Cut Out, Sew and the Leather and Fur Products are Processed to Personnel
L402164 Employed Population of Cut Out, Sew and the Leather and Fur Products are Processed to Personnel : Male
L402165 Employed Population of Cut Out, Sew and the Leather and Fur Products are Processed to Personnel : Female
L402166 Employed Population of Grain and Oil,Food,Beverage and Fodder is Produced and Processed to Personnel
L402167 Employed Population of Grain and Oil,Food,Beverage and Fodder is Produced and Processed to Personnel: Male
L402168 Employed Population of Grain and Oil,Food,Beverage and Fodder is Produced and Processed to Personnel: Female
L402169 Employed Population of Tobacco and Goods are Processed to Personnel
L402170 Employed Population of Tobacco and Goods are Processed to Personnel : Male
L402171 Employed Population of Tobacco and Goods are Processed to Personnel : Female
L402172 Employed Population of Medicines Production Personnel
L402173 Employed Population of Medicines Production Personnel : Male
L402174 Employed Population of Medicines Production Personnel : Female
L402175 Employed Population of Production and Processing Personnel of Timber and Artificial Board and etc.
L402176 Employed Population of Production and Processing Personnel of Timber and Artificial Board and etc.: Male
L402177 Employed Population of Production and Processing Personnel of Timber and Artificial Board and etc.: Female
L402178 Employed Population of Production and Processing Personnel of Construction Material
L402179 Employed Population of Production and Processing Personnel of Construction Material: Male
L402180 Employed Population of Production and Processing Personnel of Construction Material: Female
L402181 Employed Population of Personnel of Glass, Pottery,Emanel &amp; their Products Production &amp; Processing
L402182 Employed Population of Personnel of Glass, Pottery,Emanel &amp; their Products Production &amp; Processing: Male
L402183 Employed Population of Personnel of Glass, Pottery,Emanel &amp; their Products Production &amp; Processing: Female
L402184 Employed Population of Broadcast Movie &amp; TV Products Making,Broadcasting &amp; Historical Relics Protection Personnel
L402185 Employed Population of Broadcast Movie &amp; TV Products Making,Broadcasting &amp; Historical Relics Protection Personnel: Male
L402186 Employed Population of Broadcast Movie &amp; TV Products Making,Broadcasting &amp; Historical Relics Protection Personnel: Female
L402187 Employed Population of Printing Personnel
L402188 Employed Population of Printing Personnel: Male
L402189 Employed Population of Printing Personnel: Female
L402190 Employed Population of Arts &amp; Crafts Making Personnel
L402191 Employed Population of Arts &amp; Crafts Making Personnel: Male
L402192 Employed Population of Arts &amp; Crafts Making Personnel: Female
L402193 Employed Population of Culture and Education,Sports Goods Making Personnel
L402194 Employed Population of Culture and Education, Sports Goods Making Personnel: Male
L402195 Employed Population of Culture and Education, Sports Goods Making Personnel: Female
L402196 Employed Population of Project Constructors
L402197 Employed Population of Project Constructors: Male
L402198 Employed Population of Project Constructors: Female
L402199 Employed Population of Transporting Equipment Attendant &amp; Relevant Personnel
L402200 Employed Population of Transporting Equipment Attendant &amp; Relevant Personnel: Male
L402201 Employed Population of Transporting Equipment Attendant &amp; Relevant Personnel: Female
L402202 Employed Population of Personnel engaged in Environmental Monitoring and Wastes Processing
L402203 Employed Population of Personnel engaged in Environmental Monitoring and Wastes Processing: Male
L402204 Employed Population of Personnel engaged in Environmental Monitoring and Wastes Processing: Female
L402205 Employed Population of Inspection, Measurement Personnel
L402206 Employed Population of Inspection, Measurement Personnel : Male
L402207 Employed Population of Inspection, Measurement Personnel : Female
L402208 Employed Population of Other Production, Transport Equipment Operators &amp; Related Workers
L402209 Employed Population of Other Production, Transport Equipment Operators &amp; Related Workers: Male
L402210 Employed Population of Other Production, Transport Equipment Operators &amp; Related Workers: Female
L402211 Employed Population of Not Stated
L402212 Employed Population of Not Stated: Male
L402213 Employed Population of Not Stated: Female

L407001 Unemployed Population: Total
L407002 Unemployed Population: Male
L407003 Unemployed Population: Female
L407004 Unemployed Population of Students: Sub-total
L407005 Unemployed Population of Students: Male
L407006 Unemployed Population of Students: Female
L407007 Unemployed Population of Manage Household Affairs: Sub-total
L407008 Unemployed Population of Manage Household Affairs: Male
L407009 Unemployed Population of Manage Household Affairs: Female
L407010 Unemployed Population of Retired: Sub-total
L407011 Unemployed Population of Retired: Male
L407012 Unemployed Population of Retired: Female
L407013 Unemployed Population of Losing the Ability to Work: Sub-total
L407014 Unemployed Population of Losing the Ability to Work: Male
L407015 Unemployed Population of Losing the Ability to Work: Female
L407016 Unemployed Population of Having Never Worked and Looking for a Job: Sub-total
L407017 Unemployed Population of Having Never Worked and Looking for a Job: Male
L407018 Unemployed Population of Having Never Worked and Looking for a Job: Female
L407019 Unemployed Population of Losing the Job and Looking for A Job: Sub-total
L407020 Unemployed Population of Losing the Job and Looking for A Job: Male
L407021 Unemployed Population of Losing the Job and Looking for A Job: Female
L407022 Unemployed Population of Others: Sub-total
L407023 Unemployed Population of Others: Male
L407024 Unemployed Population of Others: Female</eaover>
					</overview>
				</eainfo>
				<distinfo>
					<distrib>
						<cntinfo>
							<cntorgp>
								<cntorg>University of Michigan. China Data Center</cntorg>
							</cntorgp>
							<cntaddr>
								<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
								<address>1007 E Huron St</address>
								<city>Ann Arbor</city>
								<state>MI</state>
								<postal>48104</postal>
							</cntaddr>
							<cntvoice>(734) 647-9610</cntvoice>
							<cntfax>(734) 763-0335</cntfax>
							<cntemail>chinadata@umich.edu</cntemail>
						</cntinfo>
					</distrib>
					<resdesc>cdc_2000_tibet_province2000l1</resdesc>
					<stdorder>
						<digform>
							<digtinfo>
								<formname>GeoPackage</formname>
								<formspec>zip</formspec>

								<transize>0.059 MB</transize>
							</digtinfo>
						</digform>
					</stdorder>
				</distinfo>
				<metainfo>
					<metd>20090527</metd>
					<metc>
						<cntinfo>
							<cntorgp>
								<cntorg>Research Data Services (RDS), Columbia University Libraries</cntorg>
								<cntper>GIS/Metadata Librarian</cntper>
							</cntorgp>
							<cntaddr>
								<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
								<address>420 W. 118th St., 215 IAB, MC 3301</address>
								<city>New York</city>
								<state>NY</state>
								<postal>10027</postal>
								<country>USA</country>
							</cntaddr>
							<cntvoice>(212)854-6012</cntvoice>
							<cntemail>data@library.columbia.edu</cntemail>
						</cntinfo>
					</metc>
					<metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
					<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
					<mettc>local time</mettc>
				</metainfo>
			</metadata>
