﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?><metadata>
<idinfo>
<citation>
<citeinfo>
<origin>University of Michigan. China Data Center</origin>
<pubdate>2005</pubdate>
<title>Tibet Province With 2000 Population Census Data From 100% Short Form Data</title>
<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
<serinfo>
<sername>2000 Tibet Township Population Census Data with GIS Maps</sername>
</serinfo>
<pubinfo>
<pubplace>Beijing</pubplace>
<publish>Beijing Hua tong ren shi chang xin xi you xian ze ren gong si</publish>
</pubinfo>
<onlink>https://www1.columbia.edu/sec/acis/eds/dgate/studies/C1301/data/cdc_2000_tibet_province2000a.zip
</onlink>
</citeinfo>
</citation>
<descript>
<abstract>Tibet Province With 2000 Population Census Data From 100% Short Form Data is a polygon theme representing Tibet Province, China in 2000.  Attribute information includes census data from 100% Short Form data from the 2000 China census.

This data layer is part of the Tibet 2000 Township Census data set produced by the All China Marketing Research Co. and distributed by the University of Michigan, China Data Center.</abstract>
<purpose>The data set was developed for display and analysis using GIS.</purpose>
<supplinf>Notes on China 2000 Population Census Data:
In order to guide you to use the data correctly, provide you some explanations as follows:
(l) Census time: 0:00AM of November 1, 2000 as the reference time for the census.
(2) The 2000 population census covered all persons who hold the nationality of, and have permanent residing place in the People's Republic of China. During the census, each person was enumerated in his/her permanent residing place.
The following persons should be enumerated in their permanent residing place: a) Those who reside in the townships, towns and street communities and have their permanent household registration there. b) Those who have resided in the townships, towns and street communities for more than 6 months but the places of their permanent household registration are elsewhere. c) Those who have resided in the townships, towns and street communities for less than 6 months but have been away from the place of their permanent household registration for more than 6 months. d) Those who live in the townships, towns and street communities during the population census while the places of their household registration have not yet settled. e) Those who used to live in the townships, towns and street communities but are working or studying abroad during the census and have no Permanent household registration for the time being.
(3) Two types of questionnaires (long form and short form) were used for the 2000 population census. The short form contains items that reflect the basic situation of the population, while the long form include all short form items plus other items such as migration, education, economic activities, marriage and family, fertility , housing , etc. . According to the Statute for the Fifth National Population Census and the Procedures for the Selection of Samples for the Long Forms, households selected by a random sampling program completed the long forms, and the rest of the households completed the short forms.
(4) The data table consists of three parts. The first part (variables A1-A97 and A154-A156) contains data aggregated from all households data (i. e. common items in both long and short forms) that reflects the basic situation of population. The second part (variables A98-A153 and A157-A169) contains data aggregated from the long forms from the 9.5% sample data, which present various detailed compositions of the population. The third part (variables B1-31) contains socioeconomic variables reported by the National Bureau of Statistics in annual statistics. Please note that there might be some difference between the county population aggregated from the 2000 population Census data and the one reported by government, which is derived from household registration and sample survey data.
(5) Results in this publication are based on the processing of data directly from enumeration without any adjustment. It is therefore worthwhile to notice the following:
    a. Data in the publication do not include population not enumerated in the census.
    b. Data in the publication do not include the 2.5 million servicemen of the People's Liberation Army.
    c. Total population as shown in this publication is 1,242.61 million, or 23.22 million less than the population figure of 1,265.83 million (including 2.5 million servicemen) released earlier by the National Bureau of Statistics ,which was based on the advance tabulation.
    d. The post-enumeration sample survey indicates an undercount of 1.81% in the census enumeration.
    e. The sampling ratio for the long forms = total population in the long forms/total population calculated by computer processing = 9.50%.
    f. The sampling ratio for various compositions of the population may not be the same as household is used as the ultimate sampling unit.
Users should pay attention to the above-mentioned factors when using information in the publication, and in particular, is estimating the population from the sample results.
(5) Regulation on the Classification of Urban/Rural Residence for Statistical Purpose (Provisional) prepared by the National Bureau of Statistics is used in urban/rural classification of the population in this census.</supplinf>
</descript>
<timeperd>
<timeinfo>
<sngdate>
<caldate>2000</caldate>
</sngdate>
</timeinfo>
<current>ground condition</current>
</timeperd>
<status>
<progress>Complete</progress>
<update>Unknown</update>
</status>
<spdom>
<bounding>
<westbc>
78.956635</westbc>
<eastbc>
98.984121</eastbc>
<northbc>
34.079955</northbc>
<southbc>
27.403888</southbc>
</bounding>
</spdom>
<keywords>
<theme>
<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
<themekey>society</themekey>
<themekey>boundaries</themekey>
</theme>
<theme>
<themekt>Library of Congress Subject Headings</themekt>
<themekey>Cities and towns --China --Population --Statistics --Databases.</themekey>
<themekey>Cities and towns --China --Population --Statistics --Maps.</themekey>
<themekey>Cities and towns --Census, 2000 --China --Databases.</themekey>
<themekey>Cities and towns --Census, 2000 --China --Maps.</themekey>
<themekey>China --Population --Statistics --Databases.</themekey>
<themekey>China --Population --Statistics --Maps.</themekey>
<themekey>China --Census, 2000 --Databases.</themekey>
<themekey>China --Census, 2000 --Maps.</themekey>
</theme>
<theme>
<themekt>None</themekt>
<themekey>Census</themekey>
<themekey>Population statistics</themekey>
<themekey>Demographics</themekey>
<themekey>Housing Statistics</themekey>
<themekey>Sex Statistics</themekey>
<themekey>Agriculture Statistics</themekey>
<themekey>Counties</themekey>
<themekey>Administrative and political divisions</themekey>
</theme>
<place>
	<placekt>GeoNames</placekt>
	<placekey>Tibet (1279685)</placekey>
</place>
<place>
<placekt>Library of Congress Subject Headings</placekt>
<placekey>China</placekey>
<placekey>Xizang (China)</placekey>
<placekey>Xikang Sheng (China)</placekey>
<placekey>Tibet (China)</placekey>
</place>
<temporal>
<tempkt>None</tempkt>
<tempkey>2000</tempkey>
</temporal>
</keywords>
<accconst>For current Columbia affiliates only.</accconst>
<useconst>For educational, non-commercial use only.</useconst>
<ptcontac>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>China Data Center - University of Michigan</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
<address>1007 E Huron St</address>
<city>Ann Arbor</city>
<state>MI</state>
<postal>48104</postal>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>(734) 647-9610</cntvoice>
<cntfax>(734) 763-0335</cntfax>
<cntemail>chinadata@umich.edu</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</ptcontac>





<native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.1850</native>
</idinfo>
<dataqual>
<posacc>
<horizpa>
<horizpar>The 2000 China township maps are developed for matching 2000 China population Census data, which should only be used as references for research or education instead of used as official maps. The distributor is not responsible for the accuracy of the those maps if the maps are used for business or other purposes.</horizpar>
</horizpa>
</posacc>
<lineage>
<procstep>
<procdesc>The 2000 China township GIS maps were developed for the 5th population Census data, which covered all 31 municipalities, provinces and autonomous regions of China, except for Taiwan, Hong Kong and Macao, with more than 50,000 townships (Xiang, Zhen and Jiedao). The 2000 China township maps provide geographical reference for the 5th population census data in spatial data analysis. It will help users to understand the spatial distribution of population and regional difference in China.

The population data came from the 5th China Population Census surveyed in 2000. The GIS data is based on the national digital map (1:1 million) developed by the National Geographic Information Center of China (NGCC), including rives, roads, residential area and administrative boundaries. Other sources "The China Atlas of Standard Place Names", the newly published provincial atlas, the digital city atlas, the street atlas of major cities, the zip code atlas, and the directory of all enterprises and administrative units of China.

The primary work for the 2000 China township maps is to find the geographic location of each township on the 1:1 million digital map of China. The procedures include:

1) Verifying the location of townships on the administrative maps based on 2000 population Census tables, and making the correction to those township names which don't match those names in the Census tables.

2) For those townships of cities at prefecture level and above, we found the location of those townships on the city maps based on their addresses in the directory of all China basic units and zip code.

3) For some virtual townships, which don't have central locations, we try to find the mostly related locations on the map.

4) The administrative boundaries of urban districts of prefecture cities are based on the geographic locations of their townships and related boundary maps.

5) The geographic reference degree data is extracted from the maps with the locations of the townships, compatible with 2000 population Census data.

6) The digital township map (1: 1 million) is converted from the geographic degree data.</procdesc>
<proccont>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>China Data Center - University of Michigan</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
<address>1007 E Huron St</address>
<city>Ann Arbor</city>
<state>MI</state>
<postal>48104</postal>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>(734) 647-9610</cntvoice>
<cntfax>(734) 763-0335</cntfax>
<cntemail>chinadata@umich.edu</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</proccont>
</procstep>
</lineage>
</dataqual>
<spdoinfo>
<direct>Vector</direct>
<ptvctinf>
<sdtsterm>
<sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>
<ptvctcnt>1</ptvctcnt>
</sdtsterm>
</ptvctinf>
</spdoinfo>
<spref>
  <horizsys>
    <geodetic>
      <horizdn>D_WGS_1984</horizdn>
      <ellips>WGS_1984</ellips>
      <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
      <denflat>298.257224</denflat>
    </geodetic>
  </horizsys>
</spref>



<latres>0.000000</latres>
<longres>0.000000</longres>










<eainfo>
<overview>
<eaover>Tibet 2000 Provincial Population Census Data with Maps
Variable Description
Area The area size
GB  Two digit GB code of province
Gbcode Five digit GB code of province
Cname Name of province in Chinese Pingying
Ename Name of province in English

A101001 Total Number of Households
A101002 Total Number of Family Households
A101003 Total Number of Collective Households
A101004 Total Population
A101005 Total Males
A101006 Total Females
A101007 Sex Ratio
A101008 Total Population of Family Households
A101009 Total Males of Family Households
A101010 Total Females of Family Households
A101011 Sex Ratio of Population from Family Households
A101012 Total Population of Collective Households
A101013 Total Males of Collective Households
A101014 Total Females of Collective Households
A101015 Sex Ratio of Population from Collective Households
A101016 Average Size of Family Households

A102001 Total Population
A102002 Total Males
A102003 Total Females
A102004 Total Population Who Reside in the Township, Towns and Street Communities and Have Their Permanent household Registration There.
A102005 Total Males Who Reside in the Township, Towns and Street Communities and Have Their Permanent household Registration There.
A102006 Total Females Who Reside in the Township, Towns and Street Communities and Have Their Permanent household Registration There.
A102007 Total Population Who Have Resided in the Township, Towns and Street Communities for More Than 6 Months But the places of Their Permanent household Registration Are Elsewhere.
A102008 Total Males Who Have Resided in the Township, Towns and Street Communities for More Than 6 Months But the places of Their Permanent household Registration Are Elsewhere.
A102009 Total Females Who Have Resided in the Township, Towns and Street Communities for More Than 6 Months But the places of Their Permanent household Registration Are Elsewhere.
A102010 Total Population Who Have Resided in the Township, Towns and Street Communities for Less Than 6 Months But Have Been Away From the places of Their Permanent household Registration for More Than 6 Months.
A102011 Total Males Who Have Resided in the Township, Towns and Street Communities for Less Than 6 Months But Have Been Away From the places of Their Permanent household Registration for More Than 6 Months.
A102012 Total Females Who Have Resided in the Township, Towns and Street Communities for Less Than 6 Months But Have Been Away From the places of Their Permanent household Registration for More Than 6 Months.
A102013 Total Population Who Live in the Township, Towns and Street Communities During the Population Census While the places of Their household Registration Have Not Yet Settled.
A102014 Total Males Who Live in the Township, Towns and Street Communities During the Population Census While the places of Their household Registration Have Not Yet Settled.
A102015 Total Females Who Live in the Township, Towns and Street Communities During the Population Census While the places of Their household Registration Have Not Yet Settled.
A102016 Total Population Who Used to Live in the Township, Towns and Street Communities but are Working or Studying Abroad During the Census and Have no Permanent for the Time Being.
A102017 Total Males Who Used to Live in the Township, Towns and Street Communities but are Working or Studying Abroad During the Census and Have no Permanent for the Time Being.
A102018 Total Females Who Used to Live in the Township, Towns and Street Communities but are Working or Studying Abroad During the Census and Have no Permanent for the Time Being.

A103001 Total Population with Household Registration (Have not included the whole family and individuals going out )
A103002 Total Males with Household Registration (Have not included the whole family and individuals going out)
A103003 Total Females with Household Registration (Have not included the whole family and individuals going out)
A103004 Total Number of Permanent Local Residents
A103005 Total Males of Permanent Local Residents
A103006 Total Females of Permanent Local Residents
A103007 Total Number of Population Definitely Registered as Permanent Residents
A103008 Total Males of Population Definitely Registered as Permanent Residents
A103009 Total Females of Population Definitely Registered as Permanent Residents
A103010 Total Population Working or Studying Abroad
A103011 Total Males Working or Studying Abroad
A103012 Total Females Working or Studying Abroad
A103013 Total Population Going out within Half a Year from Household Registration Places
A103014 Total Males Going out within Half a Year from Household Registration Places
A103015 Total Females Going out within Half a Year from Household Registration Places
A103016 Total Population Whose Whole Families Go out
A103017 Total Males Whose Whole Families Go out
A103018 Total Females Whose Whole Families Go out

A104001 Total Population Moved in from Other Household Registration Places
A104002 Total Males Moved in from Other Household Registration Places
A104003 Total Females Moved in from Other Household Registration Places
A104004 Total Population Moved in from the Same County (City)
A104005 Total Males Moved in from the Same County (City)
A104006 Total Females Moved in from the Same County (City)
A104007 Total Population Moved in from Other Districts of the Same City
A104008 Total Males Moved in from Other Districts of the Same City
A104009 Total Females Moved in from Other Districts of the Same City
A104010 Total Population Moved in from Other Counties or Cities of Same Province
A104011 Total Males Moved in from Other Counties or Cities of Same Province
A104012 Total Females Moved in from Other Counties or Cities of Same Province
A104013 Total Population Moved in from Other Provinces
A104014 Total Males Moved in from Other Provinces
A104015 Total Females Moved in from Other Provinces

A105001 Total Population
A105002 Total Males
A105003 Total Females
A105004 Total Agricultural Population
A105005 Total Males of Agricultural Population
A105006 Total Females of Agricultural Population
A105007 Total Non-agricultural Population
A105008 Total Males of Non-agricultural Population
A105009 Total Females of Non-agricultural Population
A105010 % of Non-agricultural Population to Total
A105011 % of Males of Non-agricultural Population to Total Males
A105012 % of Females of Non-agricultural Population to Total Females

A106001 Total Population
A106002 Total Males
A106003 Total Females
A106004 Total Population of Han People
A106005 Total Males of Han People
A106006 Total Females of Han People
A106007 Total Population of Mongolian People
A106008 Total Males of Mongolian People
A106009 Total Females of Mongolian People
A106010 Total Population of Hui People
A106011 Total Males of Hui People
A106012 Total Females of Hui People
A106013 Total Population of Tibetan People
A106014 Total Males of Tibetan People
A106015 Total Females of Tibetan People
A106016 Total Population of Uygur People
A106019 Total Males of Uygur People
A106020 Total Females of Uygur People
A106021 Total Population of Miao People
A106022 Total Males of Miao People
A106023 Total Females of Miao People
A106024 Total Population of Yi People
A106025 Total Males of Yi People
A106026 Total Females of Yi People
A106027 Total Population of Zhuang People
A106028 Total Males of Zhuang People
A106029 Total Females of Zhuang People
A106030 Total Population of Bouyei People
A106031 Total Males of Bouyei People
A106032 Total Females of Bouyei People
A106033 Total Population of Korean People
A106034 Total Males of Korean People
A106035 Total Females of Korean People
A106036 Total Population of Manchu
A106037 Total Males of Manchu
A106038 Total Females of Manchu
A106039 Total Population of Dong People
A106040 Total Males of Dong People
A106041 Total Females of Dong People
A106042 Total Population of Yao People
A106043 Total Males of Yao People
A106044 Total Females of Yao People
A106045 Total Population of Bai People
A106046 Total Males of Bai People
A106047 Total Females of Bai People
A106048 Total Population of Tujia People
A106049 Total Males of Tujia People
A106050 Total Females of Tujia People
A106051 Total Population of Hani People
A106052 Total Males of Hani People
A106053 Total Females of Hani People
A106054 Total Population of Kazak People
A106055 Total Males of Kazak People
A106056 Total Females of Kazak People
A106057 Total Population of Dai People
A106058 Total Males of Dai People
A106059 Total Females of Dai People
A106060 Total Population of Li People
A106061 Total Males of Li People
A106062 Total Females of Li People
A106063 Total Population of Lisu People
A106064 Total Males of Lisu People
A106065 Total Females of Lisu People
A106066 Total Population of Va People
A106067 Total Males of Va People
A106068 Total Females of Va People
A106069 Total Population of She People
A106070 Total Males of She People
A106071 Total Females of She People
A106072 Total Population of Gaoshan People
A106073 Total Males of Gaoshan People
A106074 Total Females of Gaoshan People
A106075 Total Population of Lahu People
A106076 Total Males of Lahu People
A106077 Total Females of Lahu People
A106078 Total Population of Shui People
A106079 Total Males of Shui People
A106080 Total Females of Shui People
A106081 Total Population of Dongxiang People
A106082 Total Males of Dongxiang People
A106083 Total Females of Dongxiang People
A106084 Total Population of Naxi People
A106085 Total Males of Naxi People
A106086 Total Females of Naxi People
A106087 Total Population of Jingpo People
A106088 Total Males of Jingpo People
A106089 Total Females of Jingpo People
A106090 Total Population of Kirgiz People
A106091 Total Males of Kirgiz People
A106092 Total Females of Kirgiz People
A106093 Total Population of Tu People
A106094 Total Males of Tu People
A106095 Total Females of Tu People
A106096 Total Population of Daur People
A106097 Total Males of Daur People
A106098 Total Females of Daur People
A106099 Total Population of Mulam People
A106100 Total Males of Mulam People
A106101 Total Females of Mulam People
A106102 Total Population of Qiang People
A106103 Total Males of Qiang People
A106104 Total Females of Qiang People
A106105 Total Population of Blang People
A106106 Total Males of Blang People
A106107 Total Females of Blang People
A106108 Total Population of Salar People
A106109 Total Males of Salar People
A106110 Total Females of Salar People
A106111 Total Population of Maonan People
A106112 Total Males of Maonan People
A106113 Total Females of Maonan People
A106114 Total Population of Gelao People
A106115 Total Males of Gelao People
A106116 Total Females of Gelao People
A106117 Total Population of Xibe People
A106118 Total Males of Xibe People
A106119 Total Females of Xibe People
A106120 Total Population of Achang People
A106121 Total Males of Achang People
A106122 Total Females of Achang People
A106123 Total Population of Pumi People
A106124 Total Males of Pumi People
A106125 Total Females of Pumi People
A106126 Total Population of Tajik
A106127 Total Males of Tajik
A106128 Total Females of Tajik
A106129 Total Population of Nu People
A106130 Total Males of Nu People
A106131 Total Females of Nu People
A106132 Total Population of Ozbek People
A106133 Total Males of Ozbek People
A106134 Total Females of Ozbek People
A106135 Total Population of Russian People
A106136 Total Males of Russian People
A106137 Total Females of Russian People
A106138 Total Population of Ewenki People
A106139 Total Males of Ewenki People
A106140 Total Females of Ewenki People
A106141 Total Population of De'ang People
A106142 Total Males of De'ang People
A106143 Total Females of De'ang People
A106144 Total Population of Bonan People
A106145 Total Males of Bonan People
A106146 Total Females of Bonan People
A106147 Total Population of Yugur People
A106148 Total Males of Yugur People
A106149 Total Females of Yugur People
A106150 Total Population of Jing People
A106151 Total Males of Jing People
A106152 Total Females of Jing People
A106153 Total Population of Tatar
A106154 Total Males of Tatar
A106155 Total Females of Tatar
A106156 Total Population of Drung People
A106157 Total Males of Drung People
A106158 Total Females of Drung People
A106159 Total Population of Oroqen People
A106160 Total Males of Oroqen People
A106161 Total Females of Oroqen People
A106162 Total Population of Hezhen People
A106163 Total Males of Hezhen People
A106164 Total Females of Hezhen People
A106165 Total Population of Moinba People
A106166 Total Males of Moinba People
A106167 Total Females of Moinba People
A106168 Total Population of Lhoba People
A106169 Total Males of Lhoba People
A106170 Total Females of Lhoba People
A106171 Total Population of Jino People
A106172 Total Males of Jino People
A106173 Total Females of Jino People
A106174 Total Population of Unidentified Peoples
A106175 Total Males of Unidentified Peoples
A106176 Total Females of Unidentified Peoples
A106177 Total Population of Chinese Foreigners
A106178 Total Males of Chinese Foreigners
A106179 Total Females of Chinese Foreigners

A107001 Total Population
A107002 Total Males
A107003 Total Females
A107004 Total Population at 0 Age
A107005 Total Males at 0 Age
A107006 Total Females at 0 Age
A107007 Total Population at 1-4 Age
A107008 Total Males at 1-4 Age
A107009 Total Females at 1-4 Age
A107010 Total Population at 5-9 Age
A107011 Total Males at 5-9 Age
A107012 Total Females at 5-9 Age
A107013 Total Population at 10-14 Age
A107014 Total Males at 10-14 Age
A107015 Total Females at 10-14 Age
A107016 Total Population at 15-19 Age
A107019 Total Males at 15-19 Age
A107020 Total Females at 15-19 Age
A107021 Total Population at 20-24 Age
A107022 Total Males at 20-24 Age
A107023 Total Females at 20-24 Age
A107024 Total Population at 25-29 Age
A107025 Total Males at 25-29 Age
A107026 Total Females at 25-29 Age
A107027 Total Population at 30-34 Age
A107028 Total Males at 30-34 Age
A107029 Total Females at 30-34 Age
A107030 Total Population at 35-39 Age
A107031 Total Males at 35-39 Age
A107032 Total Females at 35-39 Age
A107033 Total Population at 40-44 Age
A107034 Total Males at 40-44 Age
A107035 Total Females at 40-44 Age
A107036 Total Population at 45-49 Age
A107037 Total Males at 45-49 Age
A107038 Total Females at 45-49 Age
A107039 Total Population at 50-54 Age
A107040 Total Males at 50-54 Age
A107041 Total Females at 50-54 Age
A107042 Total Population at 55-59 Age
A107043 Total Males at 55-59 Age
A107044 Total Females at 55-59 Age
A107045 Total Population at 60-64 Age
A107046 Total Males at 60-64 Age
A107047 Total Females at 60-64 Age
A107048 Total Population at 65-69 Age
A107049 Total Males at 65-69 Age
A107050 Total Females at 65-69 Age
A107051 Total Population at 70-74 Age
A107052 Total Males at 70-74 Age
A107053 Total Females at 70-74 Age
A107054 Total Population at 75-79 Age
A107055 Total Males at 75-79 Age
A107056 Total Females at 75-79 Age
A107057 Total Population at 80-84 Age
A107058 Total Males at 80-84 Age
A107059 Total Females at 80-84 Age
A107060 Total Population at 85-89 Age
A107061 Total Males at 85-89 Age
A107062 Total Females at 85-89 Age
A107063 Total Population at 90-94 Age
A107064 Total Males at 90-94 Age
A107065 Total Females at 90-94 Age
A107066 Total Population at 95-99 Age
A107067 Total Males at 95-99 Age
A107068 Total Females at 95-99 Age
A107069 Total Population at 100 Age and Over
A107070 Total Males at 100 Age and Over
A107071 Total Females at 100 Age and Over

A108001 Total Population aged 6+
A108002 Total Male aged 6+
A108003 Total Female aged 6+
A108004 Population No Schooling
A108005 Male No Schooling
A108006 Female No Schooling
A108007 Population Eliminate Illiteracy
A108008 Male Eliminate Illiteracy
A108009 Female Eliminate Illiteracy
A108010 Population Primary School
A108011 Male Primary School
A108012 Female Primary School
A108013 Population Junior Middle School
A108014 Male Junior Middle School
A108015 Female Junior Middle School
A108016 Population Senior Middle School
A108019 Male Senior Middle School
A108020 Female Senior Middle School
A108021 Population Specialized Secondary School
A108022 Male Specialized Secondary School
A108023 Female Specialized Secondary School
A108024 Population Junior College
A108025 Male Junior College
A108026 Female Junior College
A108027 Population University
A108028 Male University
A108029 Female University
A108030 Population Graduate Student
A108031 Male Graduate Student
A108032 Female Graduate Student

A109001 Total Population 15+
A109002 Total Male 15+
A109003 Total Female 15+
A109004 Population Illiterate
A109005 Male Illiterate
A109006 Female Illiterate
A109007 Percentage of Illiterate to Total Population aged 15+(%)
A109008 Percentage of Male Illiterate to Total Population aged 15+(%)
A109009 Percentage of Female Illiterate to Total Population aged 15+(%)

A110001 Total Number of Households
A110002 Households with One Person
A110003 Households with Two Persons
A110004 Households with Three Persons
A110005 Households with Four Persons
A110006 Households with Five Persons
A110007 Households with Six Persons
A110008 Households with Seven Persons
A110009 Households with Eight Persons
A110010 Households with Nine Persons
A110011 Households with Ten Persons &amp; Over

A111001 Total Number of Households
A111002 Households with One Generation
A111003 Households with Two Generations
A111004 Households with Three Generations
A111005 Households with Four Generations
A111006 Households with Five &amp; Over Generations

A112001 All births
A112002 Male births
A112003 Female births
A112004 All births November of 1999
A112005 Male births November of 1999
A112006 Female births November of 1999
A112007 All births December of 1999
A112008 Male births December of 1999
A112009 Female births December of 1999
A112010 All births January of 2000
A112011 Male births January of 2000
A112012 Female births January of 2000
A112013 All births February of 2000
A112014 Male births February of 2000
A112015 Female births February of 2000
A112016 All births March of 2000
A112019 Male births March of 2000
A112020 Female births March of 2000
A112021 All births April of 2000
A112022 Male births April of 2000
A112023 Female births April of 2000
A112024 All births May of 2000
A112025 Male births May of 2000
A112026 Female births May of 2000
A112027 All births June of 2000
A112028 Male births June of 2000
A112029 Female births June of 2000
A112030 All births July of 2000
A112031 Male births July of 2000
A112032 Female births July of 2000
A112033 All births August of 2000
A112034 Male births August of 2000
A112035 Female births August of 2000
A112036 All births September of 2000
A112037 Male births September of 2000
A112038 Female births September of 2000
A112039 All births October of 2000
A112040 Male births October of 2000
A112041 Female births October of 2000

A113001 All deaths
A113002 Male deaths
A113003 Female deaths
A113004 All deaths November of 1999
A113005 Male deaths November of 1999
A113006 Female deaths November of 1999
A113007 All deaths December of 1999
A113008 Male deaths December of 1999
A113009 Female deaths December of 1999
A113010 All deaths January of 2000
A113011 Male deaths January of 2000
A113012 Female deaths January of 2000
A113013 All deaths February of 2000
A113014 Male deaths February of 2000
A113015 Female deaths February of 2000
A113016 All deaths March of 2000
A113019 Male deaths March of 2000
A113020 Female deaths March of 2000
A113021 All deaths April of 2000
A113022 Male deaths April of 2000
A113023 Female deaths April of 2000
A113024 All deaths May of 2000
A113025 Male deaths May of 2000
A113026 Female deaths May of 2000
A113027 All deaths June of 2000
A113028 Male deaths June of 2000
A113029 Female deaths June of 2000
A113030 All deaths July of 2000
A113031 Male deaths July of 2000
A113032 Female deaths July of 2000
A113033 All deaths August of 2000
A113034 Male deaths August of 2000
A113035 Female deaths August of 2000
A113036 All deaths September of 2000
A113037 Male deaths September of 2000
A113038 Female deaths September of 2000
A113039 All deaths October of 2000
A113040 Male deaths October of 2000
A113041 Female deaths October of 2000

A114001 Number of Family Households (Households)
A114002 Persons of Family Households (Person)
A114003 Average Rooms of Household (room/household)
A114004 Average Floor Space of Building (sq.m/person)

A302001 Total Population
A302002 Population 0-14
A302003 Population 15-64
A302004 Population 65+
A302005 Total Population to Total Population (%)
A302006 Population 0-14 to Total Population (%)
A302007 Population 15-64 to Total Population (%)
A302008 Population 65+ to Total Population (%)
A302009 Total Dependency Ratio
A302010 Dependency Ratio of Children
A302011 Dependency Ratio of The Aged

A502001 Family households with only one member
A502002 Male households with only one member
A502003 Female households with only one member
A502004 Family households with only one member 14 and under
A502005 Male households with only one member 14 and under
A502006 Female households with only one member 14 and under
A502007 Family households with only one member 15-19
A502008 Male households with only one member 15-19
A502009 Female households with only one member 15-19
A502010 Family households with only one member 20-24
A502011 Male households with only one member 20-24
A502012 Female households with only one member 20-24
A502013 Family households with only one member 25-29
A502014 Male households with only one member 25-29
A502015 Female households with only one member 25-29
A502016 Family households with only one member 30-34
A502017 Male households with only one member 30-34
A502018 Female households with only one member 30-34
A502019 Family households with only one member 35-39
A502020 Male households with only one member 35-39
A502021 Female households with only one member 35-39
A502022 Family households with only one member 40-44
A502023 Male households with only one member 40-44
A502024 Female households with only one member 40-44
A502025 Family households with only one member 45-49
A502026 Male households with only one member 45-49
A502027 Female households with only one member 45-49
A502028 Family households with only one member 50-54
A502029 Male households with only one member 50-54
A502030 Female households with only one member 50-54
A502031 Family households with only one member 55-59
A502032 Male households with only one member 55-59
A502033 Female households with only one member 55-59
A502034 Family households with only one member 60-64
A502035 Male households with only one member 60-64
A502036 Female households with only one member 60-64
A502037 Family households with only one member 65+
A502038 Male households with only one member 65+
A502039 Female households with only one member 65+

A503001 Number of Family households
A503002 Number of Family households with One Nationality
A503003 Percentage of Household with One Nationality to Total Households
A503004 Number of Family households with Two Nationalities
A503005 Percentage of Household with Two Nationalities to Total Households
A503006 Number of Family households with Three Nationalities
A503007 Percentage of Household with Three Nationalities to Total Households
A503008 Number of Family households with Four and Over Nationalities
A503009 Percentage of Household with Four and Over Nationalities to Total Households

A504001 Family households with persons aged 0-19
A504002 Family households with persons of 0-4
A504003 Family households with persons of 5-9
A504004 Family households with persons of 10-14
A504005 Family households with persons of 15-19

A505001 Family households with persons aged 60 and over
A505002 Family with one person of 60 and over
A505003 Family (with one person of 60 and over) of one old person only
A505004 Family (with one person of 60 and over) with one old person and other persons under age of adult
A505005 Family with one person of 60 and over (other)
A505006 Family with two persons of 60 and over
A505007 Family (with two persons of 60 and over) of one old couple only
A505008 Family (with two persons of 60 and over) with one old couple and other persons under age of adult
A505009 Family with two persons of 60 and over (other)
A505010 Family households with persons aged 60 and over (other)

A506501 Family households with persons aged 65 and over
A506502 Family with one person of 65 and over
A506503 Family (with one person of 65 and over) of one old person only
A506504 Family (with one person of 65 and over) with one old person and other persons under age of adult
A506505 Family with one person of 65 and over (other)
A506506 Family with two persons of 65 and over
A506507 Family (with two persons of 65 and over) of one old couple only
A506508 Family (with two persons of 65 and over) with one old couple and other persons under age of adult
A506509 Family with two persons of 65 and over (other)
A506510 Family households with persons aged 65 and over (other)

A601001 Total deaths Population, all ages and both sexes (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601002 Total deaths Male, all ages (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601003 Total deaths Female, all ages (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601004  Deaths Population Aged 0 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601005  Deaths Male Aged 0 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601006  Deaths Female Aged 0 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601007  Deaths Population Aged 1-4 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601008  Deaths Male Aged 1-4 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601009  Deaths Female Aged 1-4 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601010  Deaths Population Aged 5-9 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601011  Deaths Male Aged 5-9 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601012  Deaths Female Aged 5-9 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601013  Deaths Population Aged 10-14 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601014  Deaths Male Aged 10-14 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601015  Deaths Female Aged 10-14 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601016  Deaths Population Aged 15-19 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601019  Deaths Male Aged 15-19 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601020  Deaths Female Aged 15-19 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601021  Deaths Population Aged 20-24 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601022  Deaths Male Aged 20-24 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601023  Deaths Female Aged 20-24 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601024  Deaths Population Aged 25-29 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601025  Deaths Male Aged 25-29 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601026  Deaths Female Aged 25-29 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601027  Deaths Population Aged 30-34 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601028  Deaths Male Aged 30-34 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601029  Deaths Female Aged 30-34 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601030  Deaths Population Aged 35-39 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601031  Deaths Male Aged 35-39 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601032  Deaths Female Aged 35-39 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601033  Deaths Population Aged 40-44 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601034  Deaths Male Aged 40-44 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601035  Deaths Female Aged 40-44 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601036  Deaths Population Aged 45-49 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601037  Deaths Male Aged 45-49 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601038  Deaths Female Aged 45-49 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601039  Deaths Population Aged 50-54 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601040  Deaths Male Aged 50-54 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601041  Deaths Female Aged 50-54 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601042  Deaths Population Aged 55-59 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601043  Deaths Male Aged 55-59 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601044  Deaths Female Aged 55-59 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601045  Deaths Population Aged 60-64 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601046  Deaths Male Aged 60-64 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601047  Deaths Female Aged 60-64 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601048  Deaths Population Aged 65-69 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601049  Deaths Male Aged 65-69 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601050  Deaths Female Aged 65-69 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601051  Deaths Population Aged 70-74 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601052  Deaths Male Aged 70-74 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601053  Deaths Female Aged 70-74 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601054  Deaths Population Aged 75-79 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601055  Deaths Male Aged 75-79 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601056  Deaths Female Aged 75-79 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601057  Deaths Population Aged 80-84 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601058  Deaths Male Aged 80-84 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601059  Deaths Female Aged 80-84 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601060  Deaths Population Aged 85-89 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601061  Deaths Male Aged 85-89 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601062  Deaths Female Aged 85-89 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601063  Deaths Population Aged 90-94 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601064  Deaths Male Aged 90-94 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601065  Deaths Female Aged 90-94 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601066  Deaths Population Aged 95-99 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601067  Deaths Male Aged 95-99 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601068  Deaths Female Aged 95-99 (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601069  Deaths Population Aged 100 and Over (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601070  Deaths Male Aged 100 and Over (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A601071  Deaths Female Aged 100 and Over (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)

A602001 Total Deaths Population aged 6+ (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A602002 Total Deaths Male aged 6+ (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A602003 Total Deaths Female aged 6+ (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A602004 Deaths Population Aged 6+ No Schooling (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A602005 Deaths Male Aged 6+ No Schooling (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A602006 Deaths Female Aged 6+ No Schooling (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A602007 Deaths Population Aged 6+ Eliminate Illiteracy (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A602008 Deaths Male Aged 6+ Eliminate Illiteracy (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A602009 Deaths Female Aged 6+ Eliminate Illiteracy (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A602010 Deaths Population Aged 6+ Primary School (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A602011 Deaths Male Aged 6+ Primary School (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A602012 Deaths Female Aged 6+ Primary School (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A602013 Deaths Population Aged 6+ Junior Middle School (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A602014 Deaths Male Aged 6+ Junior Middle School (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A602015 Deaths Female Aged 6+ Junior Middle School (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A602016 Deaths Population Aged 6+ Senior Middle School (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A602019 Deaths Male Aged 6+ Senior Middle School (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A602020 Deaths Female Aged 6+ Senior Middle School (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A602021 Deaths Population Aged 6+ Specialized Secondary School (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A602022 Deaths Male Aged 6+ Specialized Secondary School (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A602023 Deaths Female Aged 6+ Specialized Secondary School (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A602024 Deaths Population Aged 6+ Junior College (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A602025 Deaths Male Aged 6+ Junior College (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A602026 Deaths Female Aged 6+ Junior College (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A602027 Deaths Population Aged 6+ University (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A602028 Deaths Male Aged 6+ University (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A602029 Deaths Female Aged 6+ University (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A602030 Deaths Population Aged 6+ Graduate Student (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A602031 Deaths Male Aged 6+ Graduate Student (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A602032 Deaths Female Aged 6+ Graduate Student (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)

A603001 Deaths Population 15+ (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A603002 Deaths Male 15+ (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A603003 Deaths Female 15+ (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A603004 Deaths Population 15+ Never Married (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A603005 Deaths Male 15+ Never Married (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A603006 Deaths Female 15+ Never Married (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A603007 Deaths Population 15+ First Married (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A603008 Deaths Male 15+ First Married (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A603009 Deaths Female 15+ First Married (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A603010 Deaths Population 15+ Re-married (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A603011 Deaths Male 15+ Re-married (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A603012 Deaths Female 15+ Re-married (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A603013 Deaths Population 15+ Divorced (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A603014 Deaths Male 15+ Divorced (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A603015 Deaths Female 15+ Divorced (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A603016 Deaths Population 15+ Widowed (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A603017 Deaths Male 15+ Widowed (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)
A603018 Deaths Female 15+ Widowed (1999.11.1-2000.10.31)

A701001 Total Population Moved in from Other Household Registration Places
A701002 Population Moved in from Other Townships of This County/City
A701003 Population Moved in from Other Towns of This County/City
A701004 Population Moved in from Other Subdistricts of This County/City
A701005 Population Moved in from Other Townships of This City
A701006 Population Moved in from Other Towns of This City
A701007 Population Moved in from Other Subdistricts of This City
A701008 Population Moved in from Other Counties or Cities of This Province
A701009 Population Moved in from Other Provinces

A702001 Total Population moved in with household registration in other provinces
A702002 Population moved in with household registration in Beijing
A702003 Population moved in with household registration in Tianjin
A702004 Population moved in with household registration in Hebei
A702005 Population moved in with household registration in Shanxi
A702006 Population moved in with household registration in Inner Mongolia
A702007 Population moved in with household registration in Liaoning
A702008 Population moved in with household registration in Jilin
A702009 Population moved in with household registration in Heilongjiang
A702010 Population moved in with household registration in Shanhai
A702011 Population moved in with household registration in Jiangsu
A702012 Population moved in with household registration in Zhejiang
A702013 Population moved in with household registration in Anhui
A702014 Population moved in with household registration in Fujian
A702015 Population moved in with household registration in Jiangxi
A702016 Population moved in with household registration in Shandong
A702019 Population moved in with household registration in Henai
A702020 Population moved in with household registration in Hubei
A702021 Population moved in with household registration in Hunan
A702022 Population moved in with household registration in Guangdong
A702023 Population moved in with household registration in Guangxi
A702024 Population moved in with household registration in Hainan
A702025 Population moved in with household registration in Chongqing
A702026 Population moved in with household registration in Sichuan
A702027 Population moved in with household registration in Guizhou
A702028 Population moved in with household registration in Yunnan
A702029 Population moved in with household registration in Tibet
A702030 Population moved in with household registration in Shaanxi
A702031 Population moved in with household registration in Gansu
A702032 Population moved in with household registration in Qinghai
A702033 Population moved in with household registration in Ningxia
A702034 Population moved in with household registration in Xinjiang

A703001 Total population moved in from other places
A703002 Population Moved in from Same Province
A703003 Population Moved in from the Township of Same Province
A703004 Population Moved in from the Town of Same Province
A703005 Population Moved in from the Subdistrict of Same Province
A703006 Population Moved in from Other Counties or Cities of Same Province
A703007 Population Moved in from Other Provinces
A703008 Population Moved in from Beijing
A703009 Population Moved in from Tianjin
A703010 Population Moved in from Hebei
A703011 Population Moved in from Shanxi
A703012 Population Moved in from Inner Mongolia
A703013 Population Moved in from Liaoning
A703014 Population Moved in from Jilin
A703015 Population Moved in from Heilongjiang
A703016 Population Moved in from Shanhai
A703019 Population Moved in from Jiangsu
A703020 Population Moved in from Zhejiang
A703021 Population Moved in from Anhui
A703022 Population Moved in from Fujian
A703023 Population Moved in from Jiangxi
A703024 Population Moved in from Shandong
A703025 Population Moved in from Henai
A703026 Population Moved in from Hubei
A703027 Population Moved in from Hunan
A703028 Population Moved in from Guangdong
A703029 Population Moved in from Guangxi
A703030 Population Moved in from Hainan
A703031 Population Moved in from Chongqing
A703032 Population Moved in from Sichuan
A703033 Population Moved in from Guizhou
A703034 Population Moved in from Yunnan
A703035 Population Moved in from Tibet
A703036 Population Moved in from Shaanxi
A703037 Population Moved in from Gansu
A703038 Population Moved in from Qinghai
A703039 Population Moved in from Ningxia
A703040 Population Moved in from Xinjiang

A801001 Total Households with Dwelling Rooms
A801002 Households with 0 room
A801003 Households with One Room
A801004 Households with Two Rooms
A801005 Households with Three Rooms
A801006 Households with Four Rooms
A801007 Households with Five Rooms
A801008 Households with Six Rooms
A801009 Households with Seven Rooms
A801010 Households with Eight Rooms
A801011 Households with Nine Rooms
A801012 Households with Ten Rooms and Over
A801013 Average Rooms Per Household

A802001 Total Households
A802002 Households Per Capita Living Space Under 8(Sq.m)
A802003 Households Per Capita Living Space 9-12(Sq.m)
A802004 Households Per Capita Living Space 13-16(Sq.m)
A802005 Households Per Capita Living Space 17-19(Sq.m)
A802006 Households Per Capita Living Space 20-29(Sq.m)
A802007 Households Per Capita Living Space 30-39(Sq.m)
A802008 Households Per Capita Living Space 40-49(Sq.m)
A802009 Households Per Capita Living Space Over 50(Sq.m)

A803001 Total Households
A803002 Households with 0 Room and One Generation
A803003 Households with One Room and One Generation
A803004 Households with Two Rooms and One Generation
A803005 Households with Three Rooms and One Generation
A803006 Households with Four Rooms and One Generation
A803007 Households with Five Rooms and Over and One Generation
A803008 Households with 0 Room and Two Generation
A803009 Households with Two Room and Two Generation
A803010 Households with Two Rooms and Two Generation
A803011 Households with Three Rooms and Two Generation
A803012 Households with Four Rooms and Two Generation
A803013 Households with Five Rooms and Over and Two Generation
A803014 Households with 0 Room and Three Generation
A803015 Households with Three Room and Three Generation
A803016 Households with Three Rooms and Three Generation
A803019 Households with Three Rooms and Three Generation
A803020 Households with Four Rooms and Three Generation
A803021 Households with Five Rooms and Over and Three Generation
A803022 Households with 0 Room and Four Generation
A803023 Households with Four Room and Four Generation
A803024 Households with Four Rooms and Four Generation
A803025 Households with Four Rooms and Four Generation
A803026 Households with Four Rooms and Four Generation
A803027 Households with Five Rooms and Over and Four Generation
A803028 Households with 0 Room and Five Generation
A803029 Households with Five Room and Five Generation
A803030 Households with Five Rooms and Five Generation
A803031 Households with Five Rooms and Five Generation
A803032 Households with Five Rooms and Five Generation
A803033 Households with Five Rooms and Over and Five Generation</eaover>
</overview>
</eainfo>
<distinfo>
<distrib>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>China Data Center - University of Michigan</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
<address>1007 E Huron St</address>
<city>Ann Arbor</city>
<state>MI</state>
<postal>48104</postal>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>(734) 647-9610</cntvoice>
<cntfax>(734) 763-0335</cntfax>
<cntemail>chinadata@umich.edu</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</distrib>
<resdesc>cdc_2000_tibet_province2000a</resdesc>
<stdorder>
<digform>
<digtinfo>
<formname>Geopackage</formname>
<formspec>zip</formspec>

</digtinfo>
</digform>
</stdorder>
</distinfo>
<metainfo>
<metd>20090527</metd>
<metc>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>Research Data Services (RDS), Columbia University Libraries</cntorg>
<cntper>GIS/Metadata Librarian</cntper>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
<address>420 W. 118th St., 215 IAB, MC 3301</address>
<city>New York</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postal>10027</postal>
<country>USA</country>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>(212)854-6012</cntvoice>
<cntemail>data@library.columbia.edu</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</metc>
<metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
<mettc>local time</mettc>
</metainfo>
</metadata>
