<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><metadata>
<idinfo>
<citation>
<citeinfo>
<origin>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</origin>
<pubdate>1996</pubdate>
<title>World Faults, 1996</title>
<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
<serinfo>
<sername>ArcAtlas</sername>
</serinfo>
<pubinfo>
<pubplace>Redlands, Calif.</pubplace>
<publish>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</publish>
</pubinfo>
<onlink>https://www1.columbia.edu/sec/acis/eds/dgate/studies/C1301/data/esri_1996_world_faults.zip</onlink>
</citeinfo>
</citation>
<descript>
<abstract>Faults is a polyline theme representing fault lines worldwide.</abstract>
<purpose>For educational, non-commercial purposes.  This dataset is appropriate for use in a GIS.</purpose>
<supplinf>A fault, also known as a disjunctive dislocation, is a break in the continuity of a geological formation. Faults can be formed when the earth's crust is compressed or stretched. They vary greatly in size, both in length and depth. Faults are classified according to the type and direction of movement of the rocks on either side of the fault. For example, a fault along which no appreciable movement has occurred is called a joint. Faults with appreciable movement include vertical faults, thrust faults, transcurrent faults, and displacements.

A thrust fault usually has a gently sloping shift (45 to 60 degrees). A very gently sloping thrust with overlap of tens or hundreds of kilometers is called a tectonic or overthrust sheet.

Faults caused by stretching of the earth's crust frequently result in the subsidence of one block and the uplift of another block along the plane of fracture. These are called vertical or inclined faults. Large linear tectonic structures formed by horizontal stretching are called rifts. They usually form in association with vast, arched uplifting. Rifts can be thousands of kilometers long and hundreds of kilometers wide. A very large rift is called a rift belt or zone,
such as the east African rift zone or the Baykal rift zone.

Some faults incise the earth's crust and reach the earth's upper mantle. These are called deep faults and are typically hundreds or thousands of kilometers long, as much as 700 kilometers deep, and from several hundred meters to tens of kilometers wide. Deep faults are ancient. They bound large blocks of the earth's crust and have different structures and developments.

Two types of faults are shown on the maps. They are (1) faults created by the dislocation of rocks that define the geological structures of the continents and (2) faults created by the morphology of the present-day relief and morphostructure. The first ones include tectonic contacts and thrust-faults; they are displayed and interpreted with the Structural Geology. The second ones include steps and rifts: they are displayed and interpreted with Morphostructure maps. As a rule, the first type of faults are ancient structures, while those revealed by relief are comparatively young structures that appeared during the neotectonic stage of the earth's evolution (mostly in the Neogene and Quaternary periods).</supplinf>
</descript>
<timeperd>
<timeinfo>
<sngdate>
<caldate>1996</caldate>
</sngdate>
</timeinfo>
<current>publication date</current>
</timeperd>
<status>
<progress>Complete</progress>
<update>None planned</update>
</status>
<spdom>
<bounding>
<westbc>
-180</westbc>
<eastbc>
180</eastbc>
<northbc>
85</northbc>
<southbc>
-85</southbc>
</bounding>
</spdom>
<keywords>
<theme>
<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
<themekey>geoscientificinformation</themekey>
</theme>
<theme>
<themekt>None</themekt>
<themekey>Faults</themekey>
</theme>
<place>
	<placekt>GeoNames</placekt>
	<placekey>Earth (6295630)</placekey>
</place>
<place>
<placekt>Library of Congress Subject Headings</placekt>
<placekey>Earth</placekey>
</place>
<temporal>
<tempkt>None</tempkt>
<tempkey>1996</tempkey>
</temporal>
</keywords>
<accconst>For current Columbia affiliates only.</accconst>

<useconst>For educational, non-commercial use only.</useconst>
<ptcontac>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>ESRI</cntorg>
<cntper>Data Team</cntper>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
<address>380 New York Street</address>
<city>Redlands</city>
<state>California</state>
<postal>92373-8100</postal>
<country>USA</country>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>909-793-2853</cntvoice>
<cntfax>909-793-5953</cntfax>
<cntemail>info@esri.com</cntemail>
<hours>7:00 a.m.-5:30 p.m. Pacific time, Monday-Friday</hours>
<cntinst>n the United States- Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing and consulting services to your local ESRI Regional Office. For support, you may contact Technical Support by telephone (voice) between 6:00 a.m. and 5:00 p.m. Pacific time, Monday through Friday, by dialing 888-377-4575; facsimile (fax) available at 909-792-0960; electronic mail (e-mail) support@esri.com; or visit http://support.esri.com; ESRI holidays excluded. Outside the United States Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing, sales, support, and consulting services to your local ESRI International Distributor. This information can be found at http://gis.esri.com/intldist/contactint.cfm. For other questions or comments, you may contact ESRI headquarters by e-mail, telephone, or fax or write to us.</cntinst>
</cntinfo>
</ptcontac>
<browse>
<browsen>http://www.columbia.edu/acis/eds/gis/pix/cat/faults.jpg</browsen>
<browsed>Thumbnail</browsed>
<browset>JPEG</browset>
</browse>
<native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.1850</native>
</idinfo>
<dataqual>
<lineage>
<procstep>
<procdesc>The fault maps in this atlas show the relatively large faults that reveal the geological structure of the continents, mainly fold or block structures. The location of faults corresponds to the strike of shifted rocks. Information on two types of tectonic dislocations is also given. The two types are (1) tectonic contacts with dominant vertical dislocations of rocks (mainly faults, upthrust faults, etc.) and (2) tectonic contacts with dominant horizontal dislocations of rocks (thrusts).

The morphostructure maps show the largest faults differently revealed by present-day relief. They are borders of mountains and platformian plains, ranges and depressions, various pronounced parts of river valleys, chains of lake depressions, and so on.

The attributes on the faults were acquired from the survey maps and regional geological and geomorphological maps that were used to compile the geological and geomorphological maps. The maps were of various scales.

References:

Bozhko, N. A. Pozdniy dokembriy Gondvany (The Late Precambrian of Gondwana). 1984.
Nedra, Moscow. 230 p.

Carta geologica de Angola (parte Queste), 1:1,000,000. 1980. Geol. Surv., Luanda.

Carta geologica nacional de la Republica del Ecuador, 1:1,000,000. 1982. Dir. general
de Geol. y Minas Ministerio de Recursos Naturales y Energeticos, Quito.

Carta geologico-Economica de la Republica Argentina, 1:2,000,000. 1979. Secretaria de
Mineria.

Carte lithologique du Rwanda, 1:250,000. 1981. Inst. Geographique National de
Belgique.

Carte structurale du Maroc, 1:2,000,000. 1982. Geol. Surv.

Dokembriy kontinentov (The Precambrian of the continents). 1976. Nauka, Novosibirsk. 230
pp.

Elizariev, Yu. Z. at al. Geologicheskaya karta Afriki (Geological map of Africa),
1:5,000,000. 1979. Ministry of Geology of the USSR, Moscow.

Elizariev, Yu. Z. and V. E. Zabrodin. Ob'yasnitel'naya zapiska k geologicheskoy karte Afriki
masshtaba 1:5,000,000 (Explanation to Geological map of Africa on a 1:5,000,000 scale).
1980. Ministry of Geology of the USSR, Moscow. 62 pp.

Geological map of Asia, 1:5,000,000. 1975. Sci. Press, Beijing.

Geological map of Brazil and adjoining ocean floor including mineral deposits,
1:2,500,000. 1983. Min. das Minas e Energia, Dep. Nac. de Produsao mineral, Brazilia.

Geological map of China, 1:12,000,000. In: The Atlas of Endemic Diseases and their
Environments in the People's Republic of China. 1989. Sci. Press, Beijing.

Geological map of China, 1:4,000,000. 1979. Beijing (in Chinese).

Geological map of Egypt, 1:2,000,000. 1981. Geol. Surv., Cairo.

Geological map of Liberia, 1:1,000,000. 1983. Geol. Surv., USA.

Geological map of the Republic of Botswana, 1:1,000,000. 1984. Geol. Surv., Botswana.

Geological map of South Australia, 1:1,000,000. 1983. Geol. Surv., Dep. Min. and
Energy, Canberra.

Geological map of South Australia, 1:2,000,000. 1982. Geol. Surv., Dep. Min. and
Energy, Canberra.

Geological map of Vietnam, 1:1,500,000. 1982. Hanoi.

Geological World Atlas. 1974. UNESCO, Paris.

Geologicheskaya karta (Geological map ), 1:3,000,000. 1990. In: Natsional'nyy atlas
Mongol'skoy Narodnoy Respubliki (National Atlas of Mongolian Peple's Republic), GUGK,
Moscow.

Geologicheskaya karta Laosskoy Narodno-Demokraticheskoy Respubliki (Geological map of
Laos People's Democratic Republic), 1:1,500,000. 1979. GUGK, Moscow.

Geologicheskaya karta poluostrova Indokitay i prilegayushhikh territoriy (Geological map of
Indo-China Peninsula and adjacent areas), 1:2,500,000. 1983. GUGK, Moscow.

Geologicheskaya karta Rossii i stran SNG (Geological map of Russia and CIS), 1:5,000,000.
1992. Goskomgeologiya, Moscow. 4 p.

Geologicheskaya karta Zondskikh i Filippinskikh ostrovov (Geological map of Sunda and
Philippines Islands), 1:2,500,000. 1983. GUGK, Moscow.

Geology of Eastern Canada and adjacent areas, 1:2,000,000. 1979. Geol. Surv., Can.,
Ottawa.

International Geological Map of Europe, 1:1,500,000. 1969-1972. 3rd ed. UNESCO, Paris.
International Geological Map of Europe and Mediterranean Region, 1:1,500,000. 1971.
UNESCO, Paris.

Ivanov, Yu. A. et al. Ob'yasnitel'naya zapiska k geologicheskoy karte Yuzhnoy Ameriki
masshtaba 1:5,000,000 (Explanation to Geological map of South America on a
1:5,000,000 scale). 1979. Ministry of Geology of the USSR, Moscow. 136 pp.

Khain, V. E. Regional'naya geotektonika. Severnaya i Yuzhnaya Amerika, Antarktida, Afrika
(Regional geotectonics. North and South Americas, Antarctica, Africa). 1971. Nedra,
Moscow. 548 pp.

Khain, V. E. Regional'naya geotektonika. Vneal'piyskaya Evropa i Zapadnaya Aziya
(Regional geotectonics. Non-Alpine Europe and West Asia). 1977. Nedra, Moscow. 360
pp.

Khain, V. E. Regional'naya geotektonika. Vneal'piyskaya Aziya i Avstraliya (Regional
geotectonics. Non-Alpine Asia and Australia). 1979. Nedra, Moscow. 358 pp.

King, F. B. Dokembriyskaya geologiya SShA (Precambrian geology of the U.S.A.) --
explanation to the geological map. 1979. Mir, Moscow. 96 pp.

Mapa Geologico de Chile, 1:1,000,000. 1982. Santiago.

Mapa Geologico de la Republica Argentina, 1:2,500,000. 1982. Secretaria de Minerala,
Buenos Aires.

Matveevskaya, A. L. Zapadnaya Evropa -- dokembriy kaledonskoy i varistsiyskoy zon (West
Europe -- the Precambrian of the Caledonian and Variscian zones). 1975. Nauka,
Novosibirsk. 84 pp.

Metallogenic map of South America, 1:5,000,000. 1983. Subcommission for the
Metallogenic map of the World, Caracas.

Mineral deposits and principal mineral occurrence of the Canadian Cordillera and
adjacent part of the United States, 1:2,000,000. 1984. Geol. Surv. Can., Ottawa.

Principal mineral areas of Canada, 1:7,603,200. 1984. Geol. Surv., Can., Ottawa.

Salop. L. I. Obshhaya stratigraficheskaya shkala dokembriya (General stratigraphic range of
the Precambrian). 1973. Nedra, Leningrad. 309 pp.

Salop, L. I. Periodizatsiya i korrelyatsiya dokembriya yuzhnykh materikov. Dokembriy Afriki
(Periods and correlation of the Precambrian of the southern continents. The Precambrian
of Africa). 1977. Nedra, Leningrad. 304 pp.

Stille, H. Grundfragen der vergleichenden Tektonik. 1924. Berlin, v. 8, 443 pp.

Tectonic Map of South Australia, 1:2,000,000. 1982. Geol Surv. S. Australia, Dep. Min.
and Energy, Canberra.

Tektonika Evropy i smezhnykh oblastey. Drevniye platformy, Baykalidy, Kaledonidy --
ob'yasnitel'naya zapiska k mezhdunarodnoy tektonicheskoy karte Evropy i smezhnykh
oblastey masshtaba 1:2,500,000 (Tectonics of Europe and adjoining areas. Ancient
platforms, Baykalides, Caledonides -- explanation to International tectonic map of Europe
and adjacent areas on a 1:2,500,000
scale). 1978. Nauka, Moscow. 421 pp.

Tektonika Evropy i smezhnykh oblastey. Varistsidy, ehpipaleozoyskiye platformy, Al'pidy --
ob'yasnitel'naya zapiska k mezhdunarodnoy tektonicheskoy karte Evropy i smezhnykh
oblastey masshtaba 1:2,500,000 (Tectonics of Europe and adjoining areas. Variscides,
epipaleozoic platforms, Alpides -- explanation to International tectonic map of Europe and
adjacent areas on a 1:2,500,000 scale). 1978. Nauka, Moscow. 587 pp.</procdesc>
<srcused>See process description</srcused>
<procdate>Unknown</procdate>
<proccont>
<cntinfo>
<cntaddr>
</cntaddr>
</cntinfo>
</proccont>
</procstep>
<procstep>
<procdesc>Datasets for each continent were converted from ESRI coverage to the ESRI shapefile format using the 'copy features' tool and merged into one layer using the 'merge' tool.</procdesc>
<procdate>20090507</procdate>
<proccont>
<cntinfo>
<cntperp>
<cntper>GIS/Map Librarian</cntper>
<cntorg>Research Data Services (RDS), Columbia University Libraries</cntorg>
</cntperp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
<address>420 W. 118th St. 215 IAB, MC 3301</address>
<city>New York</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postal>10027</postal>
<country>USA</country>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>(212) 854-6012</cntvoice>
<cntemail>data@library.columbia.edu</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</proccont>
</procstep>
</lineage>
</dataqual>
<spdoinfo>
<direct>Vector</direct>
<ptvctinf>
<sdtsterm>
<sdtstype>String</sdtstype>
<ptvctcnt>4441</ptvctcnt>
</sdtsterm>
</ptvctinf>
</spdoinfo>
<spref>
<horizsys>
<geograph>
<latres>0.000000</latres>
<longres>0.000000</longres>
<geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
</geograph>
<geodetic>
<horizdn>D_Clarke_1866</horizdn>
<ellips>Clarke 1866</ellips>
<semiaxis>6378206.400000</semiaxis>
<denflat>294.978698</denflat>
</geodetic>
</horizsys>
</spref>
<eainfo>
<detailed>
<enttyp>
<enttypl>
faults</enttypl>
<enttypd>Faults</enttypd>
</enttyp>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FNODE_</attrlabl>
<attrdef>From Node</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>TNODE_</attrlabl>
<attrdef>To node</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>LPOLY_</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Left polygon</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>RPOLY_</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Right polygon</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>LENGTH</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Length</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>AFFALSDD_</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Africa</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>AFFALSDD_I</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Africa</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>TYPE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The type of the fault</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ASFALSDD_</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Africa</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ASFALSDD_I</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Africa</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>AUFALSDD_</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Australia</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>AUFALSDD_I</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Australia</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>EUFALSDD_</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Europe</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>EUFALSDD_I</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Europe</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>NAFALSDD_</attrlabl>
<attrdef>North America</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>NAFALSDD_I</attrlabl>
<attrdef>North America</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SAFALSDD_</attrlabl>
<attrdef>South America</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SAFALSDD_I</attrlabl>
<attrdef>South America</attrdef>
</attr>
</detailed>
</eainfo>
<distinfo>
<distrib>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>ESRI; ESRI International Distributors</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
<address>380 New York Street</address>
<city>Redlands</city>
<state>California</state>
<postal>92373-8100</postal>
<country>USA</country>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>800-447-9778</cntvoice>
<cntinst>In the United States, contact the ESRI Telebusiness staff at 800-447-9778 for more information about our software and data. Outside the United States, please direct all inquiries to your local ESRI International Distributor. This information can be found at http://gis.esri.com/intldist/contactint.cfm.</cntinst>
</cntinfo>
</distrib>
<resdesc>esri_1996_world_faults</resdesc>
<stdorder>
<digform>
<digtinfo>
<formname>geopackage</formname>
<formspec>zip</formspec>

</digtinfo>
</digform>
</stdorder>
</distinfo>
<metainfo>
<metd>20090701</metd>
<metc>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>Research Data Services (RDS), Columbia University Libraries</cntorg>
<cntper>GIS/Metadata Librarian</cntper>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
<address>420 W. 118th St. 215 IAB, MC 3301</address>
<city>New York</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postal>10027</postal>
<country>USA</country>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>(212) 854-6012</cntvoice>
<cntemail>data@library.columbia.edu</cntemail>
<hours>7:00 a.m.-5:30 p.m. Pacific time, Monday-Friday</hours>
</cntinfo>
</metc>
<metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
<mettc>local time</mettc>
</metainfo>
</metadata>
