<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
	<idinfo>
		<citation>
			<citeinfo>
				<origin>Geological Survey (U.S.)</origin>
				<origin>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</origin>
				<pubdate>2022</pubdate>
				<title>United States National Atlas Water Feature Areas, 2022</title>
				<edition>2022</edition>
				<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
				<serinfo>
					<sername>ArcGIS Data and Maps</sername>
					<issue>2022 - World, Europe, and United States</issue>
				</serinfo>
				<pubinfo>
					<pubplace>Redlands, California, USA</pubplace>
					<publish>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</publish>
				</pubinfo>
				<othercit>Location: \usa\hydro</othercit>
				<onlink>https://www1.columbia.edu/sec/acis/eds/dgate/studies/C1301/data/esri_2022_us_hydroply.zip</onlink>
			</citeinfo>
		</citation>
		<descript>
			<langdata>eng</langdata>
			<abstract>U.S. National Atlas Water Feature Areas - Water Bodies represents the water feature areas (for example, glaciers, lakes, reservoirs, and swamps) of the United States.</abstract>
			<purpose>U.S. National Atlas Water Feature Areas - Water Bodies provides the water feature areas for geographic display and analysis at regional and national levels.</purpose>
		</descript>
		<timeperd>
			<timeinfo>
				<sngdate>
					<caldate>20120701</caldate>
				</sngdate>
			</timeinfo>
			<current>publication date</current>
		</timeperd>
		<status>
			<progress>Complete</progress>
			<update>Annually</update>
		</status>
		<spdom>
			<bounding>
				<westbc>-167.702866</westbc>
				<eastbc>-65.602569</eastbc>
				<northbc>71.322163</northbc>
				<southbc>17.930832</southbc>
			</bounding>
		</spdom>
		<keywords>
			<theme>
				<themekt>None</themekt>
				<themekey>polygon</themekey>
				<themekey>lakes</themekey>
				<themekey>hydrography</themekey>
				<themekey>glaciers</themekey>
				<themekey>inlandWaters</themekey>
				<themekey>reservoirs</themekey>
				<themekey>swamps</themekey>
				<themekey>streams</themekey>
				<themekey>water</themekey>
			</theme>
			<theme>
				<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
				<themekey>inlandWaters</themekey>
			</theme>
			<place>
				<placekt>GeoNames</placekt>
				<placekey>United States (6252001)</placekey>
			</place>
			<place>
				<placekt>None</placekt>
				<placekey>United States</placekey>
				<placekey>Puerto Rico</placekey>
			</place>
			<place>
				<placekt>Library of Congress Subject Headings</placekt>
				<placekey>United States</placekey>
			</place>
			<temporal>
				<tempkt>None</tempkt>
				<tempkey>2012</tempkey>
			</temporal>
		</keywords>
<accconst>The data are provided by multiple, third party data vendors under license to Esri for inclusion on ArcGIS Data and Maps for use with ArcGIS software. Each data vendor has its own data licensing policies and may grant varying redistribution rights to end users. Consult the redistribution rights below for this dataset provided on Data and Maps. As used herein, "Geodata" shall mean any digital dataset consisting of geographic data coordinates and associated attributes.

The redistribution rights for this dataset: Public domain data from U.S. government is freely redistributable with proper metadata and source attribution.

The terms and conditions below apply to all the datasets provided on Data and Maps.

Proprietary Rights and Copyright: Licensee acknowledges that the Data and Related Materials contain proprietary and confidential property of Esri and its licensor(s). The Data and Related Materials are owned by Esri and its licensor(s) and are protected by United States copyright laws and applicable international copyright treaties and/or conventions.

Limited Warranty and Disclaimer: Esri warrants that the media upon which the Data and Related Materials are provided will be free from defects in materials and workmanship under normal use and service for a period of ninety (90) days from the date of receipt.

THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS ARE EXCLUDED FROM THE LIMITED WARRANTY, AND THE LICENSEE EXPRESSLY ACKNOWLEDGES THAT THE DATA CONTAINS SOME NONCONFORMITIES, DEFECTS, OR ERRORS. ESRI DOES NOT WARRANT THAT THE DATA WILL MEET LICENSEE'S NEEDS OR EXPECTATIONS; THAT THE USE OF THE DATA WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED; OR THAT ALL NONCONFORMITIES, DEFECTS, OR ERRORS CAN OR WILL BE CORRECTED. ESRI IS NOT INVITING RELIANCE ON THIS DATA, AND THE LICENSEE SHOULD ALWAYS VERIFY ACTUAL DATA.

EXCEPT FOR THE LIMITED WARRANTY SET FORTH ABOVE, THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS CONTAINED THEREIN ARE PROVIDED "AS-IS," WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.

HIGH RISK ACTIVITIES:
(A) THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS ARE NOT FAULT-TOLERANT AND ARE NOT DESIGNED, MANUFACTURED, OR INTENDED FOR USE OR RESALE FOR INSURANCE UNDERWRITING OR WITH CRITICAL HEALTH AND SAFETY OR ONLINE CONTROL EQUIPMENT IN HAZARDOUS ENVIRONMENTS THAT REQUIRE FAIL-SAFE PERFORMANCE, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE OPERATION OF NUCLEAR FACILITIES, NAVIGATION OR GUIDANCE (I.E., AIRCRAFT, NAUTICAL VEHICLE, AND SO ON), OR COMMUNICATION SYSTEMS, AIR TRAFFIC CONTROL, EMERGENCY RESPONSE, TERRORISM PREVENTION OR RESPONSE, LIFE SUPPORT, OR WEAPONS SYSTEMS ("HIGH RISK ACTIVITIES"). ESRI SPECIFICALLY DISCLAIMS ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTY OF FITNESS FOR HIGH RISK ACTIVITIES.

(B) TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY LAW, LICENSEE AGREES TO INDEMNIFY, DEFEND, AND HOLD ESRI, ITS OFFICERS, DIRECTORS, EMPLOYEES, AGENTS, SUBCONTRACTORS, LICENSORS, SUCCESSORS, AND ASSIGNS HARMLESS FROM AND AGAINST ANY AND ALL LIABILITY, LOSSES, CLAIMS, EXPENSES (INCLUDING ATTORNEYS' FEES), DEMANDS, OR DAMAGES OF ANY KIND, INCLUDING DIRECT, INDIRECT, SPECIAL, PUNITIVE, INCIDENTAL, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES, ARISING OUT OF OR IN ANY WAY CONNECTED WITH LICENSEE'S USE OR PERMITTING THE USE BY OTHERS OF THE DATA, AND VENDOR'S HARDWARE OR SOFTWARE FOR HIGH RISK ACTIVITIES. DELIVERY OF THE DATA, AND VENDOR'S HARDWARE OR SOFTWARE DOES NOT CONSTITUTE A WAIVER OF THE RIGHTS AND OBLIGATIONS SET FORTH IN THIS ARTICLE.

Exclusive Remedy and Limitation of Liability: The entire liability of Esri or its licensor(s) and Licensee's exclusive remedy shall be to terminate the Agreement upon Licensee returning the Data and Related Materials to Esri with a copy of Licensee's invoice/receipt and Esri returning the license fees paid to Licensee.

IN NO EVENT SHALL ESRI AND/OR ITS LICENSOR(S) BE LIABLE FOR COSTS OF PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOST PROFITS, LOST SALES, OR BUSINESS EXPENDITURES, INVESTMENTS, OR COMMITMENTS IN CONNECTION WITH ANY BUSINESS; LOSS OF ANY GOODWILL; OR FOR ANY INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF THIS AGREEMENT OR USE OF THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS, HOWEVER CAUSED, ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, AND WHETHER OR NOT ESRI OR ITS LICENSOR(S) HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE. THESE LIMITATIONS SHALL APPLY NOTWITHSTANDING ANY FAILURE OF ESSENTIAL PURPOSE OF ANY EXCLUSIVE REMEDY.

Third Party Beneficiary: Esri's licensor(s) has (have) authorized Esri to (sub)distribute and (sub)license its (their) data as incorporated into the Data and Related Materials. As an intended third party beneficiary to this Agreement, the Esri licensor(s) is (are) entitled to directly enforce, in its own name, the rights and obligations undertaken by the Licensee and to seek all legal and equitable remedies as are afforded to Esri.

In the event that the data vendor(s) has (have) granted the end user permission to redistribute the Geodata, use proper proprietary or copyright attribution for the various data vendor(s), and provide the associated metadata file(s) with the Geodata. In compliance with FGDC metadata standards, Esri has attempted to practice proper metadata methodologies by providing any data source information, descriptions, and file names to assist in this effort.

	</accconst>
	<useconst>For educational, non-commercial use only.</useconst>
	<ptcontac>
		<cntinfo>
			<cntorgp>
				<cntorg>Esri</cntorg>
				<cntper>ArcGIS Content Team</cntper>
			</cntorgp>
			<cntaddr>
				<addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
				<address>380 New York Street</address>
				<city>Redlands</city>
				<state>California</state>
				<postal>92373-8100</postal>
				<country>US</country>
			</cntaddr>
			<cntvoice>+1-909-793-2853</cntvoice>
			<cntfax>+1-909-793-5953</cntfax>
			<cntemail>info@esri.com</cntemail>
			<hours>9:00 a.m.-5:00 p.m. Pacific time, Monday-Friday</hours>
<cntinst>In the United States- Direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing and consulting services to your local Esri Regional Office. For support, contact Esri by telephone (voice) between 5:00 a.m. and 5:00 p.m. Pacific time, Monday through Friday, by dialing +1-888-377-4575; facsimile (fax) available at +1-909-792-0960; or visit https://support.esri.com/; Esri holidays excluded. Email and chat are available through the Support page on My Esri (https://my.esri.com).

Outside the United States- Direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing, sales, support, and consulting services to your local Esri Office. This information can be found at https://www.esri.com/en-us/contact#c=us&amp;t=0. For other questions or comments, you may contact Esri headquarters by email, telephone, or fax or write to us.</cntinst>
		</cntinfo>
	</ptcontac>
	<native> Version 6.2 (Build 9200) ; Esri ArcGIS 10.9.1.28388</native>
</idinfo>
<dataqual>
	<logic>The dataset is converted to file geodatabase (FGDB) format using tools in ArcGIS. The geometry is checked, and if needed repaired.</logic>
<complete>After processing, the dataset is checked for drawing display and number of records and file sizes compared with source materials.

This map layer contains water bodies of the United States and Puerto Rico. Only water bodies appropriate for a 1:1,000,000- scale data set are included. Water bodies smaller than one square kilometer are excluded unless one of the following applies: they are in the National Atlas 1:2,000,000-scale map layer, they are in other small- scale data sets or maps, they cover a small coastal island, they have been merged with a larger feature, or their size has been reduced during alignment with other 1:1,000,000-scale map layers.

Swamps and marshes may be underrepresented in some areas. In the southeastern U.S., some swamp/marsh limits were difficult to determine due to unclear or conflicting information in imagery, topographical maps, and landcover. In Alaska, swamps and marshes appear to be underrepresented when compared to landcover data sets and topographical maps. Water bodies may also be underrepresented in areas that contain large numbers of small isolated features which were too far apart to aggregate and too small to be included by themselves.</complete>
	<posacc>
		<horizpa>
<horizpar>Water bodies are in approximately the same locations as in the NHD 100K water bodies data used as a source. However, many processes and editing tasks resulted in the movement of water body limits from their original positions, including: generalizing and aggregating water bodies, modifying water bodies to meet minimum width standards, moving water body limits 300 meters from transportation features if the two were parallel, extending or trimming water bodies to intersect coastlines or international boundaries, increasing or decreasing the gap between neighboring water bodies, adjusting water bodies to fit the streams that flow through them, and modifying water bodies to match imagery.

Horizontal positions are specified in geographic coordinates in decimal degrees. Latitudes are given to the nearest 0.000150. Longitudes are given to the nearest 0.000150. The positional accuracy is unknown.</horizpar>
		</horizpa>
	</posacc>
	<lineage>
		<srcinfo>
			<srccite>
				<citeinfo>
					<origin>National Atlas of the United States</origin>
					<pubdate>20120701</pubdate>
					<title>1:1,000,000-Scale Waterbodies of the United States</title>
					<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
					<pubinfo>
						<pubplace>Reston, Virginia, USA</pubplace>
						<publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
					</pubinfo>
					<onlink>https://www.usgs.gov/faqs/national-atlas-program-has-ended-any-data-still-available?qt-news_science_products=0#qt-news_science_products</onlink>
				</citeinfo>
			</srccite>
			<srcscale>1000000</srcscale>
			<typesrc>onLine</typesrc>
			<srctime>
				<timeinfo>
					<sngdate>
						<caldate>20120701</caldate>
					</sngdate>
				</timeinfo>
				<srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
			</srctime>
			<srccitea>National Atlas</srccitea>
			<srccontr>Attribute and geospatial data</srccontr>
		</srcinfo>
		<procstep>
			<procdesc>The following steps were performed by Esri: Downloaded the compressed file from the National Atlas of the United States and extracted it. Removed unneeded fields. Renamed some fields. Projected the dataset into WGS 1984. Converted the dataset into a file geodatabase.</procdesc>
			<srcused>withheld</srcused>
			<procdate>20131106</procdate>
		</procstep>
	</lineage>
</dataqual>
<spdoinfo>
	<direct>Vector</direct>
	<ptvctinf>
		<sdtsterm>
			<sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
			<ptvctcnt>26872</ptvctcnt>
		</sdtsterm>
	</ptvctinf>
</spdoinfo>
<spref>
	<horizsys>
		<geograph>
			<latres>0.000000</latres>
			<longres>0.000000</longres>
			<geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
		</geograph>
		<geodetic>
			<horizdn>D_WGS_1984</horizdn>
			<ellips>WGS_1984</ellips>
			<semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
			<denflat>298.257224</denflat>
		</geodetic>
	</horizsys>
	<vertdef>
		<altsys>
			<altres>0.000100</altres>
			<altenc>Explicit elevation coordinate included with horizontal coordinates</altenc>
		</altsys>
	</vertdef>
</spref>
<eainfo>
	<detailed>
		<enttyp>
			<enttypl>hydroply</enttypl>
			<enttypd>The polygons represent the water feature areas within United States.</enttypd>
			<enttypds>National Atlas of the United States</enttypds>
		</enttyp>
		<attr>
			<attrlabl>ObjectID</attrlabl>
			<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
			<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
			<attrdomv>
				<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
			</attrdomv>
		</attr>
		<attr>
			<attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
			<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
			<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
			<attrdomv>
				<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
			</attrdomv>
		</attr>
		<attr>
			<attrlabl>NAME</attrlabl>
			<attrdef>The proper name of the water feature.</attrdef>
			<attrdefs>National Atlas of the United States</attrdefs>
			<attrdomv>
				<udom>Names for the features.</udom>
			</attrdomv>
		</attr>
		<attr>
			<attrlabl>FEATURE</attrlabl>
			<attrdef>The type of water feature.</attrdef>
			<attrdefs>National Atlas of the United States</attrdefs>
			<attrdomv>
				<edom>
					<edomv>Canal</edomv>
					<edomvds>National Atlas of the United States</edomvds>
					<edomvd>An artificial open waterway constructed to transport water, to irrigate or drain land, to connect two or more bodies of water, or to serve as a waterway for water craft.</edomvd>
				</edom>
				<edom>
					<edomv>Glacier</edomv>
					<edomvds>National Atlas of the United States</edomvds>
					<edomvd>A field of ice.</edomvd>
				</edom>
				<edom>
					<edomv>Lake</edomv>
					<edomvds>National Atlas of the United States</edomvds>
					<edomvd>A standing body of water with a predominately natural shoreline surrounded by land.</edomvd>
				</edom>
				<edom>
					<edomv>Lake Dry</edomv>
					<edomvds>National Atlas of the United States</edomvds>
					<edomvd>An area that at one time contained a standing body of water.</edomvd>
				</edom>
				<edom>
					<edomv>Lake Intermittent</edomv>
					<edomvds>National Atlas of the United States</edomvds>
					<edomvd>A standing body of water that contains water for only part of the year.</edomvd>
				</edom>
				<edom>
					<edomv>Reservoir</edomv>
					<edomvds>National Atlas of the United States</edomvds>
					<edomvd>A constructed basin formed to contain water.</edomvd>
				</edom>
				<edom>
					<edomv>Stream</edomv>
					<edomvds>National Atlas of the United States</edomvds>
					<edomvd>A body of flowing water.</edomvd>
				</edom>
				<edom>
					<edomv>Swamp or Marsh</edomv>
					<edomvds>National Atlas of the United States</edomvds>
					<edomvd>A non-cultivated, vegetated area that is inundated or saturated for a significant part of the year.</edomvd>
				</edom>
			</attrdomv>
		</attr>
		<attr>
			<attrlabl>STATE</attrlabl>
			<attrdef>The two-letter abbreviation for each state where the water feature is located. If the water feature falls in multiple states, multiple state codes are listed, separated by a dash.</attrdef>
			<attrdefs>Department of Commerce, National Institute of Standards and Technology</attrdefs>
			<attrdomv>
				<codesetd>
					<codesetn>Federal Information Processing Standards 5-2</codesetn>
					<codesets>National Institute of Standards and Technology</codesets>
				</codesetd>
			</attrdomv>
		</attr>
		<attr>
			<attrlabl>Region</attrlabl>
			<attrdef>The hydrologic unit code for the major river basin in which the water feature is located. Leading zeroes are not shown. If the water feature falls in two regions, the code for the region containing the majority of the water feature is used.</attrdef>
			<attrdefs>National Atlas of the United States</attrdefs>
			<attrdomv>
				<rdom>
					<rdommin>1</rdommin>
					<rdommax>21</rdommax>
				</rdom>
			</attrdomv>
		</attr>
		<attr>
			<attrlabl>SQMI</attrlabl>
			<attrdef>The area of the water feature in square miles, calculated using the North America Albers Equal Area Conic projection.</attrdef>
			<attrdefs>National Atlas of the United States</attrdefs>
			<attrdomv>
				<udom>Calculated areas for the features.</udom>
			</attrdomv>
		</attr>
		<attr>
			<attrlabl>Perimeter</attrlabl>
			<attrdef>The length of the water feature perimeter in miles, calculated using the North America Albers Equal Area Conic projection.</attrdef>
			<attrdefs>National Atlas of the United States</attrdefs>
			<attrdomv>
				<udom>Calculated lengths for the features.</udom>
			</attrdomv>
		</attr>
		<attr>
			<attrlabl>Shape_Length</attrlabl>
			<attrdef>Length of feature in internal units.</attrdef>
			<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
			<attrdomv>
				<udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
			</attrdomv>
		</attr>
		<attr>
			<attrlabl>Shape_Area</attrlabl>
			<attrdef>Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef>
			<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
			<attrdomv>
				<udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
			</attrdomv>
		</attr>
	</detailed>
</eainfo>
<distinfo>
	<distrib>
		<cntinfo>
			<cntorgp>
				<cntorg>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</cntorg>
			</cntorgp>
			<cntaddr>
				<addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
				<address>380 New York Street</address>
				<city>Redlands</city>
				<state>California</state>
				<postal>92373-8100</postal>
				<country>US</country>
			</cntaddr>
			<cntvoice>+1-800-447-9778</cntvoice>
<cntinst>In the United States, contact the Esri Sales staff at +1-800-447-9778 or visit https://www.esri.com/en-us/contact#c=us&amp;t=1 for more information about our software and data.

Outside the United States, direct all inquiries to your local Esri Office. This information can be found at https://www.esri.com/en-us/contact#c=us&amp;t=0.</cntinst>
		</cntinfo>
	</distrib>

	<distliab>See access and use constraints information.</distliab>
	<stdorder>
		<digform>
			<digtinfo>
				<formname>GeoPackage</formname>
				<formcont>To use this data requires software that works with FGDB files.</formcont>
				
				<transize>33.0 MB</transize>
			</digtinfo>
			<digtopt>
				<onlinopt>
					<computer>
						<networka>
							<networkr>https://www.arcgis.com/home/group.html?id=24838c2d95e14dd18c25e9bad55a7f82#overview</networkr>
						</networka>
					</computer>
					<accinstr>Downloadable Data; Hosted Feature Layer</accinstr>
				</onlinopt>
				<onlinopt>
					<computer>
						<networka>
							<networkr>https://my.esri.com</networkr>
						</networka>
					</computer>
				</onlinopt>
				<offoptn>
					<offmedia>dvd</offmedia>
					<reccap>
						<recden>4.38 or 7.95</recden>
						<recdenu>GB (gigabytes)</recdenu>
					</reccap>
					<recfmt>Universal Disk Format file system</recfmt>
					<compat>Offline Data</compat>
				</offoptn>
			</digtopt>
		</digform>
		<fees>Software purchase price</fees>
		<ordering>Data and Maps is available only as part of ArcGIS software.</ordering>
	</stdorder>
	<resdesc>esri_2022_us_hydroply</resdesc>
</distinfo>
<metainfo>
	<metd>20220822</metd>
	<metc>
		<cntinfo>
			<cntorgp>
				<cntorg>Esri</cntorg>
				<cntper>ArcGIS Content Team</cntper>
			</cntorgp>
			<cntaddr>
				<addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
				<address>380 New York Street</address>
				<city>Redlands</city>
				<state>California</state>
				<postal>92373-8100</postal>
				<country>US</country>
			</cntaddr>
			<cntvoice>+1-909-793-2853</cntvoice>
			<cntfax>+1-909-793-5953</cntfax>
			<cntemail>info@esri.com</cntemail>
			<hours>9:00 a.m.-5:00 p.m. Pacific time, Monday-Friday</hours>
		</cntinfo>
	</metc>
	<metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
	<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
	<mettc>local time</mettc>
</metainfo>
</metadata>
