<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
	<idinfo>
		<citation>
			<citeinfo>
				<origin>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</origin>
				<pubdate>1996</pubdate>
				<title>Mineral Resources, 1996</title>
				<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
				<serinfo>
					<sername>ArcAtlas</sername>
				</serinfo>
				<pubinfo>
					<pubplace>Redlands, Calif.</pubplace>
					<publish>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</publish>
				</pubinfo>
				<onlink>https://www1.columbia.edu/sec/acis/eds/dgate/studies/C1301/data/esri_1996_world_minerals.zip</onlink>
			</citeinfo>
		</citation>
		<descript>
			<langdata>eng</langdata>
			<abstract>Mineral Resources, 1996 is a  point theme representing mineral deposits worldwide.</abstract>
			<purpose>For educational, non-commercial purposes.  This dataset is appropriate for use in a GIS.</purpose>
<supplinf>Mineral resources are natural substances that are used to produce power and raw materials for economic needs. Mineral resources are irregularly distributed and nonrenewable (exhaustible). In other words, mineral resources can be restocked only through exploration and the development of new deposits. Deposits are subject to different natural, technological, and economic conditions of development and exploitation.

The definition of mineral resources is economic. It does not depend directly on the rock content of a useful substance.

Scientific and technological progress allows new deposits to be exploited that have a lower content of useful substances, higher content of impurities, or worse ore occurrence. New minerals begin to be mined as well. Hence, the array of mineral resources that are used by humans is constantly expanding.</supplinf>
		</descript>
		<timeperd>
			<timeinfo>
				<sngdate>
					<caldate>1996</caldate>
				</sngdate>
			</timeinfo>
			<current>publication date</current>
		</timeperd>
		<status>
			<progress>Complete</progress>
			<update>None planned</update>
		</status>
		<spdom>
			<bounding>
				<westbc>
-180</westbc>
					<eastbc>
180</eastbc>
						<northbc>
85</northbc>
							<southbc>
-85</southbc>
							</bounding>
						</spdom>
						<keywords>
							<theme>
								<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
								<themekey>geoscientificinformation</themekey>
							</theme>
							<theme>
								<themekt>None</themekt>
								<themekey>Mineral resources</themekey>
								<themekey>Deposits</themekey>
							</theme>
							<place>
								<placekt>GeoNames</placekt>
								<placekey>Earth (6295630)</placekey>
							</place>
							<place>
								<placekt>Library of Congress Subject Headings</placekt>
								<placekey>Earth</placekey>
							</place>
							<temporal>
								<tempkt>None</tempkt>
								<tempkey>1996</tempkey>
							</temporal>
						</keywords>
						<accconst>For current Columbia affiliates only.</accconst>

						<useconst>For educational, non-commercial use only.</useconst>
						<ptcontac>
							<cntinfo>
								<cntorgp>
									<cntorg>ESRI</cntorg>
									<cntper>Data Team</cntper>
								</cntorgp>
								<cntaddr>
									<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
									<address>380 New York Street</address>
									<city>Redlands</city>
									<state>California</state>
									<postal>92373-8100</postal>
									<country>USA</country>
								</cntaddr>
								<cntvoice>909-793-2853</cntvoice>
								<cntfax>909-793-5953</cntfax>
								<cntemail>info@esri.com</cntemail>
								<hours>7:00 a.m.-5:30 p.m. Pacific time, Monday-Friday</hours>
								<cntinst>n the United States- Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing and consulting services to your local ESRI Regional Office. For support, you may contact Technical Support by telephone (voice) between 6:00 a.m. and 5:00 p.m. Pacific time, Monday through Friday, by dialing 888-377-4575; facsimile (fax) available at 909-792-0960; electronic mail (e-mail) support@esri.com; or visit http://support.esri.com; ESRI holidays excluded. Outside the United States Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing, sales, support, and consulting services to your local ESRI International Distributor. This information can be found at http://gis.esri.com/intldist/contactint.cfm. For other questions or comments, you may contact ESRI headquarters by e-mail, telephone, or fax or write to us.</cntinst>
							</cntinfo>
						</ptcontac>
						<browse>
							<browsen>http://www.columbia.edu/acis/eds/gis/pix/cat/minerals.jpg</browsen>
							<browsed>Thumbnail</browsed>
							<browset>JPEG</browset>
						</browse>
						<native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.1850</native>
					</idinfo>
					<dataqual>
						<lineage>
							<procstep>
<procdesc>The maps of mineral resources were compiled by the specialists of the Russian Research Institute of Geology of Foreign Countries. They reflect the contemporary state of mineral resources of the continents. The database contains information about significant deposits and ores of various minerals, which form the basis of the industrial potential of various countries.

Minerals are classified into groups, such as ferrous, nonferrous, rare, precious and radioactive metals, nonmetalliferous minerals, precious and industrial stones, and fuels. Some kinds of minerals that are similar in genetic features, chemical composition, or use are combined (e.g., gas and gas condensate, quartz and quartzite, apatite and phosphorite, and common and rock salts). More than 90 minerals are listed.

All deposits are characterized by genetic type, major type or group of minerals, size, and type or types of minerals. Traditionally, genetic types are not given for oil and gas fields. The classification of genetic types of deposits is based on V. I. Smirnov's classification (1982).

Each deposit (ore area) is given a three-term number. The first two terms mark a trapezium formed by the meridians and parallels of a particular map sheet. The third term is an identification number for the deposit within the trapezium.

All presently known mineral deposits of significant size are accounted for. Deposits that have been discovered in recent years but have not been developed or proven are also shown. However, deposits that are exhausted or close to it and are no longer commercially significant have been omitted. Thus, the maps indicate the actual state of mineral resources of countries and continents. Deposits on different continents were classified in the same way. This makes it possible to compare the industrial potential of countries and continents.

The database and maps were compiled from original cartographic materials as well as from data published for many years in journals, reference books, and monographs.

Mineral Resources -- References

Gulid, P.W., ed. Preliminary Metallogenic Map of North America. 1981. USGS Circular 858.

Ilyin, K.B., et al, eds. Map of Mineral Resources of Russia and Adjacent Countries (in the
former USSR boundaries). 1992. Committee on Geology and Mineral Resources
Utilization, Government of Russian Federation. A.P. Karpinsky Russian Geological Research
Institute, State Geological Enterprise Rosgeolfond. VSEGEI. 4 s.

Kozlovsky, E.A., et al, eds. Gornaya ehntsiklopedia (Mining encyclopedia). 5 volumes.
1984-1991. Sovetskaya ehntsiklopedia, Moscow.

Mapa geologico do Brasil e da area oceanic adjacente incluindo depositos minerals,
1:2,500,000. 1981. DNPM, Brasilia.

Mapa metalogenico de America Central, 1:2,000,000. 1969. San Jose.

Mapa metalogenico de America del Sur, 1;5,000,000. 1983. UNESCO, Caracas.

Metallogenic Map of Europe, 1:2,500,000. 1968-1972. UNESCO Publications, Paris.
Mining Annual Review. 1979-1995

Nickel Availability -- Market Economy Countries. 1984. USBM Information Circular 8995.

Parkinson, G., ed. Atlas of Australian Resources. 3rd series, v.5: Geology and Minerals.
1988. Australian Surveying and Land Information Group, Department of Administrative
Services, Canberra. 60 pp.

Phosphorus and Potassium. 1983-1986.

Primary Lead and Zinc Availability -- Market Economy Countries. 1985. USBM Information
Circular 9036.

Tungsten Availability -- Market Economy Countries. 1985. USBM Information Circular
9025.

World Bauxite Resources. 1986. U.S. Geol. Surv. Prof. Paper, 1076-B.

Yarmolyuk, V.A., chief editor. Map of Mineral Resources of Africa and Arabia, 1:5,000,000.
1981. Ministry of Geology of the USSR, Zarubezhgeologia, All-Union Research Institute of
Geology of Foreign Countries. VSEGEI, Leningrad. 9 s.</procdesc>
								<srcused>See Description</srcused>
								<procdate>Unknown</procdate>
								<proccont>
									<cntinfo>
										<cntaddr>
										</cntaddr>
									</cntinfo>
								</proccont>
							</procstep>
							<procstep>
								<procdesc>Datasets for each continent were converted from ESRI coverage to the ESRI shapefile format using the 'copy features' tool and merged into one layer using the 'merge' tool.</procdesc>
								<procdate>20090507</procdate>
								<proccont>
									<cntinfo>
										<cntperp>
											<cntper>GIS/Map Librarian</cntper>
											<cntorg>Research Data Services (RDS), Columbia University Libraries</cntorg>
										</cntperp>
										<cntaddr>
											<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
											<address>420 W. 118th St. 215 IAB, MC 3301</address>
											<city>New York</city>
											<state>NY</state>
											<postal>10027</postal>
											<country>USA</country>
										</cntaddr>
										<cntvoice>(212) 854-6012</cntvoice>
										<cntemail>data@library.columbia.edu</cntemail>
									</cntinfo>
								</proccont>
							</procstep>
						</lineage>
					</dataqual>
					<spdoinfo>
						<direct>Vector</direct>
						<ptvctinf>
							<sdtsterm>
								<sdtstype>Entity point</sdtstype>
								<ptvctcnt>4391</ptvctcnt>
							</sdtsterm>
						</ptvctinf>
					</spdoinfo>
					<spref>
						<horizsys>
							<geograph>
								<latres>0.000000</latres>
								<longres>0.000000</longres>
								<geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
							</geograph>
							<geodetic>
								<horizdn>D_Clarke_1866</horizdn>
								<ellips>Clarke 1866</ellips>
								<semiaxis>6378206.400000</semiaxis>
								<denflat>294.978698</denflat>
							</geodetic>
						</horizsys>
					</spref>
					<eainfo>
						<detailed>
							<enttyp>
								<enttypl>
minerals</enttypl>
								</enttyp>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
									<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
									<attrdomv>
										<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
									</attrdomv>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
									<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
									<attrdomv>
										<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
									</attrdomv>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>AREA</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Area</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>PERIMETER</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Perimeter</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>EURESDD_</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Europe</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>EURESDD_ID</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Europe ID</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>NAME</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Name</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>DIAK_CDE</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Code for any diacritical marks in the resource site name</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>TYPE</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>The origin of the mineral resource</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>GROUP</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>The kind of mineral resource</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>CONTENTS</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>The abbreviation or name of the commodity</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>FIPS_CNTRY</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Country Code</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>SIZE</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>The size of the site relative to other sites with the same mineral</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>POLYGONID</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>ID Number</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>SCALE</attrlabl>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>ANGLE</attrlabl>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>NARESDD_</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>North America</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>NARESDD_ID</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>North America ID</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>SARESDD_</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>South America</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>SARESDD_ID</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>South America ID</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>ASRESDD_</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Asia</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>ASRESDD_ID</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Asia ID</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>AURESDD_</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Australia</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>AURESDD_ID</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Australia ID</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>AFRESDD_</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Africa</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>AFRESDD_ID</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Africa ID</attrdef>
								</attr>
							</detailed>
						</eainfo>
						<distinfo>
							<distrib>
								<cntinfo>
									<cntorgp>
										<cntorg>ESRI; ESRI International Distributors</cntorg>
									</cntorgp>
									<cntaddr>
										<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
										<address>380 New York Street</address>
										<city>Redlands</city>
										<state>California</state>
										<postal>92373-8100</postal>
										<country>USA</country>
									</cntaddr>
									<cntvoice>800-447-9778</cntvoice>
									<cntinst>In the United States, contact the ESRI Telebusiness staff at 800-447-9778 for more information about our software and data. Outside the United States, please direct all inquiries to your local ESRI International Distributor. This information can be found at http://gis.esri.com/intldist/contactint.cfm.</cntinst>
								</cntinfo>
							</distrib>
							<resdesc>esri_1996_world_minerals</resdesc>
							<stdorder>
								<digform>
									<digtinfo>
										<formname>GeoPackage</formname>
										<formspec>zip</formspec>

										<transize>TBD</transize>
									</digtinfo>
								</digform>
							</stdorder>
						</distinfo>
						<metainfo>
							<metd>20090624</metd>
							<metc>
								<cntinfo>
									<cntorgp>
										<cntorg>Research Data Services (RDS), Columbia University Libraries</cntorg>
										<cntper>GIS/Metadata Librarian</cntper>
									</cntorgp>
									<cntaddr>
										<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
										<address>420 W. 118th St. 215 IAB, MC 3301</address>
										<city>New York</city>
										<state>NY</state>
										<postal>10027</postal>
										<country>USA</country>
									</cntaddr>
									<cntvoice>(212) 854-6012</cntvoice>
									<cntemail>data@library.columbia.edu</cntemail>
									<hours>7:00 a.m.-5:30 p.m. Pacific time, Monday-Friday</hours>
								</cntinfo>
							</metc>
							<metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
							<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
							<mettc>local time</mettc>
						</metainfo>
					</metadata>
