<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><metadata>
<idinfo>
<citation>
<citeinfo>
<origin>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</origin>
<pubdate>1996</pubdate>
<title>World Present Landscapes, 1996</title>
<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
<serinfo>
<sername>ArcAtlas</sername>
</serinfo>
<pubinfo>
<pubplace>Redlands, Calif.</pubplace>
<publish>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</publish>
</pubinfo>
<onlink>https://www1.columbia.edu/sec/acis/eds/dgate/studies/C1301/data/esri_1996_world_landscapes.zip</onlink>
</citeinfo>
</citation>
<descript>
<abstract>Present Landscapes is a polygon theme representing a geographical summary of the current state of the earth's environment.

Human activity has transformed the appearance and use of the land in many regions around the world. The maps of present landscapes are a geographical summary of the current state of the earth's environment. They show several related topics. First, the locations of natural landscape structures, such as plains, mountains, and plateaus are shown. Second, these natural landscapes are classified by the extent of anthropogenic transformation. Third, the various geographical belts, the more detailed zones within them, and geographical sectors are shown. Geographical belts and zones generally vary with latitude. Geographical sectors are generally longitudinal and result from the influence of the oceans along the margins of a continent.

In this atlas, plain landscapes are divided into three subclasses based on the altitude of the plain: very low, low, and high. These subclasses also indicate the origin of a plain. Very low plains result from depositing of material. Low plains can result from either deposition or denudation of material (denudational plains). High plains typically result from the denudation of material.  Anthropogenic landscapes are classified according to the degree and type of transformation resulting from human activity. The major classes of anthropogenic landscapes are described below.

Quasi-Primary Quasi-Primary landscapes correspond to zonal landscapes. These areas have not been directly influenced by humans, or they have local casual influences that do not change the landscapes in kind. Quasi-Primary landscapes are found in the Arctic and sub-Arctic glacial and stone deserts, and some arid and extra-arid landscapes. Protected areas (national parks, etc.) are included in this classification as well. At the present time, all landscapes on the earth are affected by chemicals created by human technology because they move without regard to boundaries. Therefore, even landscapes that appear to be unchanged (primary) can be considered quasi-primary.

Natural-Anthropogenic Natural-Anthropogenic landscapes are those that have been transformed to varying degrees by economic activity. Natural-anthropogenic landscapes are subdivided into two groups (secondary-transformed and anthropogenic-modified) according to the changes to natural components, as follows:

Secondary-transformed landscapes are rather sustainable complexes that are similar to natural ones. They are able to develop by themselves and exist without human help. They result from the overuse of natural landscapes in the past by such activities as overgrazing, regular fires, and overcutting. Typically, these landscapes are more arid in the tropical and equatorial belts and more continental in the temperate belts than would be expected in primary landscapes. This group also includes present landscapes in which existing extensive land use can result in some reversible changes, if they cease being used. Anthropogenic-modified landscapes are highly changed natural complexes that are directly affected by economic activity. The most widespread of these landscapes are modified by agriculture (arable, plantation, and pasture landscapes) and forestry (which
occupy as much as 80 to 90 percent of certain world regions), as well as their combinations (forestry-arable and pasture arable landscapes).</abstract>
<purpose>For educational, non-commercial purposes.  This dataset is appropriate for use in a GIS.</purpose>
</descript>
<timeperd>
<timeinfo>
<sngdate>
<caldate>1996</caldate>
</sngdate>
</timeinfo>
<current>publication date</current>
</timeperd>
<status>
<progress>Complete</progress>
<update>None planned</update>
</status>
<spdom>
<bounding>
<westbc>
-180</westbc>
<eastbc>
180</eastbc>
<northbc>
85</northbc>
<southbc>
-85</southbc>
</bounding>
</spdom>
<keywords>
<theme>
<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
<themekey>society</themekey>
<themekey>geoscientificinformation</themekey>
<themekey>environment</themekey>
<themekey>farming</themekey>
</theme>
<theme>
<themekt>None</themekt>
<themekey>Present Landscapes</themekey>
</theme>
<place>
	<placekt>GeoNames</placekt>
	<placekey>Earth (6295630)</placekey>
</place>
<place>
<placekt>Library of Congress Subject Headings</placekt>
<placekey>Earth</placekey>
</place>
<temporal>
<tempkt>None</tempkt>
<tempkey>1996</tempkey>
</temporal>
</keywords>
<accconst>For current Columbia affiliates only.</accconst>

<useconst>For educational, non-commercial use only.</useconst>
<ptcontac>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>ESRI</cntorg>
<cntper>Data Team</cntper>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
<address>380 New York Street</address>
<city>Redlands</city>
<state>California</state>
<postal>92373-8100</postal>
<country>USA</country>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>909-793-2853</cntvoice>
<cntfax>909-793-5953</cntfax>
<cntemail>info@esri.com</cntemail>
<hours>7:00 a.m.-5:30 p.m. Pacific time, Monday-Friday</hours>
<cntinst>n the United States- Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing and consulting services to your local ESRI Regional Office. For support, you may contact Technical Support by telephone (voice) between 6:00 a.m. and 5:00 p.m. Pacific time, Monday through Friday, by dialing 888-377-4575; facsimile (fax) available at 909-792-0960; electronic mail (e-mail) support@esri.com; or visit http://support.esri.com; ESRI holidays excluded. Outside the United States Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing, sales, support, and consulting services to your local ESRI International Distributor. This information can be found at http://gis.esri.com/intldist/contactint.cfm. For other questions or comments, you may contact ESRI headquarters by e-mail, telephone, or fax or write to us.</cntinst>
</cntinfo>
</ptcontac>
<browse>
<browsen>http://www.columbia.edu/acis/eds/gis/pix/cat/landscape.jpg</browsen>
<browsed>Thumbnail</browsed>
<browset>JPEG</browset>
</browse>
<native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.1850</native>
</idinfo>
<dataqual>
<lineage>
<srcinfo>
<srccite>
<citeinfo>
<origin>United Nations Environment Programme</origin>
<pubdate>1992</pubdate>
<title>Atlas of desertification</title>
<geoform>atlas</geoform>
<pubinfo>
<pubplace>London</pubplace>
<publish>United Nations Environment Programme</publish>
</pubinfo>
</citeinfo>
</srccite>
<typesrc>paper</typesrc>
<srccitea>Atlas of desertification</srccitea>
</srcinfo>
<srcinfo>
<srccite>
<citeinfo>
<origin>National Geographic Society</origin>
<pubdate>1987</pubdate>
<title>Atlas of North America: Space Age Portrait of a Continent</title>
<geoform>atlas</geoform>
<pubinfo>
<pubplace>Washington, D. C.</pubplace>
<publish>National Geographic Society</publish>
</pubinfo>
</citeinfo>
</srccite>
<typesrc>paper</typesrc>
<srccitea>Atlas of North America: Space Age Portrait of a Continent</srccitea>
</srcinfo>
<srcinfo>
<srccite>
<citeinfo>
<origin>Comite europeen pour la sauvegarde de la nature et des ressources naturelles</origin>
<pubdate>1979</pubdate>
<title>Carta de la vegetation des Etats membres du Conseil a l'Europe.</title>
<geoform>map</geoform>
<pubinfo>
<pubplace>Strasbourg</pubplace>
</pubinfo>
</citeinfo>
</srccite>
<srcscale>30000000</srcscale>
<typesrc>paper</typesrc>
<srccitea>Carta de la vegetation des Etats membres du Conseil a l'Europe.</srccitea>
</srcinfo>
<srcinfo>
<srccite>
<citeinfo>
<pubdate>1988</pubdate>
<title>Geomorfologicheskaja karta Mira (dlja vysshykh uchebnykh zavedenij).</title>
<geoform>map</geoform>
<pubinfo>
<pubplace>Moscow</pubplace>
<publish>GUGK</publish>
</pubinfo>
</citeinfo>
</srccite>
<srcscale>15000000</srcscale>
<typesrc>paper</typesrc>
<srccitea>Geomorfologicheskaja karta Mira</srccitea>
</srcinfo>
<srcinfo>
<srccite>
<citeinfo>
<pubdate>1985</pubdate>
<title>Karta chetvertichnykh otlozhenij Evrazii</title>
<geoform>map</geoform>
<pubinfo>
<pubplace>Leningrad</pubplace>
<publish>VSEGEN</publish>
</pubinfo>
</citeinfo>
</srccite>
<srcscale>2500000</srcscale>
<typesrc>paper</typesrc>
<srccitea>Karta chetvertichnykh otlozhenij Evrazii</srccitea>
</srcinfo>
<srcinfo>
<srccite>
<citeinfo>
<pubdate>1986</pubdate>
<title>Pochvennaja karta Mira (dlja vysshykh uchebnykh zavedenij).</title>
<geoform>map</geoform>
<pubinfo>
<pubplace>Moscow</pubplace>
<publish>GUGK</publish>
</pubinfo>
</citeinfo>
</srccite>
<srcscale>15000000</srcscale>
<typesrc>paper</typesrc>
<srccitea>Pochvennaja karta Mira</srccitea>
</srcinfo>
<srcinfo>
<srccite>
<citeinfo>
<origin>FAO/UNESCO</origin>
<pubdate>197701981</pubdate>
<title>Soil Map of the World</title>
<pubinfo>
<pubplace>Paris</pubplace>
<publish>FAO/UNESCO.</publish>
</pubinfo>
</citeinfo>
</srccite>
<srcscale>5000000</srcscale>
<typesrc>paper</typesrc>
<srccitea>Soil Map of the World</srccitea>
</srcinfo>
<srcinfo>
<srccite>
<citeinfo>
<pubdate>1969-1976</pubdate>
<title>World atlas of agriculture under the aegis of the International association of agricultural economists</title>
<pubinfo>
<publish>Novara</publish>
</pubinfo>
</citeinfo>
</srccite>
<typesrc>paper</typesrc>
<srccitea>World atlas of agriculture under the aegis of the International association of agricultural economists</srccitea>
</srcinfo>
<procstep>
<procdesc>Inventory and synthesis of the contemporary scientific knowledge of the earth's terrestrial landscape structure and its various modifications by economic activity were conducted by the Department of Physical Geography and Geoecology of Moscow State University. The natural landscapes were mapped for the atlas according to a complex analysis of a world landscape map and component maps (soil, geomorphology, Quaternary deposits, vegetation, etc.), as well as interpretation of satellite images.

The impact, intensity, and character of anthropogenic changes to natural landscape subsystems were also determined by a complex analysis of the world maps of land use and soil transformation, in addition to numerous national cartographic, aerial, and space data. Because the availability of cartographic, aerial, and space data varies for different parts of the earth, the level of detail that could be compiled for the maps also varies. The landscape locations and characteristics shown in the atlas are highly generalized because of the global and continental map scale.

Zonal types of landscapes are classified by combinations of phytocoenoses and soils caused by climate. In some cases, characteristic of moisture regimes are used as well.

 Zones are characterized by soil-geographic, geobotanic, and hydrothermal unity. Belts are distinguished by macroclimatic parameters such as athmospheric circulation, thermal regimes in extratropical latitudes, and moisture regimes in tropical latitudes.

Ranges of altitudinal belts are classified by combinations of lower and upper beltswithin macroslopes of mountains.

Areas of zonal types of landscapes are classified into plains, low mountains, plateaus and tablelands. Areas of altitudinal types of landscapes are classified into middle mountains and high mountains.</procdesc>
<srcused>Atlas of desertification</srcused>
<srcused>Atlas of North America: Space Age Portrait of a Continent</srcused>
<srcused>Carta de la vegetation des Etats membres du Conseil a l'Europe.</srcused>
<srcused>Geograficheskie pojasa i zonal'nye tipy landshaftov Mira</srcused>
<srcused>Geomorfologicheskaja karta Mira</srcused>
<srcused>Karta chetvertichnykh otlozhenij Evrazii</srcused>
<srcused>Pochvennaja karta Mira</srcused>
<srcused>Soil Map of the World</srcused>
<srcused>World atlas of agriculture under the aegis of the International association of agricultural economists</srcused>
<srcused>Zemel'nye ugod'ja Mira</srcused>
<procdate>Unknown</procdate>
<proccont>
<cntinfo>
<cntaddr>
</cntaddr>
</cntinfo>
</proccont>
</procstep>
<procstep>
<procdesc>Datasets for each continent were converted from ESRI coverage to the ESRI shapefile format using the 'copy features' tool and merged into one layer using the 'merge' tool.</procdesc>
<procdate>20090507</procdate>
<proccont>
<cntinfo>
<cntperp>
<cntper>GIS/Map Librarian</cntper>
<cntorg>Research Data Services (RDS), Columbia University Libraries</cntorg>
</cntperp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
<address>420 W. 118th St. 215 IAB, MC 3301</address>
<city>New York</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postal>10027</postal>
<country>USA</country>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>(212) 854-6012</cntvoice>
<cntemail>data@library.columbia.edu</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</proccont>
</procstep>
</lineage>
</dataqual>
<spdoinfo>
<direct>Vector</direct>
<ptvctinf>
<sdtsterm>
<sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>
<ptvctcnt>6518</ptvctcnt>
</sdtsterm>
</ptvctinf>
</spdoinfo>
<spref>
<horizsys>
<geograph>
<latres>0.000000</latres>
<longres>0.000000</longres>
<geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
</geograph>
<geodetic>
<horizdn>D_Clarke_1866</horizdn>
<ellips>Clarke 1866</ellips>
<semiaxis>6378206.400000</semiaxis>
<denflat>294.978698</denflat>
</geodetic>
</horizsys>
</spref>
<eainfo>
<detailed>
<enttyp>
<enttypl>
landscape</enttypl>
</enttyp>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>AREA</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Area</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>PERIMETER</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Perimeter</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SALANDDD_</attrlabl>
<attrdef>South America</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SALANDDD_I</attrlabl>
<attrdef>South America ID</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>TYPE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Contains a code for the type of present landscape (see entity attributr overview description section)</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ANTHROP</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Contains a code for the specific anthropogenic landscape modification (see entity attributr overview description section)</attrdef>
<attrdomv>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ZONE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The natural landscape zone</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ANTH_IMP</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The general type of human activity transforming the landscape.</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>RELIEF</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Natural relief.</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>MOD_CLASS</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The class of an anthropogenic landscape modification</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>BELT</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The natural landscape belt</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>NALANDDD_</attrlabl>
<attrdef>North America</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>NALANDDD_I</attrlabl>
<attrdef>North America ID</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>EULANDDD_</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Europe</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>EULANDDD_I</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Europe ID</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>AULANDDD_</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Australia</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>AULANDDD_I</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Australia ID</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ASLANDDD_</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Asia</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ASLANDDD_I</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Asia ID</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>AFLANDDD_</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Africa</attrdef>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>AFLANDDD_I</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Africa ID</attrdef>
</attr>
</detailed>
<overview>
<eaover>Present landscape type codes
POLAR BELT
ZONE: POLAR DESERT
Zonal types of landscapes
1 Ice desert (continental ice cover and outlet glaciers)
2 Stony desert
Types of altitudinal landscape ranges
101 Polar desert
ZONE: ARCTIC TUNDRA
Zonal types of landscapes
3 Arctic tundra on gelic regosols
Types of altitudinal landscape ranges
101 Polar desert
SUBPOLAR BELTS
ZONE: TUNDRA
Zonal types of landscapes
4 Dwarf-shrub-forb-grass tundra on foli-humic leptosols
5 Meadow-moss, moss-lichen-dwarf-shrub, and dwarf-shrub tundra on foli-humic
leptosols, gelic and dystric gleysols
Types of altitudinal landscape ranges
102 Meadow tundra and open woodland -- tundra
103 Tundra -- polar desert
ZONE: FOREST-TUNDRA AND PRETUNDRA
Zonal types of landscapes
6 Meadow-dwarf-shrub, dark and light coniferous forest-tundra on haplic and leptic
podzols, and gleysols
Types of altitudinal landscape ranges
104 Open woodland -- shrub tundra
105 Shrub tundra -- golets desert
TEMPERATE BELT
ZONE: OPEN WOODLAND
Zonal types of landscapes
7 Small-leafed tall-grass-meadow open woodland on foli-humic leptosols, ochric
andosols, and humic podzols
Types of altitudinal landscape ranges
106 Meadow tundra and open woodland -- tundra
ZONE: TAIGA
Zonal types of landscapes
8 Dark and light coniferous moderately humid and humid taiga (northern) on haplic
and leptic podzols, and gleysols
9 Light and dark coniferous moderately humid taiga (middle) on podzols, dystric
podzoluvisols, and calci-gelic cambisols
10 Light coniferous taiga (middle) on gelic gleysols and calci-gelic cambisols
11 Light and dark coniferous moderately humid taiga (southern) on albic luvisols
12 Light coniferous taiga (southern) on albic luvisols
Types of altitudinal landscape ranges
107 Taiga -- meadow tundra
108 Taiga -- tundra
109 Taiga -- tundra -- golets desert
ZONE: FOREST
Mixed Forest
Zonal types of landscapes
13 Coniferous-broad-leafed and coniferous-small-leafed humid and moderately humid
mixed forest on albic luvisols, orthic greyzems, and dystric cambisols
Broad-leafed Forest
Zonal types of landscapes
14 Humid broad-leafed forest on eutric cambisols
15 Moderately humid broad-leafed forest on albic luvisols, orthic greyzems, and dystric
cambisols
16 Moderately humid open broad-leafed forest with conifers on solonetzi-umbric
gleysols
Types of altitudinal landscape ranges
110 Mixed forest -- coniferous forest
111 Mixed forest -- coniferous forest -- tundra
112 Mixed forest -- coniferous forest -- meadow
ZONE: FOREST-STEPPE
Zonal types of landscapes
17 Small-leafed, coniferous-small-leafed, and coniferous-deciduous forest-steppe on
Luvic chernozems and orthic greyzems
18 Broad-leafed forest-steppe (including prairie) on orthic greyzems, haplic
phaeozems, and chernozems
19 Small-leafed-coniferous forest-steppe on chernozems and haplic kastanozems
Types of altitudinal landscape ranges
113 Forest-steppe -- coniferous forest -- meadow tundra (or alpine meadow)
ZONE: STEPPE
Zonal types of landscapes
20 Forb-grass and grass steppe on calcic and deep calcic chernozems
21 Forb-turf and turf steppe on calcic chernozems and haplic kastanozems, including
solonetzi-mollic calcisols
22 Turf-grass-shrub steppe on luvic kastanozems, including solonetzi-mollic calcisols
and solonetz
23 Undershrub-grass steppe on kastanozems and haplic xerosols
Types of altitudinal landscape ranges
114 Steppe -- coniferous forest -- tundra
115 Steppe -- mixed (or coniferous) forest -- (alpine) meadow
ZONE: SEMIDESERT AND DESERT
Zonal types of landscapes
24 Grass-dwarf-shrub, dwarf-shrub, and undershrub semidesert and desert on haplic
xerosols and yermosols
ZONE: DESERT
Zonal types of landscapes
25 Dwarf-shrub and undershrub desert on yermosols and calcic xerosols
26 Virtually unvegetated desert
Types of altitudinal landscape ranges
116 Semidesert -- forest -- meadow
117 Semidesert -- steppe -- forest -- meadow
SUBTROPICAL BELT
ZONE: FOREST
Mixed Forest
Zonal types of landscapes
27 Excessively humid coniferous-broad-leafed forest (hemi- hylaea) on dystric
cambisols
28 Permanently humid coniferous-deciduous forest on chromic luvisols and nitosols
29 Seasonally humid coniferous-broad-leafed forest on chromic and eutric cambisols
30 Seasonally humid broad-leafed-coniferous forest on ferrallic cambisols and nitosols
Types of altitudinal landscape ranges
118 Evergreen mixed forest -- meadow
119 Mixed forest -- meadow
Semievergreen Deciduous Forest
Zonal types of landscapes
31 Humid semievergreen deciduous forest on ferrallic cambisols and nitosols
32 Humid open woodland (parkland) on haplic chernozems
Types of altitudinal landscape ranges
120 Mixed forest -- coniferous forest -- alpine meadow
121 Forest -- open woodland -- meadow
Coniferous Forest
Zonal types of landscapes
33 Moderately humid and moderately arid coniferous open woodland on chromic
cambisols
ZONE: EVERGREEN SCLEROPHYLLOUS (MEDITERRANEAN) FOREST,
OPEN WOODLAND, SHRUBLAND
Zonal types of landscapes
34 Summer-dry open woodland and shrubland on chromic cambisols
35 Summer-dry forest and shrubland on chromic cambisols and haplic nitosols
Types of altitudinal landscape ranges
122 Sclerophyllous forest -- mixed forest -- coniferous forest -- steppe (or meadow)
123 Sclerophyllous forest -- shrubland -- open woodland -- steppe -- meadow
ZONE: SEMIDESERT AND DESERT
Zonal types of landscapes
36 Shrub, dwarf-shrub, and undershrub semidesert and desert on calcic cambisols and
calcic xerosols
Types of altitudinal landscape ranges
124 Steppe -- mixed forest -- alpine meadow
125 Steppe (or semidesert) -- coniferous forest -- alpine meadow (or steppe)
ZONE: DESERT
Zonal types of landscapes
37 Succulent desert on chromic xerosols
38 Tree-dwarf-shrub desert on sand and chromic xerosols
39 Shrub and undershrub, including succulent and ephemeral, desert on chromic and
calcic xerosols and haplic yermosols
40 Grass-dwarf-shrub desert of cold high mountains on eutric leptosols
Types of altitudinal landscape ranges
126 Semidesert (or desert) -- shrubland -- open woodland -- steppe (or meadow)
127 Semidesert -- steppe -- semidesert
ZONE: OPEN WOODLAND AND SHRUBLAND
Zonal types of landscapes
41 Seasonally humid open woodland and shrubland on chromic cambisols and
chromic xerosols
Types of altitudinal landscape ranges
128 Sclerophyllous shrubland -- open woodland -- steppe (or meadow)
ZONE: STEPPE
Zonal types of landscapes
42 Shrub-grass and dwarf-shrub-grass steppe on chromic xerosols
43 Cold meadow steppe (of interior tablelands) on mollic cambisols
44 Meadow steppe on haplic and chromi-haplic phaeozems
Types of altitudinal landscape ranges
129 Steppe -- mixed forest -- alpine meadow
130 Steppe (or semidesert) -- coniferous forest -- alpine meadow (or steppe)
ZONE: PRAIRIE
Zonal types of landscapes
45 Seasonally humid prairie on chromic cambisols and chromi-haplic phaeozems
46 Permanently humid prairie on haplic phaeozems
Types of altitudinal landscape ranges
130 Steppe (or semidesert) -- coniferous forest -- alpine meadow (or steppe)
TROPICAL BELT
ZONE: DESERT
Zonal types of landscapes
47 Virtually unvegetated desert
48 Ephemeral-bulbaceous-succulent desert with high relative humidity on eutric
leptosols
49 Grass and dwarf-shrub-grass desert on calcic leptosols and calcic xerosols
50 Shrub and dwarf-shrub desert on eutric leptosols and sand (including cold high
tablelands)
51 Dwarf-shrub and shrub desert on chromic xerosols
52 Dwarf-shrub and shrub desert on calcic cambisols
ZONE: SEMIDESERT
Zonal types of landscapes
53 Grass-shrub succulent semidesert with high relative humidity on chromic xerosols
54 Grass-shrub semidesert on chromic xerosols
55 Grass-shrub semidesert of cold high tablelands on eutric leptosols
Types of altitudinal landscape ranges
131 Desert -- (loma) -- desert
132 Desert (or semidesert) -- open woodland -- semidesert
ZONE: STEPPE
Zonal types of landscapes
56 Shrub steppe of cold high plateaus on mollic cambisols
Types of altitudinal landscape ranges
133 Steppe -- montane xerophytes -- meadow
ZONE: OPEN WOODLAND, SHRUBLAND, SAVANNA
Zonal types of landscapes
57 Semidesert savanna and open woodland on chromic xerosols
58 xerophytic open woodland and shrubland on haplic nitosols and calci-chromic
cambisols
59 Evergreen open woodland and shrubland on rhodic and haplic nitosols
Types of altitudinal landscape ranges
134 Open woodland -- steppe (or montane xerophytes)
135 Open woodland -- forest -- steppe (or meadow)
ZONE: EVERGREEN AND SEMIEVERGREEN FOREST
Zonal types of landscapes
60 Seasonally and permanently humid forest on acric ferralsols and rhodic nitosols
Types of altitudinal landscape ranges
136 Semievergreen forest -- coniferous forest -- meadow
137 Evergreen forest -- mixed forest -- coniferous forest -- (alpine) meadow
138 Evergreen forest -- semievergreen forest -- meadow
SUBEQUATORIAL BELT
ZONE: FOREST
Evergreen Forest
Zonal types of landscapes
61 Humid and seasonally humid evergreen forest on acric ferralsols
62 Semidry evergreen forest and shrubland on rhodic nitosols and chromic xerosols
Types of altitudinal landscape ranges
139 Evergreen forest -- meadow (or paramo)
Semievergreen Forest
Zonal types of landscapes
63 Humid and seasonally humid semievergreen forest on acric ferralsols and rhodic
nitosols
Types of altitudinal landscape ranges
140 Deciduous forest -- evergreen forest -- meadow
Deciduous Forest
Zonal types of landscapes
64 Seasonally humid and dry deciduous forest on rhodic and haplic nitosols and Pellic
Vertisols
Types of altitudinal landscape ranges
140 Deciduous forest -- evergreen forest -- meadow
ZONE: SAVANNA AND OPEN WOODLAND
Zonal types of landscapes
65 Humid evergreen open woodland and tall-grass savanna on rhodic and haplic
nitosols
66 Seasonally humid open woodland and low-tree savanna on rhodic and haplic
nitosols and chromic xerosols
67 Semidry savanna, open woodland, and shrubland on chromic xerosols
Types of altitudinal landscape ranges
141 Savanna -- forest -- paramo (or meadow)
EQUATORIAL BELT
ZONE: EVERGREEN FOREST
Rain Forest (Hylaea)
Zonal types of landscapes
68 Excessively humid evergreen rain forest on xantic and gleyic ferralsols
69 Humid rain forest on acric ferralsols
Evergreen - Deciduous Forest
Zonal types of landscapes
70 Seasonally humid evergreen-deciduous forest on acric ferralsols
Types of altitudinal landscape ranges
142 Hylaea -- paramo
INTRAZONAL LANDSCAPES
River Valleys
71 River valley
Hydromorphic Landscapes
Coastal
72 Temperate marshes
73 Tropical, subequatorial, and equatorial mangroves
74 River delta
Plain
75 Temperate wetland
76 Tropical, subequatorial, and equatorial wetland
Other Intrazonal Landscapes
77 Halophytic landscapes
78 Glaciers
MISCELLANEOUS LANDSCAPES
94 No data (appears on volcanic islands in Oceania)
999 Lakes
Landscape modification codes
Anthropogenic Modified Landscapes (100-series codes)
101 Arable irrigated highly fertilized
102 Arable irrigated little fertilized
103 Arable non-irrigated highly fertilized
104 Arable non-irrigated little fertilized
105 Horticultural reclaimed
106 Meadow and arable intensively reclaimed
107 Improved pasture
108 Degrading pasture
109 Pasture and arable reclaimed
110 Pasture and arable unreclaimed
111 Forest and pasture and arable highly reclaimed
112 Forest and arable
113 Forest and pasture
114 Forest and horticultural
115 Forestry reclaimed
116 Degrading forestry
117 Local (including oasis) agricultural
118 Recreational
Secondary-Transformed Landscapes (200-series codes)
The type of transformation is indicated by the third digit and the anthropogenic impact is
indicated by the third digit. For example, 236 is forest-steppe impacted by grazing and
forestry activities.
Type of transformation--indicated by second digit
210 Tundra
220 Forest
230 Forest-steppe
240 Steppe
250 Savanna and open woodland
260 Desert
270 Meadow
Anthropogenic impact--indicated by third digit
201 Cultivation
202 Grazing
203 Forestry
204 Grazing and cultivation
205 Cultivation and forestry
206 Grazing and forestry
Quasi-Primary Landscapes
300 Quasi-primary landscapes
Other codes
0 no modification code (for lakes, not applicable; for volcanic islands in Australia and
Oceania; no data)</eaover>
</overview>
</eainfo>
<distinfo>
<distrib>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>ESRI; ESRI International Distributors</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
<address>380 New York Street</address>
<city>Redlands</city>
<state>California</state>
<postal>92373-8100</postal>
<country>USA</country>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>800-447-9778</cntvoice>
<cntinst>In the United States, contact the ESRI Telebusiness staff at 800-447-9778 for more information about our software and data. Outside the United States, please direct all inquiries to your local ESRI International Distributor. This information can be found at http://gis.esri.com/intldist/contactint.cfm.</cntinst>
</cntinfo>
</distrib>
<resdesc>esri_1996_world_landscapes</resdesc>
<stdorder>
<digform>
<digtinfo>
<formname>geopackage</formname>
<formspec>zip</formspec>

</digtinfo>
</digform>
</stdorder>
</distinfo>
<metainfo>
<metd>20090619</metd>
<metc>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>Research Data Services (RDS), Columbia University Libraries</cntorg>
<cntper>GIS/Metadata Librarian</cntper>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
<address>420 W. 118th St. 215 IAB, MC 3301</address>
<city>New York</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postal>10027</postal>
<country>USA</country>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>(212) 854-6012</cntvoice>
<cntemail>data@library.columbia.edu</cntemail>
<hours>7:00 a.m.-5:30 p.m. Pacific time, Monday-Friday</hours>
</cntinfo>
</metc>
<metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
<mettc>local time</mettc>
</metainfo>
</metadata>
