<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
	<idinfo>
		<citation>
			<citeinfo>
				<origin>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</origin>
				<pubdate>1996</pubdate>
				<title>Morphosculpture (line), 1996</title>
				<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
				<serinfo>
					<sername>ArcAtlas</sername>
				</serinfo>
				<pubinfo>
					<pubplace>Redlands, Calif.</pubplace>
					<publish>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</publish>
				</pubinfo>
				<onlink>https://www1.columbia.edu/sec/acis/eds/dgate/studies/C1301/data/esri_1996_world_morphosculpture.zip</onlink>
			</citeinfo>
		</citation>
		<descript>
			<langdata>eng</langdata>
			<abstract>Morphosculpture (line), 1996 is a polyline theme representing Morphosculpture worldwide.  Attribute information indicates whether these linear features are Lateritic crust or Landforms of end moraine</abstract>
			<purpose>For educational, non-commercial purposes.  This dataset is appropriate for use in a GIS.</purpose>
<supplinf>Morphosculpture is the detailed shaping of the earth's landforms. Processes such as erosion and sedimentation are primarily responsible for morphosculpture. Landforms are classified and mapped by present-day natural and climatic zones. The climatic zones vary with latitude and altitude, paleogeographic features (relict elements or landforms), and trends of exogenic processes (accumulation or destruction). The underlying morphostructure also influences the resulting morphosculpture.

The most important factors that sculpt the earth's landforms are running water (fluvial morphosculpture), ice (glacial and cryogenic morphosculpture), and wind (eolian and arid morphosculpture). Other important factors are easily soluble bedrock (karst) and gravity (talus).

Fluvial morphosculpture is landforms shaped by accumulation and erosion of material caused by the action of water. Accumulation landforms are connected with areas of absolute or relative subsidence of the earth's crust, such as low plains. Erosion landforms, including young ones, pertain to uplifted areas such as highlands and mountains.

Glacial and cryogenic morphosculpture is the result of both ancient glaciations and contemporary glacial and cryogenic phenomena. Special cryogenic morphosculpture is formed within present permafrost areas, both on mainland and island areas. It includes mound, polygonal, solifluction, icing, and nivation landforms.

Arid morphosculpture is a set of ancient and present-day erosion and eolian landforms. Eolian accumulation and deflation forms of different ages are dominant. They are particularly pronounced in sand extratropical and tropical deserts, where the formation of eolian relief such as dunes has prevailed for a long time.

Other morphosculptures include karst, polygenetic landforms of exogenic relief, which are developed in some areas and not directly connected with present-day and ancient geographical zones (Baer's mounds), and gravitation forms (talus).</supplinf>
		</descript>
		<timeperd>
			<timeinfo>
				<sngdate>
					<caldate>1996</caldate>
				</sngdate>
			</timeinfo>
			<current>publication date</current>
		</timeperd>
		<status>
			<progress>Complete</progress>
			<update>None planned</update>
		</status>
		<spdom>
			<bounding>
				<westbc>
-180</westbc>
					<eastbc>
180</eastbc>
						<northbc>
85</northbc>
							<southbc>
-85</southbc>
							</bounding>
						</spdom>
						<keywords>
							<theme>
								<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
								<themekey>Geology</themekey>
							</theme>
							<theme>
								<themekt>None</themekt>
								<themekey>Morphosculpture</themekey>
							</theme>
							<place>
								<placekt>GeoNames</placekt>
								<placekey>Earth</placekey>
							</place>
							<temporal>
								<tempkt>None</tempkt>
								<tempkey>1996</tempkey>
							</temporal>
						</keywords>
						<accconst>For current Columbia affiliates only.</accconst>

						<useconst>For educational, non-commercial use only.</useconst>
						<ptcontac>
							<cntinfo>
								<cntorgp>
									<cntorg>ESRI</cntorg>
									<cntper>Data Team</cntper>
								</cntorgp>
								<cntaddr>
									<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
									<address>380 New York Street</address>
									<city>Redlands</city>
									<state>California</state>
									<postal>92373-8100</postal>
									<country>USA</country>
								</cntaddr>
								<cntvoice>909-793-2853</cntvoice>
								<cntfax>909-793-5953</cntfax>
								<cntemail>info@esri.com</cntemail>
								<hours>7:00 a.m.-5:30 p.m. Pacific time, Monday-Friday</hours>
								<cntinst>n the United States- Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing and consulting services to your local ESRI Regional Office. For support, you may contact Technical Support by telephone (voice) between 6:00 a.m. and 5:00 p.m. Pacific time, Monday through Friday, by dialing 888-377-4575; facsimile (fax) available at 909-792-0960; electronic mail (e-mail) support@esri.com; or visit http://support.esri.com; ESRI holidays excluded. Outside the United States Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing, sales, support, and consulting services to your local ESRI International Distributor. This information can be found at http://gis.esri.com/intldist/contactint.cfm. For other questions or comments, you may contact ESRI headquarters by e-mail, telephone, or fax or write to us.</cntinst>
							</cntinfo>
						</ptcontac>
					</idinfo>
					<dataqual>
						<lineage>
							<procstep>
<procdesc>Morphosculpture was mapped using the morphostructure map as a base to provide a "control" for the position and type of geomorphological features. These features are grouped into different types of morphosculpture, while superimosed landforms are presented in elements. Local landforms are separated into additional point and line coverages.

Morphosculpture -- References

Bigarella, J. J., and H. F. Garner. Predvaritel'naja paleogeomorfologicheskaja karta
Juzhnoj Ameriki. (Preliminary paleogeomorphological map of South America.) In:
Paleogeografija i perigljatsial'nye javlenija plejstotsena. (Paleogeography and periglacial
phenomena of the Pleistocene.) Moscow. 1975. pp. 200-207.

Serebryanny, L. R., ed. Geomorfologicheskoe kartovedenie SSSR i chastej sveta. Nauka,
Moscow. 1973. 248 pp.

Embleton, C., ed. Geomorphology of Europe. Macmillan, London. 1984. 464 pp.

Etchevehere, P.H. Bosquejo de regiones geomorfologicas y de drenaje de la Republica
Argentina. Instituto de suelos y agrotecnia, Buenos Aires. Publication No. 75. 1961. pp. 7-
26.

Flint, R. F., and F. Fidalgo. Glacial geology of the east flank of the Argentine Andes
between latitude 39 deg.10 min. and latitude 41 deg. 20 min. S. The Geological Society
of America. Bulletin. 1964. 75, 4. pp. 335-352.

Flint, R. F., and F. Fidalgo. Glacial drift in the Eastern Argentine Andes between latitude
41 deg.10 min. and latitude 43 deg. 10 min. S. The Geological Society of America.
Bulletin. 1969. 80, 6. pp. 1043-1052.

Klammer, G. Die Palaowuste des Pantanal von Mato Grosso und die pleistozane
Klimageschichte der brasilianischen Randtropen. Zeitschrift fur Geomorphologie. N. F.
1982. 26, 4. pp. 393-416.

Liedtke, H. Die nordischen Vereisungen in Mitteleuropa. 2 Auflage Forschungen zur
deutschen Landeskunde, Bd. 204, Trier. 1981. 307 pp.

Polanski, J. The maximum glaciation in the Argentine Cordillera. The Geological Society
of America. Special Paper. 1965. 85. pp. 453-472.

Serebryanny, L. R. Islandija: strana -- ljudi -- khozjajstvo. (Iceland: country -- people --
economy.) Mysl', Moscow. 1969. 248 pp. (Geomorphological map).

Tricart, J. Existencia de medanos cuaternarios en los llanos del Orinoco (Colombia y
Venezuela). Colombia geografica -- Revista del Instituto Geografico Agustin Codazzi.
1977. 4, 5, 1. pp. 69-79.</procdesc>
								<srcused>See process description</srcused>
								<procdate>Unknown</procdate>
								<proccont>
									<cntinfo>
										<cntaddr>
										</cntaddr>
									</cntinfo>
								</proccont>
							</procstep>
							<procstep>
								<procdesc>Datasets for each continent were converted from ESRI coverage to the ESRI shapefile format using the 'copy features' tool and merged into one layer using the 'merge' tool.</procdesc>
								<procdate>20090507</procdate>
								<proccont>
									<cntinfo>
										<cntperp>
											<cntper>GIS/Map Librarian</cntper>
											<cntorg>Research Data Services (RDS), Columbia University Libraries</cntorg>
										</cntperp>
										<cntaddr>
											<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
											<address>420 W. 118th St. 215 IAB, MC 3301</address>
											<city>New York</city>
											<state>NY</state>
											<postal>10027</postal>
											<country>USA</country>
										</cntaddr>
										<cntvoice>(212) 854-6012</cntvoice>
										<cntemail>data@library.columbia.edu</cntemail>
									</cntinfo>
								</proccont>
							</procstep>
						</lineage>
					</dataqual>
					<spdoinfo>
						<direct>Vector</direct>
						<ptvctinf>
							<sdtsterm>
								<sdtstype>String</sdtstype>
								<ptvctcnt>62</ptvctcnt>
							</sdtsterm>
						</ptvctinf>
					</spdoinfo>
					<spref>
						<horizsys>
							<geograph>
								<latres>0.000000</latres>
								<longres>0.000000</longres>
								<geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
							</geograph>
							<geodetic>
								<horizdn>D_Clarke_1866</horizdn>
								<ellips>Clarke 1866</ellips>
								<semiaxis>6378206.400000</semiaxis>
								<denflat>294.978698</denflat>
							</geodetic>
						</horizsys>
					</spref>
					<eainfo>
						<detailed>
							<enttyp>
								<enttypl>
m_sculpt_elemdd_ln</enttypl>
								</enttyp>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
									<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
									<attrdomv>
										<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
									</attrdomv>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
									<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
									<attrdomv>
										<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
									</attrdomv>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>FNODE_</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Frome node</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>TNODE_</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>To node</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>LPOLY_</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Left polygon</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>RPOLY_</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Right polygon</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>LENGTH</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Length</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>EUELEMDD_</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Europe</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>EUELEMDD_I</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Europe</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>ELEM_A</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Local superimposed landforms</attrdef>
									<attrdomv>
										<edom>
											<edomv>52</edomv>
											<edomvd>Lateritic crust</edomvd>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>53</edomv>
											<edomvd>Landforms of end moraine</edomvd>
										</edom>
									</attrdomv>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>AFELEMDD_</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Africa</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>AFELEMDD_I</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Africa</attrdef>
								</attr>
							</detailed>
							<overview>
<eaover>Group 1. Inherited and present-day morphosculpture

Subgroup 1. Fluvial morphosculpture
Types:
1 Fluviomarine plains and deltas
2 Alluvial and lacustrine-alluvial plains
3 Alluvial plains
4 Lacustrine alluvial plains
5 Lacustrine plains
6 Alluvial-proluvial and proluvial plains
7 Plains of problematic genesis (glacial or marine)

Subgroup 2. Denudation and erosion morphosculpture
Types:
8 Deeply dissected (h &gt; 100 m) plains and plateaus
37 Deeply dissected (h &gt; 100 m) plains and plateaus with prevailing step-like and
table landforms
9 Moderately dissected (h = 30 to 100 m) plains and plateaus; in South America,
the features formed like "half oranges"
10 Slightly dissected (h &gt; 30 m) plains and plateaus
11 Deeply dissected (h &gt; 500 m) mountains
12 Moderately dissected (h &lt; 500 m) mountains

Subgroup 3. Glacial and cryogenic morphosculpture
Types:
102 Exaration and deposition relief of present-day glacial regions (ice sheets, glaciers)

Subgroup 5. Morphostructure of different genesis
Types:
13 Karst relief
14 Salt plains ("salari")
110 Coral islands

Group 2. Relict morphologic structure differently transformed by recent
processes

Subgroup 3. Glacial and cryogenic morphosculpture
Types:
15 Knob-and-kettle moraine relief (recent glacial deposition landforms)
16 Upland knob-and-kettle moraine relief (recent glacial deposition landforms)
17 Glacial deposition relief transformed by erosion and cryogenic processes
18 Upland glacial deposition relief transformed by erosion and cryogenic processes
19 Glaciolacustrine relief
20 Fluvioglacial relief (prevailing outwash plains)
21 Moraine plans with ridges and depressions
22 Moraine plains with ridges and hills
23 Large residual hills formed by exaration
24 Small hills formed by exaration and denudation at thick moraine cover
25 Smoothed exaration-denudation relief at thick moraine cover
26 Structural denudation relief eroded by exaration at thin moraine cove
27 Structural denudation relief eroded by exaration at prevailing glaciolacustrine
deposits
28 Plains and tablelands with exaration landforms
29 Exaration and deposition relief formed by mountain glaciation and transformed by
frost, nivation, and gravitation
30 Exaration and deposition relief formed by mountain glaciation and transformed by
frost, nivation, and gravitation at thick moraine cover
31 Relief of various exaration landforms
32 Glacial deposition and fluvial relief of piedmont plains
Subgroup 1. Fluvial morphosculpture
33 Marine and abrasion plains and terraces
34 Alluvial plains
35 Alluvial and lacustrine-alluvial plains

Subgroup 4. Arid (eolian) morphosculpture
36 Dunes

No data code
110 No data for coral islands</eaover>
							</overview>
						</eainfo>
						<distinfo>
							<distrib>
								<cntinfo>
									<cntorgp>
										<cntorg>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</cntorg>
									</cntorgp>
									<cntaddr>
										<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
										<address>380 New York Street</address>
										<city>Redlands</city>
										<state>California</state>
										<postal>92373-8100</postal>
										<country>USA</country>
									</cntaddr>
									<cntvoice>800-447-9778</cntvoice>
									<cntinst>In the United States, contact the ESRI Telebusiness staff at 800-447-9778 for more information about our software and data. Outside the United States, please direct all inquiries to your local ESRI International Distributor. This information can be found at http://gis.esri.com/intldist/contactint.cfm.</cntinst>
								</cntinfo>
							</distrib>
							<resdesc>esri_1996_world_morphosculpture</resdesc>
							<stdorder>
								<digform>
									<digtinfo>
										<formname>GeoPackage</formname>
										<formspec>zip</formspec>

										<transize>0.020 MB</transize>
									</digtinfo>
								</digform>
							</stdorder>
						</distinfo>
						<metainfo>
							<metd>20090701</metd>
							<metc>
								<cntinfo>
									<cntorgp>
										<cntorg>Research Data Services (RDS), Columbia University Libraries</cntorg>
										<cntper>GIS/Metadata Librarian</cntper>
									</cntorgp>
									<cntaddr>
										<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
										<address>420 W. 118th St. 215 IAB, MC 3301</address>
										<city>New York</city>
										<state>NY</state>
										<postal>10027</postal>
										<country>USA</country>
									</cntaddr>
									<cntvoice>(212) 854-6012</cntvoice>
									<cntemail>data@library.columbia.edu</cntemail>
									<hours>7:00 a.m.-5:30 p.m. Pacific time, Monday-Friday</hours>
								</cntinfo>
							</metc>
							<metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
							<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
							<mettc>local time</mettc>
						</metainfo>
					</metadata>
