<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
	<idinfo>
		<citation>
			<citeinfo>
				<origin>Geological Survey (U.S.)</origin>
				<origin>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</origin>
				<pubdate>2008</pubdate>
				<title>United States Historic Earthquakes, 2008</title>
				<edition>2008</edition>
				<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
				<serinfo>
					<sername>ESRI Data &amp; Maps</sername>
					<issue>2008 World, Europe, United States, Canada, and Mexico</issue>
				</serinfo>
				<pubinfo>
					<pubplace>Redlands, California, USA</pubplace>
					<publish>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</publish>
				</pubinfo>
				<onlink>https://www1.columbia.edu/sec/acis/eds/dgate/studies/C1301/data/esri_2008_usa_quakehis.zip</onlink>
			</citeinfo>
		</citation>
		<descript>
<abstract>United States Historic Earthquakes is a point theme representing the locations of significant, historic earthquakes in United States and adjacent Canada and Mexico that caused deaths, property damage, and geological effects, or were otherwise experienced by the resident populations.  Attribute information includes  the depth, maximum magnitude, Modified Mercalli Intensity, location, date and time of the earthquakes. 

This dataset is a part of the 2008 ESRI Data &amp; Maps collection.</abstract>
			<purpose>United States Historic Earthquakes provides the locations of significant, historic earthquakes for geographic display and analysis at regional and national levels. This data set is intended for a mixed audience of specialists and non-specialists alike who have a need for general, non-technical information about significant U.S. earthquakes.</purpose>
			<supplinf>Largest scale when displaying the data: 1:1,000,000.</supplinf>
		</descript>
		<timeperd>
			<timeinfo>
				<rngdates>
					<begdate>1568</begdate>
					<enddate>20040127</enddate>
				</rngdates>
			</timeinfo>
			<current>ground condition</current>
		</timeperd>
		<status>
			<progress>Complete</progress>
			<update>Annually</update>
		</status>
		<spdom>
			<bounding>
				<westbc>
-179.992676</westbc>
					<eastbc>
180.000000</eastbc>
						<northbc>
68.688660</northbc>
							<southbc>
17.250000</southbc>
							</bounding>
						</spdom>
						<keywords>
							<theme>
								<themekt>None</themekt>
								<themekey>point</themekey>
								<themekey>earthquakes</themekey>
								<themekey>historic earthquakes</themekey>
								<themekey>depths</themekey>
								<themekey>magnitudes</themekey>
								<themekey>geological effects</themekey>
							</theme>
							<theme>
								<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
								<themekey>geoscientificInformation</themekey>
							</theme>
							<place>
								<placekt>GeoNames</placekt>
								<placekey>United States (6252001)</placekey>
							</place>
							<place>
								<placekt>Library of Congress Subject Headings</placekt>
								<placekey>United States</placekey>
							</place>
							<temporal>
								<tempkt>None</tempkt>
								<tempkey>1568-2004</tempkey>
							</temporal>
						</keywords>
						<accconst>For current Columbia affiliates only.</accconst>

						<useconst>For educational, non-commercial use only.</useconst>
						<ptcontac>
							<cntinfo>
								<cntorgp>
									<cntorg>ESRI</cntorg>
									<cntper>Data Team</cntper>
								</cntorgp>
								<cntaddr>
									<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
									<address>380 New York Street</address>
									<city>Redlands</city>
									<state>California</state>
									<postal>92373-8100</postal>
									<country>USA</country>
								</cntaddr>
								<cntvoice>909-793-2853</cntvoice>
								<cntfax>909-793-5953</cntfax>
								<cntemail>info@esri.com</cntemail>
								<hours>7:00 a.m.-5:30 p.m. Pacific time, Monday-Friday</hours>
<cntinst>In the United States:
Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing and consulting services to your local ESRI Regional Office.  For support, you may contact ESRI Support Center by telephone (voice) between 6:00 a.m. and 5:00 p.m. Pacific time, Monday through Friday, by dialing 888-377-4575; facsimile (fax) available at 909-792-0960; electronic mail (e-mail) support@esri.com; or visit http://support.esri.com/; ESRI holidays excluded. 

Outside the United States
Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing, sales, support, and consulting services to your local ESRI International Distributor.  This information can be found at http://gis.esri.com/intldist/contact/.  

For other questions or comments, you may contact ESRI headquarters by e-mail, telephone, or fax or write to us.</cntinst>
							</cntinfo>
						</ptcontac>
						<browse>
							<browsen>http://www.columbia.edu/acis/eds/gis/pix/cat/esri_93_usa_quakehis.jpg</browsen>
							<browsed>Thumbnail</browsed>
							<browset>JPEG</browset>
						</browse>
						<native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 1; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.1.0.722</native>
					</idinfo>
					<dataqual>
						<attracc>
							<attraccr>The attribute table was scanned for unreasonable attribute values of depth and magnitude.</attraccr>
						</attracc>
<logic>No formal tests for logical consistency were performed on this data set, principally because the data set contains attribute values that were arrived at by either or both quantitative (i.e. instrumental) and qualitative (i.e. historical) methods.  Earthquakes that occurred prior to the introduction of seismological instrumentation are known only from written records, such as newspapers, books and journals, and diaries, which often may provide contradictory information that has to be carefully examined and weighed.  As seismographs became more common in the early 1960's, the origin time and location were both more precisely and accurately determined but the compilation and evaluation of intensity reports was, and still is, a process that involves considerable subjectivity.  As a result, all attributes associated with a given earthquake should be considered provisional and subject to further revision based on acquisition of new information and use of new analytical methods.

The shapefile is converted to SDC (Smart Data Compression) format using either ESRI SDC Data Development Kit Professional 2 (DDKP2) or tools in ArcGIS.  The SDC data set is then loaded into ArcSDE to verify and validate the geometry.</logic>
<complete>This data set contains information on significant, historical earthquakes that caused deaths, property damage, geological effects, or that were experienced by populations in the epicentral area, for the United States, Puerto Rico, and the U.S. Virgin Islands, and adjacent Canada and Mexico.  These data are limited to the best estimates of earthquake locations and to attributes such as magnitude and maximum intensity.

After processing, the data set is checked for drawing display and number of records and file sizes compared with source materials.</complete>
						<posacc>
							<horizpa>
								<horizpar>100 meters is the nominal precision of the reported instrumentally located coordinate values but accuracy is considerably less.  Accuracy depends upon numerous factors including imprecision of the velocity model of the earth, uneven distribution of seismic stations, and imprecisions in the computational algorithm.  Following initial proofreading of the input data file, a preliminary map of the locations of the earthquakes was produced which was examined for gross errors in spatial location.</horizpar>
							</horizpa>
							<vertacc>
								<vertaccr>Although depths are reported to the nearest one kilometer, the accuracy for recent earthquakes is considerably less owing to uncertainties in the velocity model of the earth, uneven distribution of seismic stations, and imprecisions in the computational algorithm.</vertaccr>
							</vertacc>
						</posacc>
						<lineage>
							<srcinfo>
								<srccite>
									<citeinfo>
										<origin>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</origin>
										<pubdate>200501</pubdate>
										<title>Significant United States Earthquakes, 1568-2004</title>
										<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
										<pubinfo>
											<pubplace>Reston, Virginia, USA</pubplace>
											<publish>United States Geological Survey</publish>
										</pubinfo>
										<othercit>Downloaded the data set in November 2005.</othercit>
										<onlink>http://nationalatlas.gov/atlasftp.html</onlink>
									</citeinfo>
								</srccite>
								<srcscale>2000000</srcscale>
								<typesrc>online</typesrc>
								<srctime>
									<timeinfo>
										<rngdates>
											<begdate>1568</begdate>
											<enddate>20040127</enddate>
										</rngdates>
									</timeinfo>
									<srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
								</srctime>
								<srccitea>National Atlas</srccitea>
								<srccontr>Attribute and geospatial data</srccontr>
							</srcinfo>
							<procstep>
								<procdesc>Data for the years 1568 to 1989, from the Seismicity of the United States, 1568-1989 (Revised) (1993), were combined with the Preliminary Determination of Epicenters (2004) data for 1990 to 2004.  The Earthquake History of the United States (1982) and the Project catalogue and seismic hazard maps, Seismic hazard in Latin America and the Caribbean (1997) were used to compile information for additional locations or for years not covered by the other sources.  The resulting text file was loaded into ArcView and converted to a shapefile.  Three records for Puerto Rico were dropped because they did not include values for longitude and latitude.</procdesc>
								<procdate>200411</procdate>
								<srcprod>National Atlas</srcprod>
							</procstep>
							<procstep>
								<procdesc>The following steps were performed by ESRI: Downloaded the compressed file from the National Atlas of the United States and uncompressed the shapefile (quksigx020.shp).  Removed attributes STATE, DEATHS, and DAMAGE.  Renamed and rearranged the remaining attributes.  Removed features near Guam.  Converted the data set to SDC.  Created ArcGIS layer file (.lyr), projection file (.prj), and spatial indices.</procdesc>
								<srcused>National Atlas</srcused>
								<procdate>20060418</procdate>
							</procstep>
						</lineage>
					</dataqual>
					<spdoinfo>
						<direct>Vector</direct>
						<ptvctinf>
							<sdtsterm>
								<sdtstype>Entity point</sdtstype>
								<ptvctcnt>5345</ptvctcnt>
							</sdtsterm>
						</ptvctinf>
					</spdoinfo>
					<spref>
						<horizsys>
							<geograph>
								<latres>0.000001</latres>
								<longres>0.000001</longres>
								<geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
							</geograph>
							<geodetic>
								<horizdn>D_WGS_1984</horizdn>
								<ellips>WGS_1984</ellips>
								<semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
								<denflat>298.257224</denflat>
							</geodetic>
						</horizsys>
						<vertdef>
							<depthsys>
								<depthres>1</depthres>
								<depthdu>kilometers</depthdu>
								<depthem>Attribute values</depthem>
							</depthsys>
						</vertdef>
					</spref>
					<eainfo>
						<detailed>
							<enttyp>
								<enttypl>
quakehis</enttypl>
									<enttypd>The points represent earthquakes within or near to the United States that caused deaths, property damage, or geological effects, or that were experienced by populations in the epicentral area.</enttypd>
									<enttypds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</enttypds>
								</enttyp>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>ObjectID</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
									<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
									<attrdomv>
										<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
									</attrdomv>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
									<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
									<attrdomv>
										<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
									</attrdomv>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>DEPTH</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>The depth of focus of the earthquake in kilometers. A value of 0 may indicate the depth is unknown.</attrdef>
									<attrdefs>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</attrdefs>
									<attrdomv>
										<udom>Numbers for the features.</udom>
									</attrdomv>
									<attrdomv>
										<edom>
											<edomv>-9999</edomv>
											<edomvd>Unknown.</edomvd>
											<edomvds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</edomvds>
										</edom>
									</attrdomv>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>MAG</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>The maximum magnitude of the earthquake.  The maximum magnitude is the greatest of the body wave magnitude, duration, moment magnitude, surface wave magnitude, or local magnitude defined for the region.</attrdef>
									<attrdefs>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</attrdefs>
									<attrdomv>
										<udom>Numbers for the features.</udom>
									</attrdomv>
									<attrdomv>
										<edom>
											<edomv>-9999</edomv>
											<edomvd>Unknown.</edomvd>
											<edomvds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</edomvds>
										</edom>
									</attrdomv>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>MMI</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>The Modified Mercalli Intensity of the earthquake, where the integer value represents the Roman numeral designation of the MMI intensity.</attrdef>
									<attrdefs>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</attrdefs>
									<attrdomv>
										<edom>
											<edomv>F</edomv>
											<edomvd>The earthquake was felt but no Modified Mercalli Intensity was assigned.</edomvd>
											<edomvds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</edomvds>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>2</edomv>
											<edomvd>Felt only by a few persons at rest, especially on upper floors of buildings.  Delicately suspended objects may swing.</edomvd>
											<edomvds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</edomvds>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>3</edomv>
											<edomvd>Felt quite noticeably by persons indoors, especially on upper floors of buildings.  Many people do not recognize it as an earthquake.  Standing motorcars may rock slightly.  Vibration similar to the passing of truck.  Duration estimated.</edomvd>
											<edomvds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</edomvds>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>4</edomv>
											<edomvd>Felt indoors by many, outdoors by few during the day. At night, some awakened.  Dishes, windows, doors disturbed; walls make cracking sound.  Sensation like heavy truck striking building.  Standing motorcars rocked noticeably.</edomvd>
											<edomvds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</edomvds>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>5</edomv>
											<edomvd>Felt by nearly everyone; many awakened.  Some dishes, windows broken.  Unstable objects overturned. Pendulum clocks may stop.</edomvd>
											<edomvds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</edomvds>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>6</edomv>
											<edomvd>Felt by all; many frightened.  Some heavy furniture moved; a few instances of fallen plaster.  Damage slight.</edomvd>
											<edomvds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</edomvds>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>7</edomv>
											<edomvd>Damage negligible in building of good design and construction; slight to moderate in well-built ordinary structures; considerable damage in poorly built or badly designed structures; some chimneys broken.  Noticed by persons driving motorcars.</edomvd>
											<edomvds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</edomvds>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>8</edomv>
											<edomvd>Damage slight in specially designed structures; considerable in ordinary substantial buildings with partial collapse.  Damage great in poorly built structures.  Fall of chimneys, factory stacks, columns, monuments, and walls.  Heavy furniture overturned.</edomvd>
											<edomvds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</edomvds>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>9</edomv>
											<edomvd>Damage considerable in specially designed structures; well-designed frame structures thrown out of plumb. Damage great in substantial buildings, with partial collapse.  Buildings shifted off foundations.</edomvd>
											<edomvds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</edomvds>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>10</edomv>
											<edomvd>Some well-built wooden structures destroyed; most masonry and frame structures destroyed with foundations.  Railroad rails bent.</edomvd>
											<edomvds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</edomvds>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>11</edomv>
											<edomvd>Few, if any (masonry) structures remain standing. Bridges destroyed.  Railroad rails bent greatly.</edomvd>
											<edomvds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</edomvds>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>12</edomv>
											<edomvd>Damage total. Lines of sight and level distorted. Objects thrown into the air.</edomvd>
											<edomvds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</edomvds>
										</edom>
									</attrdomv>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>LOCATION</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>The name of the town, city, physical feature, or other describable location nearest to the occurrence.</attrdef>
									<attrdefs>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</attrdefs>
									<attrdomv>
										<udom>Descriptions for the features.</udom>
									</attrdomv>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>YEAR</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>The year of the occurrence.</attrdef>
									<attrdefs>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</attrdefs>
									<attrdomv>
										<rdom>
											<rdommin>1568</rdommin>
											<rdommax>2004</rdommax>
										</rdom>
									</attrdomv>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>MONTH</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>The month of the occurrence.</attrdef>
									<attrdefs>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</attrdefs>
									<attrdomv>
										<rdom>
											<rdommin>1</rdommin>
											<rdommax>12</rdommax>
										</rdom>
									</attrdomv>
									<attrdomv>
										<edom>
											<edomv>-9999</edomv>
											<edomvd>Unknown.</edomvd>
											<edomvds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</edomvds>
										</edom>
									</attrdomv>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>DAY</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>The day of the month of the occurrence.</attrdef>
									<attrdefs>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</attrdefs>
									<attrdomv>
										<rdom>
											<rdommin>1</rdommin>
											<rdommax>31</rdommax>
										</rdom>
									</attrdomv>
									<attrdomv>
										<edom>
											<edomv>-9999</edomv>
											<edomvd>Unknown.</edomvd>
											<edomvds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</edomvds>
										</edom>
									</attrdomv>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>HOUR</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>The hour of day of the occurrence on a 24-hour clock in Greenwich Mean Time (GMT).</attrdef>
									<attrdefs>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</attrdefs>
									<attrdomv>
										<rdom>
											<rdommin>0</rdommin>
											<rdommax>23</rdommax>
										</rdom>
									</attrdomv>
									<attrdomv>
										<edom>
											<edomv>-9999</edomv>
											<edomvd>Unknown.</edomvd>
											<edomvds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</edomvds>
										</edom>
									</attrdomv>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>MINUTE</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>The minute of the hour of the occurrence.</attrdef>
									<attrdefs>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</attrdefs>
									<attrdomv>
										<rdom>
											<rdommin>0</rdommin>
											<rdommax>59</rdommax>
										</rdom>
									</attrdomv>
									<attrdomv>
										<edom>
											<edomv>-9999</edomv>
											<edomvd>Unknown.</edomvd>
											<edomvds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</edomvds>
										</edom>
									</attrdomv>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>SECOND</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>The second of the minute of the occurrence.</attrdef>
									<attrdefs>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</attrdefs>
									<attrdomv>
										<rdom>
											<rdommin>0.00</rdommin>
											<rdommax>59.99</rdommax>
										</rdom>
									</attrdomv>
									<attrdomv>
										<edom>
											<edomv>-9999</edomv>
											<edomvd>Unknown.</edomvd>
											<edomvds>National Atlas of the United States and the United States Geological Survey</edomvds>
										</edom>
									</attrdomv>
								</attr>
							</detailed>
						</eainfo>
						<distinfo>
							<distrib>
								<cntinfo>
									<cntorgp>
										<cntorg>ESRI; ESRI International Distributors</cntorg>
									</cntorgp>
									<cntaddr>
										<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
										<address>380 New York Street</address>
										<city>Redlands</city>
										<state>California</state>
										<postal>92373-8100</postal>
										<country>USA</country>
									</cntaddr>
									<cntvoice>800-447-9778</cntvoice>
<cntinst>In the United States, contact the ESRI Telebusiness staff at 800-447-9778 for more information about our software and data.

Outside the United States, please direct all inquiries to your local ESRI International Distributor.  This information can be found at http://gis.esri.com/intldist/contact/.</cntinst>
								</cntinfo>
							</distrib>
							<resdesc>esri_2008_usa_quakehis</resdesc>
							<stdorder>
								<digform>
									<digtinfo>
										<formname>SDC</formname>
										<formspec>zip</formspec>
										<transize>0.212</transize>
									</digtinfo>
									<digtopt>
										<offoptn>
											<offmedia>DVDROM</offmedia>
											<reccap>
												<recden>7.95</recden>
												<recdenu>GB (gigabytes)</recdenu>
											</reccap>
											<recfmt>UDF (Universal Disc Format)</recfmt>
										</offoptn>
									</digtopt>
								</digform>
								<fees>Software purchase price</fees>
								<ordering>ESRI Data &amp; Maps is available only as part of ESRI software.</ordering>
							</stdorder>
							<techpreq>To use this data requires software that supports SDC files.</techpreq>
						</distinfo>
						<metainfo>
							<metd>20090715</metd>
							<metc>
								<cntinfo>
									<cntorgp>
										<cntorg>Research Data Services (RDS), Columbia University Libraries</cntorg>
										<cntper>GIS/Metadata Librarian</cntper>
									</cntorgp>
									<cntaddr>
										<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
										<address>420 W. 118th St. 215 IAB, MC 3301</address>
										<city>New York</city>
										<state>NY</state>
										<postal>10027</postal>
										<country>USA</country>
									</cntaddr>
									<cntvoice>(212) 854-6012</cntvoice>
									<cntemail>data@library.columbia.edu</cntemail>
								</cntinfo>
							</metc>
							<metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
							<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
							<mettc>local time</mettc>
						</metainfo>
					</metadata>
