<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
	<idinfo>
		<citation>
			<citeinfo>
				<origin>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</origin>
				<pubdate>1996</pubdate>
				<title>World Air Temperature Distribution in July (line), 1996</title>
				<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
				<serinfo>
					<sername>ArcAtlas</sername>
				</serinfo>
				<pubinfo>
					<pubplace>Redlands, Calif.</pubplace>
					<publish>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</publish>
				</pubinfo>
				<onlink>https://www1.columbia.edu/sec/acis/eds/dgate/studies/C1301/data/esri_1996_world_julytempline.zip</onlink>
			</citeinfo>
		</citation>
		<descript>
			<langdata>eng</langdata>
			<abstract>World Air Temperature Distribution in July (line), 1996 is a polyline theme representing the distribution of air temperatures in July worldwide.</abstract>
			<purpose>For educational, non-commercial purposes.  This dataset is appropriate for use in a GIS.</purpose>
<supplinf>Air temperature near the earth's surface is a major climatic factor controlling the
environment and significantly influencing the quality of human life.

The temperature of the air near the ground is mostly a result of heat exchange with the ground. It depends on two main factors: solar radiation and ground characteristics. The amount of solar radiation received by a place on the earth varies with latitude and with season. Annual solar radiation increases from the high latitudes (poles) to the low latitudes (tropics). Solar radiation varies seasonally with sun altitude. The proportion of solar radiation absorbed by the ground is the most important characteristic influencing the how much the ground heats the surrounding air. The proportion of absorbed solar radiation ranges from 10 percent for dry, clean, cold snow to 90 percent for water. For example, the proportion of absorbed radiation is about 78 to 86 percent for vegetation, 70 to 75 percent for desert sand, and 10 to 60 percent for snow, depending on its moisture and dust contents.

The air temperature of a region is influenced by regional heat exchange and air masses transferred to the region by atmospheric circulation. Land and water have different thermal characteristics. Land heats and cools more readily than water, so the continents are warmer in summer and cooler in winter than the oceans. Because the characteristics of air masses are formed by heat exchange along their routes, atmospheric circulation pattern over continents and ocean is also a leading factor determining air temperature. Large ice covers, such as in Antarctica, the Arctic, and Greenland, also influence the character of
the air masses over them.

Ocean currents are another factor that influence air temperature. The ocean currents affect the temperature of the air masses that pass over them. Air mass routes go westward between 30 and 75 degrees latitudes, and eastward at latitudes above 75 degrees and below 30 degrees in both the northern and southern hemispheres.

Air temperatures on the windward sides of the continents are similar to the temperatures of the ocean air masses because they are not yet modified much by the temperature of the land. These areas are said to have maritime climates. In the interiors and the leeward sides of continents, air temperatures are significantly modified by the ground. These areas are said to have continental climates. Continental climates are characterized by great annual temperature range, that is, a great difference between summer and winter temperatures. The range also increases with increasing latitude. In contrast, maritime climates are characterized by cool summers and mild winters.

Altitude also controls air temperature. Air temperatures generally decrease with altitude for two reasons: (1) increasing distance from the greatest surface area of the ground, which is the air's heat source, and (2) the natural expansion and cooling of the air as it rises, which results from the thinning of the atmosphere with altitude. The change in temperature with altitude (the vertical temperature gradient) is greater for dry air than for moist air. The rate of change averages 0.8 degrees Celsius per 100 meters of altitude. It is less in humid climates, 0.5 degrees per 100 meters, because as the rising air cools, water condenses and heat is released, slowing the rate of cooling.

Air temperatures decrease at rates close to the average gradient in summer, but in winter, the decrease is often broken by a temperature inversion. An inversion occurs when cold dense air accumulates near the cold ground and warmer air is found above it, causing the normal vertical gradient to be reversed. Mountains can be barriers to air masses. As a result, their altitudes and directions have an
effect on a region's air temperatures and atmospheric circulation.</supplinf>
		</descript>
		<timeperd>
			<timeinfo>
				<sngdate>
					<caldate>1996</caldate>
				</sngdate>
			</timeinfo>
			<current>publication date</current>
		</timeperd>
		<status>
			<progress>Complete</progress>
			<update>None planned</update>
		</status>
		<spdom>
			<bounding>
				<westbc>
-180</westbc>
					<eastbc>
180</eastbc>
						<northbc>
85</northbc>
							<southbc>
-85</southbc>
							</bounding>
						</spdom>
						<keywords>
							<theme>
								<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
								<themekey>Climate</themekey>
							</theme>
							<theme>
								<themekt>None</themekt>
								<themekey>Temperature</themekey>
							</theme>
							<place>
								<placekt>GeoNames</placekt>
								<placekey>Earth</placekey>
							</place>
							<temporal>
								<tempkt>None</tempkt>
								<tempkey>1996</tempkey>
							</temporal>
						</keywords>
						<accconst>For current Columbia affiliates only.</accconst>

						<useconst>For educational, non-commercial use only.</useconst>
						<ptcontac>
							<cntinfo>
								<cntorgp>
									<cntorg>ESRI</cntorg>
									<cntper>Data Team</cntper>
								</cntorgp>
								<cntaddr>
									<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
									<address>380 New York Street</address>
									<city>Redlands</city>
									<state>California</state>
									<postal>92373-8100</postal>
									<country>USA</country>
								</cntaddr>
								<cntvoice>909-793-2853</cntvoice>
								<cntfax>909-793-5953</cntfax>
								<cntemail>info@esri.com</cntemail>
								<hours>7:00 a.m.-5:30 p.m. Pacific time, Monday-Friday</hours>
								<cntinst>n the United States- Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing and consulting services to your local ESRI Regional Office. For support, you may contact Technical Support by telephone (voice) between 6:00 a.m. and 5:00 p.m. Pacific time, Monday through Friday, by dialing 888-377-4575; facsimile (fax) available at 909-792-0960; electronic mail (e-mail) support@esri.com; or visit http://support.esri.com; ESRI holidays excluded. Outside the United States Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing, sales, support, and consulting services to your local ESRI International Distributor. This information can be found at http://gis.esri.com/intldist/contactint.cfm. For other questions or comments, you may contact ESRI headquarters by e-mail, telephone, or fax or write to us.</cntinst>
							</cntinfo>
						</ptcontac>
						<browse>
							<browsen>http://www.columbia.edu/acis/eds/gis/pix/cat/temp_jul_ln.jpg</browsen>
							<browsed>Thumbnail</browsed>
							<browset>JPEG</browset>
						</browse>
						<native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.1850</native>
					</idinfo>
					<dataqual>
						<lineage>
							<srcinfo>
								<srccite>
									<citeinfo>
										<origin>Department of National Development</origin>
										<pubdate>1952</pubdate>
										<title>Atlas of Australian Resources. First Series.</title>
										<geoform>atlas</geoform>
										<pubinfo>
											<pubplace>Canberra</pubplace>
											<publish>Department of National Development</publish>
										</pubinfo>
									</citeinfo>
								</srccite>
								<typesrc>paper</typesrc>
								<srccitea>Atlas of Australian Resources</srccitea>
							</srcinfo>
							<srcinfo>
								<srccite>
									<citeinfo>
										<origin>WHO, UNESCO, USSR Goskomgidromet, UNEP</origin>
										<pubdate>1981</pubdate>
										<title>Climatic atlas of Asia</title>
										<geoform>atlas</geoform>
										<pubinfo>
											<pubplace>Leningrad</pubplace>
											<publish>Gidrometeoizdat</publish>
										</pubinfo>
									</citeinfo>
								</srccite>
								<typesrc>paper</typesrc>
								<srccitea>Climatic atlas of Asia</srccitea>
							</srcinfo>
							<srcinfo>
								<srccite>
									<citeinfo>
										<origin>WHO, UNESCO, Cartographia. Technical supervisor F.</origin>
										<pubdate>1970</pubdate>
										<title>Climatic atlas of Europe</title>
										<geoform>atlas</geoform>
										<pubinfo>
											<pubplace>Budapest</pubplace>
										</pubinfo>
									</citeinfo>
								</srccite>
								<typesrc>paper</typesrc>
								<srccitea>Climatic atlas of Europe</srccitea>
							</srcinfo>
							<srcinfo>
								<srccite>
									<citeinfo>
										<origin>WHO, UNESCO, Cartographia.</origin>
										<pubdate>1979</pubdate>
										<title>Climatic atlas of North and Central America</title>
										<pubinfo>
											<pubplace>Budapest</pubplace>
										</pubinfo>
									</citeinfo>
								</srccite>
								<typesrc>paper</typesrc>
								<srccitea>Climatic atlas of North and Central America</srccitea>
							</srcinfo>
							<srcinfo>
								<srccite>
									<citeinfo>
										<origin>WHO, UNESCO, Cartographia. Budapest</origin>
										<pubdate>1975</pubdate>
										<title>Climatic atlas of South America</title>
										<geoform>atlas</geoform>
									</citeinfo>
								</srccite>
								<typesrc>paper</typesrc>
								<srccitea>Climatic atlas of South America</srccitea>
							</srcinfo>
							<srcinfo>
								<srccite>
									<citeinfo>
										<origin>Lebedev, A. N.</origin>
										<pubdate>1978</pubdate>
										<title>Klimaticheskiy atlas Afriki</title>
										<geoform>atlas</geoform>
										<pubinfo>
											<pubplace>Leningrad</pubplace>
											<publish>Gidrometeoizdat</publish>
										</pubinfo>
									</citeinfo>
								</srccite>
								<typesrc>paper</typesrc>
								<srccitea>Klimaticheskiy atlas Afriki</srccitea>
							</srcinfo>
							<srcinfo>
								<srccite>
									<citeinfo>
										<origin>Parkinson, G., and Thompson, C.J.</origin>
										<pubdate>1986</pubdate>
										<title>Atlas of Australian Resources</title>
										<geoform>atlas</geoform>
										<pubinfo>
											<pubplace>Canberra</pubplace>
											<publish>Commonwealth Government printer</publish>
										</pubinfo>
									</citeinfo>
								</srccite>
								<typesrc>paper</typesrc>
								<srccitea>Atlas of Australian Resources</srccitea>
							</srcinfo>
							<procstep>
<procdesc>The mean air temperature maps were compiled with the data of about 9,000 meteorological stations. On the land, air temperature is measured by a thermometer at a height of 2 meters protected from solar radiation. Linear interpolation of the station data was possible only on flat plains far from the coasts. In other places, the isolines were laid out considering geographical situation. The isolines agree with the air temperature observations at each station.

Air temperatures decrease with increasing altitude on humid windward slopes by a vertical gradient of about 0.5 degree per 100 meters, and at arid leeward slopes by a vertical gradient of about 0.7 degree per 100 meters. The temperatures decrease toward water bodies in summer. Near the oceans, the increase is found at a distance of hundreds of kilometers on windward shores, and at a distance of thousands of kilometers on leeward shores. Near lakes, the distance is tens of kilometers. Taken into account are the observations that mean July temperatures are near 10 degrees Celsius at the boundary between the forest and tundra, and the heat-moisture ratio is about 1 (heat is in terms of evaporation) at the boundary between the forest and steppe. The decrease of the temperature range with altitude is taken into account as well. The isolines defined by this method were generalized and plotted using common cartographic methods.</procdesc>
								<srcused>Atlas of Australian Resources</srcused>
								<srcused>Climatic atlas of Asia</srcused>
								<srcused>Climatic atlas of Europe</srcused>
								<srcused>Climatic atlas of North and Central America</srcused>
								<srcused>Climatic atlas of South America</srcused>
								<srcused>Klimaticheskiy atlas Afriki</srcused>
								<srcused>Atlas of Australian Resources</srcused>
								<procdate>Unknown</procdate>
								<proccont>
									<cntinfo>
										<cntaddr>
										</cntaddr>
									</cntinfo>
								</proccont>
							</procstep>
							<procstep>
								<procdesc>Datasets for each continent were converted from ESRI coverage to the ESRI shapefile format using the 'copy features' tool and merged into one layer using the 'merge' tool.</procdesc>
								<procdate>20090507</procdate>
								<proccont>
									<cntinfo>
										<cntperp>
											<cntper>GIS/Map Librarian</cntper>
											<cntorg>Research Data Services (RDS), Columbia University Libraries</cntorg>
										</cntperp>
										<cntaddr>
											<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
											<address>420 W. 118th St. 215 IAB, MC 3301</address>
											<city>New York</city>
											<state>NY</state>
											<postal>10027</postal>
											<country>USA</country>
										</cntaddr>
										<cntvoice>(212) 854-6012</cntvoice>
										<cntemail>data@library.columbia.edu</cntemail>
									</cntinfo>
								</proccont>
							</procstep>
						</lineage>
					</dataqual>
					<spdoinfo>
						<direct>Vector</direct>
						<ptvctinf>
							<sdtsterm>
								<sdtstype>String</sdtstype>
								<ptvctcnt>6960</ptvctcnt>
							</sdtsterm>
						</ptvctinf>
					</spdoinfo>
					<spref>
						<horizsys>
							<geograph>
								<latres>0.000000</latres>
								<longres>0.000000</longres>
								<geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
							</geograph>
							<geodetic>
								<horizdn>D_Clarke_1866</horizdn>
								<ellips>Clarke 1866</ellips>
								<semiaxis>6378206.400000</semiaxis>
								<denflat>294.978698</denflat>
							</geodetic>
						</horizsys>
					</spref>
					<eainfo>
						<detailed>
							<enttyp>
								<enttypl>
temp_jul_ln</enttypl>
									<enttypd>Air temperature areas</enttypd>
								</enttyp>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
									<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
									<attrdomv>
										<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
									</attrdomv>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
									<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
									<attrdomv>
										<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
									</attrdomv>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>FNODE_</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Frome Node</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>TNODE_</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>To Node</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>LPOLY_</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Left Polygon</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>RPOLY_</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Right Polygon</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>LENGTH</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Length</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>SATJULDD_</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>South America</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>SATJULDD_I</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>South America ID</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>TEMPERATUR</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>temperature in degrees Celcius</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>LINE_TYPE</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Line Type</attrdef>
									<attrdomv>
										<edom>
											<edomv>coastline</edomv>
											<edomvd>coastline</edomvd>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>isoline</edomv>
											<edomvd>isolinev</edomvd>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>af_as_bnd</edomv>
											<edomvd>boundary between Africa and Asia</edomvd>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>eu_as_bnd</edomv>
											<edomvd>boundary between Europe and Asia</edomvd>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>na_sa_bnd</edomv>
											<edomvd>boundary between North and South America</edomvd>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>Gridline</edomv>
											<edomvd>180 degrees longitude line</edomvd>
										</edom>
									</attrdomv>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>NATJULDD_</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>North America</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>NATJULDD_I</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>North America ID</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>EUTJULDD_</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Europe</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>EUTJULDD_I</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Europe ID</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>AUTJULDD_</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Australia</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>AUTJULDD_I</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Australia ID</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>ASTJULDD_</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Asia</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>ASTJULDD_I</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Asia ID</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>ANTJULLB_</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Antarctica</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>ANTJULLB_I</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Antarctica</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>AFTJULDD_</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Africa</attrdef>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>AFTJULDD_I</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Africa ID</attrdef>
								</attr>
							</detailed>
						</eainfo>
						<distinfo>
							<distrib>
								<cntinfo>
									<cntorgp>
										<cntorg>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</cntorg>
									</cntorgp>
									<cntaddr>
										<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
										<address>380 New York Street</address>
										<city>Redlands</city>
										<state>California</state>
										<postal>92373-8100</postal>
										<country>USA</country>
									</cntaddr>
									<cntvoice>800-447-9778</cntvoice>
									<cntinst>In the United States, contact the ESRI Telebusiness staff at 800-447-9778 for more information about our software and data. Outside the United States, please direct all inquiries to your local ESRI International Distributor. This information can be found at http://gis.esri.com/intldist/contactint.cfm.</cntinst>
								</cntinfo>
							</distrib>
							<resdesc>esri_1996_world_julytempline</resdesc>
							<stdorder>
								<digform>
									<digtinfo>
										<formname>GeoPackage</formname>
										<formspec>zip</formspec>

										<transize>6.1 MB</transize>
									</digtinfo>
								</digform>
							</stdorder>
						</distinfo>
						<metainfo>
							<metd>20090611</metd>
							<metc>
								<cntinfo>
									<cntorgp>
										<cntorg>Research Data Services (RDS), Columbia University Libraries</cntorg>
										<cntper>GIS/Metadata Librarian</cntper>
									</cntorgp>
									<cntaddr>
										<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
										<address>420 W. 118th St. 215 IAB, MC 3301</address>
										<city>New York</city>
										<state>NY</state>
										<postal>10027</postal>
										<country>USA</country>
									</cntaddr>
									<cntvoice>(212) 854-6012</cntvoice>
									<cntemail>data@library.columbia.edu</cntemail>
									<hours>7:00 a.m.-5:30 p.m. Pacific time, Monday-Friday</hours>
								</cntinfo>
							</metc>
							<metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
							<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
							<mettc>local time</mettc>
						</metainfo>
					</metadata>
