<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
	<idinfo>
		<citation>
			<citeinfo>
				<origin>Geological Survey (U.S.)</origin>
				<origin>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</origin>
				<pubdate>2022</pubdate>
				<title>United States Buildings, 2022</title>
				<edition>2022</edition>
				<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
				<serinfo>
					<sername>ArcGIS Data and Maps</sername>
					<issue>2022 - World, Europe, and United States</issue>
				</serinfo>
				<pubinfo>
					<pubplace>Redlands, California, USA</pubplace>
					<publish>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</publish>
				</pubinfo>
				<othercit>Location: \usa\landmarks</othercit>
				<onlink>https://www1.columbia.edu/sec/acis/eds/dgate/studies/C1301/data/esri_2022_us_gblding.zip</onlink>
			</citeinfo>
		</citation>
		<descript>
			<abstract>U.S. Geographic Names Information System Buildings represents the Federal standard for geographic nomenclature and contains information about the proper names and locations of physical and cultural geographic features located throughout the United States and its Territories. The U.S. Geological Survey developed the Geographic Names Information System (GNIS) for the U.S. Board on Geographic Names, a Federal inter-agency body chartered by public law to maintain uniform feature name usage throughout the Government and to promulgate standard names to the public.</abstract>
			<purpose>Geographic Names Information System, of which U.S. Geographic Names Information System Buildings is a part, is the official repository of domestic geographic names data; the official vehicle for geographic names use by all departments of the Federal Government; and the source for applying geographic names to Federal electronic and printed products of all types in the United States. The feature locative information has been used in emergency preparedness, marketing, site-selection and analysis, genealogical and historical research, and transportation routing applications.</purpose>
		</descript>
		<timeperd>
			<timeinfo>
				<mdattim>
					<sngdate>
						<caldate>19810501</caldate>
					</sngdate>
					<sngdate>
						<caldate>20190901</caldate>
					</sngdate>
				</mdattim>
			</timeinfo>
			<current>publication date: 1981-05-01, 2019-09-01; ground condition: 1974-Present</current>
		</timeperd>
		<status>
			<progress>Complete</progress>
			<update>Annually</update>
		</status>
		<spdom>
			<bounding>
				<westbc>-176.642089</westbc>
				<eastbc>158.209722</eastbc>
				<northbc>71.298996</northbc>
				<southbc>-14.286667</southbc>
			</bounding>
		</spdom>
		<keywords>
			<theme>
				<themekt>None</themekt>
				<themekey>point</themekey>
				<themekey>building</themekey>
				<themekey>public building</themekey>
				<themekey>place name</themekey>
				<themekey>geographic feature</themekey>
				<themekey>elevation</themekey>
				<themekey>structure</themekey>
			</theme>
			<theme>
				<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
				<themekey>structure</themekey>
				<themekey>elevation</themekey>
			</theme>
			<place>
				<placekt>GeoNames</placekt>
				<placekey>United States (6252001)</placekey>
			</place>
			<place>
				<placekt>None</placekt>
				<placekey>United States</placekey>
				<placekey>U.S. Commonwealths</placekey>
				<placekey>U.S. Freely Associated States</placekey>
				<placekey>U.S. Territories</placekey>
			</place>
			<place>
				<placekt>Library of Congress Subject Headings</placekt>
				<placekey>United States</placekey>
			</place>
			<temporal>
				<tempkt>None</tempkt>
				<tempkey>1981</tempkey>
				<tempkey>2019</tempkey>
				<tempkey>1974-Present</tempkey>
			</temporal>
		</keywords>
		<accconst>For current Columbia affiliates only.</accconst>
		<useconst>For educational, non-commercial use only.</useconst>
		<ptcontac>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>Esri</cntorg>
					<cntper>ArcGIS Content Team</cntper>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
					<address>380 New York Street</address>
					<city>Redlands</city>
					<state>California</state>
					<postal>92373-8100</postal>
					<country>US</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>+1-909-793-2853</cntvoice>
				<cntfax>+1-909-793-5953</cntfax>
				<cntemail>info@esri.com</cntemail>
				<hours>9:00 a.m.-5:00 p.m. Pacific time, Monday-Friday</hours>
<cntinst>In the United States- Direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing and consulting services to your local Esri Regional Office. For support, contact Esri by telephone (voice) between 5:00 a.m. and 5:00 p.m. Pacific time, Monday through Friday, by dialing +1-888-377-4575; facsimile (fax) available at +1-909-792-0960; or visit https://support.esri.com/; Esri holidays excluded. Email and chat are available through the Support page on My Esri (https://my.esri.com).

Outside the United States- Direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing, sales, support, and consulting services to your local Esri Office. This information can be found at https://www.esri.com/en-us/contact#c=us&amp;t=0. For other questions or comments, you may contact Esri headquarters by email, telephone, or fax or write to us.</cntinst>
			</cntinfo>
		</ptcontac>
		<native> Version 6.2 (Build 9200) ; Esri ArcGIS 10.9.1.28388</native>
	</idinfo>
	<dataqual>
		<logic>The dataset is converted to file geodatabase (FGDB) format using tools in ArcGIS. The geometry is checked, and if needed repaired.</logic>
		<complete>After processing, the dataset is checked for drawing display and number of records and file sizes compared with source materials.</complete>
		<posacc>
			<horizpa>
				<horizpar>The geospatial part of this dataset was calculated from latitude/longitude coordinates. The source data is based upon the use of printed or electronic source graphics which are compiled to meet National Map Accuracy Standards.</horizpar>
			</horizpa>
		</posacc>
		<lineage>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>Geological Survey (U.S.)</origin>
						<pubdate>19810501</pubdate>
						<title>U.S. Geographic Names Information System (GNIS)</title>
						<edition>20190901</edition>
						<geoform>tabular digital data</geoform>
						<pubinfo>
							<pubplace>Reston, Virginia, USA</pubplace>
							<publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
						</pubinfo>
						<othercit>Downloaded the NationalFile_20190901.zip file.</othercit>
						<onlink>https://www.usgs.gov/core-science-systems/ngp/board-on-geographic-names/download-gnis-data</onlink>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<srcscale>24000</srcscale>
				<typesrc>onLine</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<mdattim>
							<sngdate>
								<caldate>19810501</caldate>
							</sngdate>
							<sngdate>
								<caldate>20190901</caldate>
							</sngdate>
						</mdattim>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>publication date: 1981-05-01, 2019-09-01; ground condition: 1974-Present</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>USGS - GNIS</srccitea>
				<srccontr>Attribute and geospatial data</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>GNIS Phase I data compilation and edit - Feature name and attribute data were collected from the largest-scale USGS topographic maps available. These data were compared to the records of the U.S. Board on Geographic Names. This phase is complete. GNIS Phase II data compilation and edit - Feature name and attribute data are collected from official state and local sources and other approved sources including historical maps and documents. This phase is not complete. GNIS Maintenance program - Federal and state maintenance cooperators submit new and corrected data in conjunction with their mapping and geographical information system data maintenance programs. The GNIS has an active data gathering and maintenance program. A web-based data entry and edit application allows authorized users to submit transaction data directly for validation and entry into the database, where it immediately becomes available to all web services and applications. A test and demonstration site is available. Government agencies at all levels are encouraged to join this program. Other organizations and individuals will be considered on a case basis. Partnerships - the Geographic Names Project enters into partnerships with State names authorities and State and local GIS agencies to integrate name, location, and attribute data in the GNIS with State and local datasets. These partnerships utilize GIS and web technology to automate and simplify data maintenance, ensure data consistency, integrity, and accuracy, and meet the requirements of the Board on Geographic Names for national names standardization. Government agencies at all levels are encouraged to join this program. Other organizations and individuals will be considered on a case basis.</procdesc>
				<procdate>not complete</procdate>
				<srcprod>withheld</srcprod>
			</procstep>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>The following steps were performed by Esri: Downloaded the tabular file from the U.S. Geological Survey website. Converted the file (containing latitude and longitude coordinates) to an FGDB dataset. Re-projected Hawaii to improve its alignment. Selected the nine GNIS datasets based on their class types. Removed features with incorrect coordinates and where the NAME fields contain the word 'Squaw'. Added the STCTYFIPS fields and populated them using source state and county fields. Adjusted the widths of the NAME fields. Removed unneeded fields.</procdesc>
				<srcused>withheld</srcused>
				<procdate>20191011</procdate>
			</procstep>
		</lineage>
	</dataqual>
	<spdoinfo>
		<direct>Vector</direct>
		<ptvctinf>
			<sdtsterm>
				<sdtstype>Entity point</sdtstype>
				<ptvctcnt>158606</ptvctcnt>
			</sdtsterm>
		</ptvctinf>
	</spdoinfo>
	<eainfo>
		<detailed>
			<enttyp>
				<enttypl>gblding</enttypl>
				<enttypd>The points represent physical and cultural geographic features located throughout the United States and its Territories.</enttypd>
				<enttypds>U.S. Geological Survey</enttypds>
			</enttyp>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>ObjectID</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>NAME</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>The name of the geographic feature. It is the proper name, specific term, or expression by which a particular geographic entity is, or was, known.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>U.S. Geological Survey, United States Board on Geographic Names</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<codesetd>
						<codesetn>Principles, Policies, and Procedures: Domestic Geographic Names</codesetn>
						<codesets>Principles, Policies, and Procedures: Domestic Geographic Names, By Donald J. Orth, Executive Secretary, Domestic Geographic Names (emeritus) and Roger L. Payne, Executive Secretary, United States Board on Geographic Names and Domestic Geographic Names, Third printing (revised) and Preliminary Online Edition, 1997</codesets>
					</codesetd>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>STCTYFIPS</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>The combined state/territory and county code. The combined code (five-digit number) uniquely identifies the county in which the geographic feature is located.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>American National Standards Institute</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<codesetd>
						<codesetn>INCITS 38:2009, (Formerly FIPS 5-2) Codes for the Identification of the States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, and the Insular Areas of the United States; INCITS 31:2009, (Formerly FIPS 6-4) Codes for the Identification of Counties and Equivalent Entities of the United States, its Possessions, and Insular Areas</codesetn>
						<codesets>American National Standards Institute</codesets>
					</codesetd>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>ELEV_METER</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>The elevation of the feature in meters relative to sea level.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>U.S. Geological Survey</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<udom>Numbers for the features.</udom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
		</detailed>
	</eainfo>
	<distinfo>
		<distrib>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>Esri; Esri Offices</cntorg>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
					<address>380 New York Street</address>
					<city>Redlands</city>
					<state>California</state>
					<postal>92373-8100</postal>
					<country>US</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>+1-800-447-9778</cntvoice>
<cntinst>In the United States, contact the Esri Sales staff at +1-800-447-9778 or visit https://www.esri.com/en-us/contact#c=us&amp;t=1 for more information about our software and data.

Outside the United States, direct all inquiries to your local Esri Office. This information can be found at https://www.esri.com/en-us/contact#c=us&amp;t=0.</cntinst>
			</cntinfo>
		</distrib>

		<distliab>See access and use constraints information.</distliab>
		<stdorder>
			<digform>
				<digtinfo>
					<formname>File Geodatabase Feature Class</formname>
					<formcont>To use this data requires software that works with FGDB files.</formcont>
					<filedec>ArcGIS software</filedec>
				</digtinfo>
				<digtopt>
					<onlinopt>
						<computer>
							<networka>
								<networkr>https://www.arcgis.com/home/group.html?id=24838c2d95e14dd18c25e9bad55a7f82#overview</networkr>
							</networka>
						</computer>
						<accinstr>Downloadable Data; Hosted Feature Layer</accinstr>
					</onlinopt>
					<onlinopt>
						<computer>
							<networka>
								<networkr>https://my.esri.com</networkr>
							</networka>
						</computer>
					</onlinopt>
					<offoptn>
						<offmedia>dvd</offmedia>
						<reccap>
							<recden>4.38 or 7.95</recden>
							<recdenu>GB (gigabytes)</recdenu>
						</reccap>
						<recfmt>Universal Disk Format file system</recfmt>
						<compat>Offline Data</compat>
					</offoptn>
				</digtopt>
			</digform>
			<fees>Software purchase price</fees>
			<ordering>Data and Maps is available only as part of ArcGIS software.</ordering>
		</stdorder>
		<resdesc>esri_2022_us_gblding</resdesc>
	</distinfo>
	<metainfo>
		<metd>20220822</metd>
		<metc>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>Esri</cntorg>
					<cntper>ArcGIS Content Team</cntper>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
					<address>380 New York Street</address>
					<city>Redlands</city>
					<state>California</state>
					<postal>92373-8100</postal>
					<country>US</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>+1-909-793-2853</cntvoice>
				<cntfax>+1-909-793-5953</cntfax>
				<cntemail>info@esri.com</cntemail>
				<hours>9:00 a.m.-5:00 p.m. Pacific time, Monday-Friday</hours>
			</cntinfo>
		</metc>
		<metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
		<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
		<mettc>local time</mettc>
	</metainfo>
</metadata>
