<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://www.fgdc.gov/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd">
<metadata>
	<idinfo>
		<citation>
			<citeinfo>
				<origin>International Steering Committee for Global Mapping</origin>
				<pubdate>2000</pubdate>
				<title>Philippines Vegetation, 2000</title>
				<geoform>raster digital data</geoform>
				<pubinfo>
					<pubplace>Tsukuba, Japan</pubplace>
					<publish>International Steering Committee for Global Mapping</publish>
				</pubinfo>
				<onlink>https://www.columbia.edu/acis/eds/gis/images/iscgm_philippines_2000_veg_rast.zip</onlink>
			</citeinfo>
		</citation>
		<descript>
			<langdata>eng</langdata>
			<abstract>Philippines Vegetation is a raster theme representing percentages of tree cover throughout Philippines at a resolution of 30 arc seconds.  This layer is a component of the Global Map a 1:1,000,000 scale framework dataset of the world. It consists of vector and raster layers of transport, administrative boundaries, drainage, elevation, vegetation, land use and land cover data. The data were prepared from information provided by national mapping and other organizations worldwide.</abstract>
			<purpose>The concept of Global Mapping, and the establishment of an international body for
Global Mapping, was first proposed by the Ministry of Construction of Japan (MOC) in
1992; and in 1994 the Geographical Survey Institute of Japan (GSI) proposed the first
draft Map Specifications. The project currently involves the participation of many
interested nations.
The main objective of this global project is to bring all nations and concerned
organizations together to develop and provide easy and open access to global digital
geographic information at a scale of 1:1 million. This would be used to facilitate the
implementation of global agreements and conventions for environmental protection,
for monitoring of major environmental phenomena and to encourage economic
growth within the context of sustainable development. As part of this objective, a
Global Map product will be developed to this specification.
The Global Map will also contribute to the development of a Global Spatial Data
Infrastructure.</purpose>
		</descript>
		<timeperd>
			<timeinfo>
				<sngdate>
					<caldate>1999</caldate>
				</sngdate>
			</timeinfo>
			<current>ground condition</current>
		</timeperd>
		<status>
			<progress>Complete</progress>
			<update>Unknown</update>
		</status>
		<spdom>
			<bounding>
				<westbc>
103.423960</westbc>
					<eastbc>
141.573960</eastbc>
						<northbc>
26.250000</northbc>
							<southbc>
-1.250000</southbc>
							</bounding>
						</spdom>
						<keywords>
							<theme>
								<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
								<themekey>biota</themekey>
							</theme>
							<theme>
								<themekt>None</themekt>
								<themekey>Trees</themekey>
								<themekey>Vegetation</themekey>
							</theme>
							<place>
								<placekt>GeoNames</placekt>
								<placekey>Philippines (1694008)</placekey>
							</place>
							<place>
								<placekt>Library of Congress Subject Headings</placekt>
								<placekey>Philippines</placekey>
							</place>
							<temporal>
								<tempkt>None</tempkt>
								<tempkey>1999</tempkey>
							</temporal>
						</keywords>
						<accconst>For current Columbia affiliates only.</accconst>
						<useconst>For educational, non-commercial use only.</useconst>
						<ptcontac>
							<cntinfo>
								<cntorgp>
									<cntorg>Geographical Survey Institute</cntorg>
									<cntper>Global Map Secretariat</cntper>
								</cntorgp>
								<cntaddr>
									<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
									<address>Geographical Survey Institute, Kitasato 1</address>
									<city>Tsukuba</city>
									<state>Ibaraki</state>
									<postal>305-0811</postal>
									<country>JAPAN</country>
								</cntaddr>
								<cntvoice>+81-29-864-6910</cntvoice>
								<cntemail>sec@iscgm.org</cntemail>
							</cntinfo>
						</ptcontac>
						<browse>
							<browsen>http://www.columbia.edu/acis/eds/gis/pix/cat/PhillipinesVegitation.jpg</browsen>
							<browsed>Thumbnail Image</browsed>
							<browset>JPEG</browset>
						</browse>
						<native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.2.5.1450</native>
					</idinfo>
					<dataqual>
						<attracc>
						</attracc>
						<logic>Logical consistency is a measure of the degree to which data complies with the technical specification. Logical consistency was validated by tests to check that table and file names are set out as in the Data Dictionary. Graphical tests checking such things as intersections, polygon closure, minimum sizes of polygons and length of linear features were also carried out.</logic>
						<complete>Completeness is a measure of the degree to which all features listed in the technical specification have been captured, in accordance with the selection criteria, definitions and other rules specified. All instances of a feature and its attribute values that meet the selection criteria and appear on the source materials are captured. The data is generalized so the selection of features is to some extent subjective.</complete>
						<posacc>
							<horizpa>
				<horizpar>For horizontal accuracy, 90% of points will be within 2km of their actual
location. In the case of data obtained from satellite images, the maximum error
is less than or equal to 0.5km.</horizpar>
							</horizpa>
							<vertacc>
				<vertaccr>Vertical accuracy is notionally  within 150 meters for 90% of points. This figure may
need to be reviewed once the data are available, as sources to this accuracy
may not be available in areas of high relief.</vertaccr>
							</vertacc>
						</posacc>
						<lineage>
							<procstep>
								<procdesc>The source data for the raster data layers was supplied by the United States Geological Survey and consisted of the revised Global 30" Elevation dataset (GTOPO30) produced by EROS and data derived from the Global Landcover Characteristics Database (CLCCD), a cooperative venture between USGS, the University of Nebraska-Lincoln and the European Commission's Joint Research Centre (JRC). The land cover, land use and vegetation layers were edited by AUSLIG to reflect some errors of classification. However, it was not subjected to a thorough vetting.</procdesc>
								<procdate>200006</procdate>
								<proccont>
									<cntinfo>
										<cntorgp>
											<cntorg>National Mapping and Resource Information Authority</cntorg>
										</cntorgp>
										<cntaddr>
											<addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
											<address>Fort Andres Bonifacio</address>
											<city>Makati</city>
											<country>Philippines</country>
										</cntaddr>
									</cntinfo>
								</proccont>
							</procstep>
							<procstep>
								<procdesc>All of the original tiles were merged into one dataset, which was exported to the GRID format.</procdesc>
								<procdate>20090302</procdate>
								<proccont>
									<cntinfo>
										<cntperp>
											<cntper>GIS/Map Librarian</cntper>
											<cntorg>Research Data Services (RDS), Columbia University Libraries</cntorg>
										</cntperp>
										<cntaddr>
											<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
											<address>420 W. 118th St. 215 IAB, MC 3301</address>
											<city>New York</city>
											<state>NY</state>
											<postal>10027</postal>
											<country>USA</country>
										</cntaddr>
										<cntvoice>(212) 854-6012</cntvoice>
										<cntemail>data@library.columbia.edu</cntemail>
										<hours>11:00AM-5:00PM Monday - Thursday, 1:00PM-5:00PM Friday EST-USA</hours>
									</cntinfo>
								</proccont>
							</procstep>
						</lineage>
					</dataqual>
					<spdoinfo>
						<direct>Raster</direct>
						<rastinfo>
							<rasttype>Grid Cell</rasttype>
							<rowcount>3300</rowcount>
							<colcount>4578</colcount>
							<vrtcount>1</vrtcount>
						</rastinfo>
					</spdoinfo>
					<spref>
						<horizsys>
							<geograph>
								<latres>0.000000</latres>
								<longres>0.000000</longres>
								<geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
							</geograph>
							<geodetic>
								<horizdn>D_WGS_1984</horizdn>
								<ellips>WGS_1984</ellips>
								<semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
								<denflat>298.257224</denflat>
							</geodetic>
						</horizsys>
						<vertdef>
							<altsys>
								<altres>0.000100</altres>
								<altenc>Explicit elevation coordinate included with horizontal coordinates</altenc>
							</altsys>
						</vertdef>
					</spref>
					<eainfo>
						<detailed>
							<enttyp>
								<enttypl>
vegetation.vat</enttypl>
									<enttypd>Vegetation</enttypd>
								</enttyp>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>Rowid</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
									<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
									<attrdomv>
										<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
									</attrdomv>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>VALUE</attrlabl>
									<attrdef>Vegetation type</attrdef>
									<attrdomv>
										<edom>
											<edomv>10</edomv>
											<edomvd>Tropical rainforest: Evergreen forest which has high rainfall and high humidity throughout the year. This class has an upper canopy formed by trees from 30 to 40m tall and may have occasional emerging trees taller than the upper canopy.</edomvd>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>20</edomv>
											<edomvd>Hydrotropic forest: Deciduous broad-leaved trees which are defoliated in dry season and foliate in rainy season.</edomvd>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>30</edomv>
											<edomvd>Grassland in tropical or sub-tropical zone: Grassland which has a long dry season and is heavily dried. Trees are only sparsely distributed. Plant density depends on dryness.</edomvd>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>40</edomv>
											<edomvd>Semi desert in tropical or sub-tropical zone: Plants are sparsely distributed in the area which has a little rainfall and is heavily dried</edomvd>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>50</edomv>
											<edomvd>Desert in tropical or sub-tropical zone: Plants are very sparsely distributed in the area which has a little rainfall and is extremely dried.</edomvd>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>60</edomv>
											<edomvd>Evergreen thick-leaved forest: Forest which has high rainfall in the rainy season and is relatively dried in summer. Trees which have evergreen thick and hard leaves dominate this forest.</edomvd>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>70</edomv>
											<edomvd>Evergreen broad-leaved forest: Forest in the warm temperate zone which has high rainfall in summer, or is humid throughout the year. Broad-leaved trees which have a little larger leaves than evergreen thick-leaved trees are the main component of this forest.</edomvd>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>80</edomv>
											<edomvd>Deciduous broad-leaved forest: Forest which mainly consists of trees defoliated in winter. This forest appears in the area which has sufficient rainfall in cool temperate zone.</edomvd>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>90</edomv>
											<edomvd>Grassland in temperate zone: Grassland in drier climates in temperate zone. No trees grow.</edomvd>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>100</edomv>
											<edomvd>Semi-desert in temperate zone: Heavily dried area in the temperate zone. Grasses, such as mugwort and pigweed cover this area.</edomvd>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>110</edomv>
											<edomvd>Desert in temperate zone: Extremely dried area in temperate zone. Grasses, such as mugwort and pigweed cover this area.</edomvd>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>120</edomv>
											<edomvd>Northern coniferous forest: Coniferous trees in semi-frigid zone which has very cold and long winter. Trees in this forest are usually evergreen</edomvd>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>130</edomv>
											<edomvd>Tundra: Plant colony consists of shrub, grass with broad leaves, moss and lichen. Trees cannot become tall due to severe cold.</edomvd>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>140</edomv>
											<edomvd>Water body: Water surfaces, such as rivers and lakes.</edomvd>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>150</edomv>
											<edomvd>Ice and snow: Area which is covered with snow and ice throughout the year.</edomvd>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>210</edomv>
											<edomvd>Wetland: Vegetated area with waterlogged soils or surface water for significant periods of the year.</edomvd>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>220</edomv>
											<edomvd>Mixed forest: Forest containing a mixture of types. Usually deciduous and coniferous.</edomvd>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>230</edomv>
											<edomvd>Mixed land: Area containing a mosaic of other types.</edomvd>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>240</edomv>
											<edomvd>Non natural: Cultivated, urban or otherwise modified vegetation.</edomvd>
										</edom>
										<edom>
											<edomv>250</edomv>
											<edomvd>Unclassified: Areas not included in other classifications. For example, barren land.</edomvd>
										</edom>
									</attrdomv>
								</attr>
								<attr>
									<attrlabl>COUNT</attrlabl>
								</attr>
							</detailed>
						</eainfo>
						<distinfo>
							<distrib>
								<cntinfo>
									<cntorgp>
										<cntorg>Geographical Survey Institute</cntorg>
										<cntper>Global Map Secretariat</cntper>
									</cntorgp>
									<cntaddr>
										<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
										<address>Geographical Survey Institute, Kitasato 1</address>
										<city>Tsukuba</city>
										<state>Ibaraki</state>
										<postal>305-0811</postal>
										<country>JAPAN</country>
									</cntaddr>
									<cntvoice>+81-29-864-6910</cntvoice>
									<cntfax>+81-29-864-6923</cntfax>
									<cntemail>sec@iscgm.org</cntemail>
								</cntinfo>
							</distrib>
							<resdesc>iscgm_philippines_2000_veg_rast</resdesc>
							<stdorder>
								<digform>
									<digtinfo>
										<formname>GRID</formname>
										<formspec>zip</formspec>
										<transize>0.3 MB</transize>
									</digtinfo>
								</digform>
							</stdorder>
						</distinfo>
						<metainfo>
							<metd>20090311</metd>
							<metc>
								<cntinfo>
									<cntorgp>
										<cntorg>Research Data Services (RDS), Columbia University Libraries</cntorg>
										<cntper>GIS/Metadata Librarian</cntper>
									</cntorgp>
									<cntaddr>
										<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
										<address>420 W. 118th St., 215 IAB, MC 3301</address>
										<city>New York</city>
										<state>NY</state>
										<postal>10027</postal>
									</cntaddr>
									<cntvoice>(212)854-6012</cntvoice>
									<cntemail>data@library.columbia.edu</cntemail>
								</cntinfo>
							</metc>
							<metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
							<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
							<mettc>local time</mettc>
						</metainfo>
					</metadata>
