<metadata>
	<idinfo>
		<citation>
			<citeinfo>
				<origin>United States. Bureau of Transportation Statistics</origin>
				<origin>United States. Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration</origin>
				<origin>United States. Department of Transportation. Research and Innovative Technology Administration</origin>
				<pubdate>2012</pubdate>
				<title>United States Hazardous Material Routes, 2013</title>
				<edition>2005 Preliminary Edition</edition>
				<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
				<serinfo>
					<sername>FMCSA Hazardous Material Routes</sername>
					<issue>None at time of this release.</issue>
				</serinfo>
				<pubinfo>
					<pubplace>Washington, DC</pubplace>
					<publish>United States. Bureau of Transportation Statistics</publish>
				</pubinfo>
				<lworkcit>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>Research and Innovative Technology Administration's Bureau of Transportation Statistics (RITA/BTS)</origin>
						<pubdate>20120724</pubdate>
						<title>National Transportation Atlas Databases (NTAD) 2013</title>
						<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
						<onlink>http://www.bts.gov/programs/geographic_information_services/</onlink>

				</citeinfo></lworkcit>
			<onlink>https://www.columbia.edu/acis/eds/gis/images/ntad_2013_hazmat.zip</onlink></citeinfo>
		</citation>
		<descript>
			<abstract>The Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration (FMCSA) Hazardous Material Routes were developed using the 2004 First Edition TIGER/Line files. The routes are described in the National Hazardous Material Route Registry (NMHRR). The on-line NMHRR linkage is http://hazmat.fmcsa.dot.gov/nhmrr/index.asp With the exception of 13 features that were not identified with the Tiger/Lines, Hazmat routes were created by extracting the TIGER/Line segments that corresponded to each individual route. Hazmat routes in the NTAD, are organized into 3 database files, hazmat.shp, hmroutes.dbf, and hmstcnty.dbf. Each record in each database represents a unique Tiger/Line segment. These Tiger/Line segments are grouped into routes identified as character strings in the ROUTE_ID field in the hmroutes.dbf table. The route name appearing in the ROUTE_ID is assigned by FMCSA and is unique for each State [this sentence could be deleted - it doesn't add a lot to it]. The hmstcnty.dbf table allows the user to select routes by State and County. A single shapefile, called hazmat.shp, represents geometry for all routes in the United States.</abstract>
			<purpose>In order for the public to be able to view the Hazardous Material Routes reported to FMCSA, the data is being released in ESRI shapefile format for use in a GIS system.</purpose>
			<supplinf>The data provided is in the native Latitude/Longitude coordinate system inherited from the TIGER/Line data.</supplinf>
		</descript>
		<timeperd>
			<timeinfo>
				<sngdate>
					<caldate>2012</caldate>
					<time>unknown</time>
				</sngdate>
			</timeinfo>
			<current>Unknown</current>
		</timeperd>
		<spdom>
			<bounding>
				<westbc>-124.216232</westbc>
				<eastbc>-71.051495</eastbc>
				<northbc>49.000758</northbc>
				<southbc>26.111954</southbc>
			</bounding>
		</spdom>
		<keywords>
			<theme>
				<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
				<themekey>Boundaries</themekey>
			</theme>
			<theme>
				<themekt>FGDC Framework Themes</themekt>
				<themekey>FWTRANSPORTATION</themekey>
				<themekey>FWROADS</themekey>
				<themekey>FWGOVERNMENTALUNITS</themekey>
			</theme>
			<theme>
				<themekt>None</themekt>
				<themekey>Vector</themekey>
				<themekey>Feature Identifier</themekey>
				<themekey>TIGER/Line Identification Number (TLID)</themekey>
				<themekey>Census Feature Class Code (CFCC)</themekey>
				<themekey>Latitude/Longitude</themekey>
				<themekey>TIGER/Line</themekey>
				<themekey>Point/Node</themekey>
				<themekey>Hazardous Material Route</themekey>
				<themekey>Line Feature</themekey>
				<themekey>FMCSA</themekey>
			</theme>
			<place>
				<placekt>GeoNames</placekt>
				<placekey>United States (6252001)</placekey>
			</place>
			<place>
				<placekt>Library of Congress Subject Headings</placekt>
				<placekey>United States</placekey>
			</place>
			<temporal>
				<tempkt>None</tempkt>
				<tempkey>2007</tempkey>
				<tempkey>2010</tempkey>
				<tempkey>2011</tempkey>
				<tempkey>2009</tempkey>
				<tempkey>2008</tempkey>
				<tempkey>2006</tempkey>
				<tempkey>2012</tempkey>
				<tempkey>2013</tempkey>
			</temporal>
		</keywords>
		<accconst>None</accconst>
		<useconst>None</useconst>
		<ptcontac>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>Hazardous Material Routes:U.S. Department of Transportation Volpe NTSC TIGER/Line:U.S. Department of Commerce, U.S. Census Bureau, Geography Division</cntorg>
				</cntorgp>
			</cntinfo>
		</ptcontac>
		<ptcontac>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>Research and Innovative Technology Administration's Bureau of Transportation Statistics (RITA/BTS)</cntorg>
					<cntper>National Transportation Atlas Database (NTAD) 2013</cntper>
				</cntorgp>
			</cntinfo>
		</ptcontac>
		<ptcontac>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration</cntorg>
					<cntper>David Miller</cntper>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntpos>Program Manager</cntpos>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>unknown</addrtype>
					<address>1200 New Jersey Ave. SE</address>
					<city>Washington</city>
					<state>DC</state>
					<postal>20590</postal>
					<country>US</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>202-366-5011</cntvoice>
				<cntemail>david.miller@dot.gov</cntemail>
				<cntinst>Web link to latest HAZMAT route information: http://www.fmcsa.dot.gov/safety-security/hazmat/national-hazmat-Route.aspx
</cntinst>
			</cntinfo>
		</ptcontac>
		<secinfo>
			<secclass>Unclassified</secclass>
		</secinfo>
		<native>Microsoft Windows 7 Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; Esri ArcGIS 10.1.0.3035</native>
		<crossref>
			<citeinfo>
				<origin>Research and Innovative Technology Administration's Bureau of Transportation Statistics (RITA/BTS)</origin>
				<pubdate>20120724</pubdate>
				<title>National Transportation Atlas Databases (NTAD) 2013</title>
				<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
				<pubinfo>
					<pubplace>Washington, DC</pubplace>
					<publish>Research and Innovative Technology Administration's Bureau of Transportation Statistics (RITA/BTS)</publish>
				</pubinfo>
				<onlink>http://www.bts.gov/programs/geographic_information_services/</onlink>
			</citeinfo>
		</crossref>
	</idinfo>
	<dataqual>
		<attracc>
			<attraccr>Inherited TIGER/Line attributes are accurate against Federal Information Processing Standards (FIPS), FIPS Publication 6-4, and FIPS-55 at the 100% level for the codes and base names. The remaining attribute information has been examined but has not been fully tested for accuracy.</attraccr>
		</attracc>
		<logic>Route consistency is being reviewed at this time. Network consistency is inherited from TIGER/Line: The feature network of lines (as represented by Record Types 1 and 2) is complete for census purposes. Spatial objects in TIGER/Line belong to the "Geometry and Topology" (GT) class of objects in the "Spatial Data Transfer Standard" (SDTS) FIPS Publication 173 and are topologically valid. Node/geometry and topology GT-polygon/chain relationships are collected or generated to satisfy topological edit requirements. These requirements include: (1) Complete chains must begin and end at nodes. (2) Complete chains must connect to each other at nodes. (3) Complete chains do not extend through nodes. (4) Left and right GT-polygons are defined for each complete chain element and are consistent throughout the extract process. (5) The chains representing the limits of the files are free of gaps. The Census Bureau performed automated tests to ensure logical consistency and limits of files. All polygons are tested for closure. The Census Bureau uses its internally developed Geographic Update System to enhance and modify spatial and attribute data in the Census TIGER database. Standard geographic codes, such as FIPS codes for states, counties, municipalities, and places, are used when encoding spatial entities. The Census Bureau performed spatial data tests for logical consistency of the codes during the compilation of the original Census TIGER database files. Most of the codes themselves were provided to the Census Bureau by the USGS, the agency responsible for maintaining FIPS 55. Feature attribute information has been examined but has not been fully tested for consistency.</logic>
		<complete>Of the 904 routes reported, 897 have been created.</complete>
		<posacc>
			<horizpa>
				<horizpar>Accuracy is inherited from the TIGER/Line files: The Census Bureau uses Global Positioning System (GPS) coordinates at road centerline intersections to evaluate the horizontal spatial accuracy of source files that may be used to realign road features in the TIGER database and test the horizontal spatial accuracy of the road features in the TIGER/Line files. The test compares a survey-grade GPS coordinate to its associated road centerline intersection in the TIGER file. The test is based upon an independent collection of GPS coordinates for a random sample of road intersections from a centerline file that meet certain criteria. The points are referred to as the sample points and are gathered through a private contractor working for the Census Bureau. Since the collection method uses survey-quality GPS-based field techniques, the resulting control points are considered "ground truth" against which the TIGER road centerline intersection coordinates are compared. The distances between the coordinates are calculated and the Census Bureau determines the Circular Error 95% (CE95). That is, the accuracy of the file in meters with 95% confidence. The CE95 can be calculated from the mean and standard deviation by using the formula: mean of differences plus (2.65 times the standard deviation). CE95 results reported for each file tested are determined using a spreadsheet with embedded statistical formula. The use and applicability of the spreadsheet and its embedded formula have been verified by Census Bureau statisticians. The basis of the calculation is the use of the root mean square error (RSME). This is the method as stated in the U.S. Government's Federal Geographic Data Committee Standard FGDC-STD-007.3-1998, Geospatial Positioning Accuracy Standards. Part 3: National Standard for Spatial Data Accuracy. The results of using this measure of accuracy are in compliance with Federal Spatial Data requirements. In terms of the Census Bureau application, the dataset coordinate values are those taken from the centerline file and the coordinate values from an independent source of higher accuracy are those acquired through the Census Bureau's contractor. Refer to the 2004 First Edition TIGER/Line metadata for each county or statistically equivalent entity for information on the spatial accuracy of features in that county. Please note that the horizontal spatial accuracy, where reported, refers only to the realigned road features identified as matched to the positionally accurate source file with that accuracy. It is not the spatial accuracy of the TIGER/Line file as a whole.</horizpar>
			</horizpa>
		</posacc>
		<lineage>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>Hazardous Material Routes:U.S. Department of Transportation Volpe NTSC TIGER/Line:U.S. Department of Commerce, U.S. Census Bureau, Geography Division</origin>
						<pubdate>unpublished material</pubdate>
						<title>National Hazardous Material Routes</title>
						<pubinfo>
							<pubplace>Washington, DC</pubplace>
							<publish>Research and Innovative Technology Administration's Bureau of Transportation Statistics (RITA/BTS)</publish>
						</pubinfo>
					</citeinfo></srccite>
				<typesrc>CD-ROM</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<sngdate>
							<caldate>20120101</caldate>
						</sngdate>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>NMHRR</srccitea>
				<srccontr>Geographic and cartographic information (line segments) selected from the Census TIGER/Line database.</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>Hazardous Material Routes are extracted from the Census TIGER/Line files. This is the preliminary release.</procdesc>
				<srcused>NMHRR</srcused>
				<procdate>20060101</procdate>
			</procstep>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>RITA/BTS has normalized the original HazMat table in an effort to increase efficiencies in data storage and retrieval. The original table contained the following fields: FID (Primary Key), Shape (geometry), TLID, FEDIRP, FENAME, FETYPE, FEDIRS, CFCC, STCNTY, RouteID, RouteType. After studying the table it was found that the STCNTY, ROUTEID and ROUTETYPE fields could be separated from the hazmat table and placed into related tables. Below are the processes taken to normalize the data. First the primary key field (FID) was duplicated within hazmat table. The field was named PK and now acts as the primary key for the table. Then the table was run through a program that identified which records were duplicates. For each duplicate record the appropriate Primary Key was assigned. Next the hmroutes table was created. The RouteID and RouteType fields were placed in this table along with FK field. The FK field was populated with the PK values of the hazmat table and will serve as the foreign key field. The ROUTEID field was a concatenation of the State Abbreviation, the Route Type and the Route Number. The table was run through a program that parsed and stored the state abbreviation, the route type and route number into separate fields. Then the hmstcnty table was created. The STCNTY field was placed in this table along with FK field. The FK field was populated with the PK values of the hazmat table and will serve as the foreign key field. The STCNTY field was a concatenation of the State FIPS and the County FIPS codes. The table was run through a program that parsed and stored the state FIPS and county FIPS into separate fields. Finally the duplicate records in the hazmat table were deleted.</procdesc>
				<procdate>20060101</procdate>
				<proccont>
					<cntinfo>
						<cntorgp>
							<cntorg>Research and Innovative Technology Administration's Bureau of Transportation Statistics (RITA/BTS)</cntorg>
							<cntper>Geospatial Information Program</cntper>
						</cntorgp>
						<cntaddr>
							<addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
							<address>1200 New Jersey Ave., SE</address>
							<city>Washington</city>
							<state>DC</state>
							<postal>20590</postal>
							<country>US</country>
						</cntaddr>
						<cntvoice>1 202 366 DATA</cntvoice>
						<cntfax>1 202 366 3640</cntfax>
						<cntemail>answers@bts.gov</cntemail>
					</cntinfo>
				</proccont>
			</procstep>
		</lineage>
	</dataqual>
	<spdoinfo>
		<indspref>Federal Information Processing Standards (FIPS) and feature names.</indspref>
		<direct>Vector</direct>
		<ptvctinf>
			<sdtsterm>
				<sdtstype>String</sdtstype>
				<ptvctcnt>145005</ptvctcnt>
			</sdtsterm>
		</ptvctinf>
	</spdoinfo>
	<spref>
		<horizsys>
			<geograph>
				<latres>8.983152841195215e-009</latres>
				<longres>8.983152841195215e-009</longres>
				<geogunit>Decimal Degrees</geogunit>
			</geograph>
			<geodetic>
				<horizdn>D WGS 1984</horizdn>
				<ellips>WGS 1984</ellips>
				<semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
				<denflat>298.257223563</denflat>
			</geodetic>
		</horizsys>
	</spref>
	<eainfo>
		<detailed>
			<enttyp>
				<enttypl>hazmat</enttypl>
				<enttypd>FMCSA Hazardous Material Routes in GIS Format</enttypd>
				<enttypds>Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration</enttypds>
			</enttyp>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>System generated primary key; a unique identification number for the feature</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Internal Arcview Generated Attribute</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>ArcView</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>Polyline</edomv>
						<edomvd>Polygonal Shapes as defined by ArcView</edomvd>
						<edomvds>ArcView Internal Attribute</edomvds>
					</edom>
					<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>TLID</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>The Tiger Line Identification number</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Census TIGER/Line</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>0</rdommin>
						<rdommax>212556923</rdommax>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>FEDIRP</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Feature direction prefix</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Census TIGER/Line</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>N</edomv>
						<edomvd>North</edomvd>
						<edomvds>USBOC</edomvds>
					</edom>
					<edom>
						<edomv>NE</edomv>
						<edomvd>North East</edomvd>
						<edomvds>USBOC</edomvds>
					</edom>
					<edom>
						<edomv>NW</edomv>
						<edomvd>North West</edomvd>
						<edomvds>USBOC</edomvds>
					</edom>
					<edom>
						<edomv>E</edomv>
						<edomvd>East</edomvd>
						<edomvds>USBOC</edomvds>
					</edom>
					<edom>
						<edomv>S</edomv>
						<edomvd>South</edomvd>
						<edomvds>USBOC</edomvds>
					</edom>
					<edom>
						<edomv>SE</edomv>
						<edomvd>South East</edomvd>
						<edomvds>USBOC</edomvds>
					</edom>
					<edom>
						<edomv>SW</edomv>
						<edomvd>South West</edomvd>
						<edomvds>USBOC</edomvds>
					</edom>
					<edom>
						<edomv>W</edomv>
						<edomvd>West</edomvd>
						<edomvds>USBOC</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>FENAME</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Feature name</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Census TIGER/Line</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<udom>Character Value</udom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>FETYPE</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Feature Type</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Census TIGER/Line</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<udom>Character Value</udom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>FEDIRS</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Feature Direction Code</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Census TIGER/Line</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>E</edomv>
						<edomvd>East</edomvd>
						<edomvds>USBOC</edomvds>
					</edom>
					<edom>
						<edomv>N</edomv>
						<edomvd>North</edomvd>
						<edomvds>USBOC</edomvds>
					</edom>
					<edom>
						<edomv>NE</edomv>
						<edomvd>North East</edomvd>
						<edomvds>USBOC</edomvds>
					</edom>
					<edom>
						<edomv>NW</edomv>
						<edomvd>North West</edomvd>
						<edomvds>USBOC</edomvds>
					</edom>
					<edom>
						<edomv>S</edomv>
						<edomvd>South</edomvd>
						<edomvds>USBOC</edomvds>
					</edom>
					<edom>
						<edomv>SE</edomv>
						<edomvd>South East</edomvd>
						<edomvds>USBOC</edomvds>
					</edom>
					<edom>
						<edomv>SW</edomv>
						<edomvd>South West</edomvd>
						<edomvds>USBOC</edomvds>
					</edom>
					<edom>
						<edomv>W</edomv>
						<edomvd>West</edomvd>
						<edomvds>USBOC</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>CFCC</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Census Feature Class Code</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Census TIGER/Line</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<codesetd>
						<codesetn>Census Feature Class Code</codesetn>
						<codesets>USBOC</codesets>
					</codesetd>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>PK</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Primary Key</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>RITA/BTS</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<udom>Numeric Value</udom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
		</detailed>
		<overview>
			<eaover>Hazardous Material Route files contain data describing Line Features.
The data/attributes describing the lines include coordinates, feature identifiers (route id and route type), CFCCs (inherited from TIGER/Line and used to identify
the TIGER/Line characteristic of a feature) and secondary feature name (Street name: inherited from TIGER/Line)

The hazmat table stores the basic spatial data for the Hazardous Materials information.  The hmroutes tables stores the routing information and the hmstcnty table holds the state and county information.  All of the data are not stored in a single table because it is inefficient.

To integrate the hmroutes table with the hazmat table you must create a relationship between the two.  This relationship is defined by hazmat's PK field and the hmroute's FK field.  More specifically for each PK value in the hazmat table there are one or more FK values in the hmroutes table.

To integrate the hmstcnty table with the hazmat table you must create a relationship between the two.  This relationship is defined by hazmat's PK field and the hmstcnty's FK field.  More specifically for each PK value in the hazmat table there are one or more FK values in the hmstcnty table.  For information on how to create a relationship between tables search for the term "relate" in the help file of your GIS application.</eaover>
			<eadetcit>hmstcnty
OID - The primary key and a unique identification number for the record
FK - The foreign key.  This field is used to link this table and the related features of the hazmat table
StFIPS - The State FIPS code for the related feature
CntyFIPS - the county FIPS code for the related feature</eadetcit>
			<eadetcit>hmroutes
OID - The primary key and a unique identification number for the record
FK - The foreign key.  This field is used to link this table and the related features of the hazmat table.
STATEABBR - Abbreviation of the state in which the related hazmat feature occurs
ROUTE_ID - The original route identification code presented by Highways.  It's a concatenation of the State Abbreviation, the Route Type and the Route Number.
STATEABBR - The two letter state abbreviation
ROUTE_TYPE - The route type of the related hazmat feature
ROUTENUM - the route number of the related Hazmat feature.</eadetcit>
		</overview>
	</eainfo>
	<distinfo>
		<distrib>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>Research and Innovative Technology Administration's Bureau of Transportation Statistics (RITA/BTS)</cntorg>
					<cntper>Office of Geospatial Information Systems</cntper>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing</addrtype>
					<address>1200 New Jersey Ave., SE</address>
					<city>Washington</city>
					<state>DC</state>
					<postal>20590</postal>
					<country>US</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>(202) 366-3282</cntvoice>
				<cntemail>answers@bts.gov</cntemail>
			</cntinfo>
		</distrib>
		<resdesc>ntad_2013_hazmat</resdesc>
		<stdorder>
			<digform>

				<digtopt>
					<offoptn>
						<offmedia>dvd</offmedia>
						<reccap>
							<recden>650</recden>
							<recdenu>megabytes</recdenu>
						</reccap>
						<recfmt>ISO 9660</recfmt>
					</offoptn>
				</digtopt>
			</digform>
			<ordering>Call 202-366-DATA, or E-mail (answers@bts.gov) RITA/BTS to request the National Transportation Atlas Databases (NTAD) 2013 DVD. This and other RITA/BTS products may be ordered from the RITA/BTS Internet website http://www.bts.gov/programs/geographic_information_services/.</ordering>
		</stdorder>
		<availabl>
			<timeinfo>
				<sngdate>
					<caldate>20120101</caldate>
				</sngdate>
			</timeinfo>
		</availabl>
	</distinfo>
	<metainfo>
		<metd>20140925</metd>
		<metc>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>Research Data Services (RDS), Columbia University Libraries</cntorg>
					<cntper>GIS/Metadata Librarian</cntper>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
					<address>420 W. 118th St., 215 IAB, MC 3301</address>
					<city>New York</city>
					<state>NY</state>
					<postal>10027</postal>
					<country>USA</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>(212)854-6012</cntvoice>
				<cntemail>data@library.columbia.edu</cntemail>
			</cntinfo>
		</metc>
		<metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
		<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
		<mettc>local time</mettc>
	</metainfo>
</metadata>
